<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Steam Game News</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/?feed=mygames</link><description>All of your Steam games' news, combined!</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 21:42:47 GMT</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:46:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Friday Facts #238 - The GUI update (Part II)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2758894130292085714</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The GUI update (Part II) - Technology tree&lt;/h2&gt;Today we will speak a bit about the work in progress of the Technology tree, and the main GUI style/philosophy evolution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The visual style is evolving and becoming more mature. The aim is to be as functional as possible, and also be pleasant to interact with, always having in mind the limitations of making it work in our engine. This is why we bet for a neutral and sober look that helps to focus on the relevant elements, without the distraction of possible decorative elements. This is not easy to decide, because the tradition of video-games is very rich in decorative GUI elements, and I&amp;#39;m sure that many of you would prefer having screws and rust in the corners of the metal panels and cables hanging everywhere in the GUI. Me too. Sometimes. I believe that once the GUI is completely functional, there will be some minimal decoration and this kind of fantasy, but this will be another chapter if it ever happens.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are paying a lot of attention to the readability in general, according to the AAA standards of the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_Content_Accessibility_Guidelines"&gt;WCAG&lt;/a&gt;. So the contrast with the panels and the font is increased quite a lot compared to &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://factorio.com/blog/post/fff-212"&gt;previous mock-ups&lt;/a&gt; by simply using a &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://contrastchecker.com/"&gt;contrast checker&lt;/a&gt;. Also the font size is increased by 2pt so it is more comfortable to read. Anyway, the user will have control of the font size in the options menu.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bear in mind that the next mock-ups are a work in progress, and we still developing our standards, so some colours and solutions can vary through further iterations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Getting to the point - Research queue&lt;/h2&gt;This picture shows the actuality of the state of the technology tree:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/e705d0b5738c0d9d5d314f70b98d50d9307ecab2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As you can see in the top left frame we added a new functionality. In this panel you can organize the order of your researches and see the progress in real time.&lt;br /&gt;The player will be able to cancel a queued technology just by hovering the card and pressing the cancel button. This progress is attached to the card, and will also be visible in the tree itself.&lt;br /&gt; See the screen below. The fluid wagon has been researched and you can see this in the tree and in the queue.&lt;br /&gt;By using the principle that, when the GUI tells you about some element, it always tries to use this very element, not a representation of it in another frame of the screen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/24f4855125ca23145ff7708486600424afb5ebc7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Featured Technology&lt;/h2&gt;The index of technologies remains as it is, but the position of the Featured technology frame is now attached to the tech tree, next to the technology itself. The link between the type of technology and info or interactions related to it, are physically tied. We are trying as much as possible to interact with the elements in situ, trying not to open unnecessary frames or pop ups of any kind and lose our visual focus.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/3d80016ae0e87807b57bb66ee2fb9e0764524acd.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/b48d966896ed4fa4cfe81574f22b67bb00a3ba47.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/3d80016ae0e87807b57bb66ee2fb9e0764524acd.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/a0898b23a4d337db0fab31d8d22a06cdf5fff20e.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The same happens with the research/queue button. It is placed on top of the featured technology and wraps it with a color indicating it&amp;#39;s state, and providing the possible interaction. When the technology is researched, or unavailable, the button appears pressed and the color changes.&lt;br /&gt;The color code of the cards remains as before, we have just added a new orange state. Yellow for available, orange for queued, red unavailable, and green researched.As said above, tonalities may change in future, but this is pretty much it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/f1e55a9a1ed6609d377ab018a50a4f6da7e8a08c.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The opposition&lt;/h2&gt;As this is a dev blog post, it might be nice to show you some internal part of the process. The thing is, that my domain is mainly programming and gameplay, and Alberts domain is graphics. GUI is often something in between, so the two views on the subject tend to be hard to agree on occasionally. In situations like this, and I can tell you that there were a lot of these over the years, we are able to argue for quite some time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The proposal comes to me and the inevitable discussion about how is the GUI actually going to be implemented. I really love the overall change of the looks, it suddenly looks so much better and professional. But obviously, different people have different priorities, and are used to different things in UI.&lt;br /&gt;I personally had problem understanding, that the &lt;em&gt;Queue&lt;/em&gt; button is actually a button on a first glance. I&amp;#39;m used to the standard (not only in Factorio), that a confirmation button is in the right bottom corner of every window. I am also used to the fact that text button just looks the same everywhere, so I can recognize that it is a button instantly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a reference I would like to show the blueprint confirm.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/91c214c87da9dc7ed634b28bf2fa27ee609f81eb.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was never designed by Albert, and will be touched by the UI changes in 0.17, but it might be a good lesson about standards for us anyway. It is the confirm like window, that doesn&amp;#39;t have the confirmation button as a text button in the right bottom corner. It has a sprite button in the top right corner instead. We have it in the game for quite some time, so we should be used to it, but I still feel like I&amp;#39;m lost for split of second when this window appears and I would actually prefer if it was standardized.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I understand that there is very good reason to have the proposal done this way, both graphically and logically, and I&amp;#39;m aware that Alberts understands the importance of standardisation more than me. We might just have different views on what is the more important principle when these come into conflict. It might be interesting to see what has the reader to say.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Epilogue&lt;/h2&gt;As you can see, the GUI re-design tries to be very respectful to the current one, making changes only when is very clear to us that is for the best of Factorio, and not for the sake of changes. I&amp;#39;d like to talk about more subjects, like multi-resolution, HR tile-set, modularity, animations, other mechanics and some more GUI philosophy, but it&amp;#39;s late and there are more Fridays.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;#39;m very curious to see what you think about it in the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://forums.factorio.com/59598"&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt;.</description><author>Klonan</author><guid>2758894130292085714</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:46:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March Map Jam Winner</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394102381818941363</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Overgrowth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The map jam polls are now over.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our winner, with 32 votes was &lt;strong&gt;Halzoid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check out the winning entry here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1350624857"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1350624857&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The rest of the maps were also great, and worth checking out. Here&amp;#39;s a link to all the entries: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=25000&amp;requiredtags%5B0%5D=march2018jam&amp;actualsort=mostrecent&amp;browsesort=mostrecent&amp;p=1"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=25000&amp;requiredtags%5B0%5D=march2018jam&amp;actualsort=mostrecent&amp;browsesort=mostrecent&amp;p=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We will be having another map jam in a few months. If you didn&amp;#39;t get a chance to participate in this jam, you have some time to practice up for the next one. See this post for several up-to-date editor tutorials: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/25000/discussions/0/1697167355219210068/"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/app/25000/discussions/0/1697167355219210068/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can also join the official Wolfire Discord to get notified ahead of time when the next jam is going to happen, and to get help learning the editor. &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://discord.gg/wolfire"&gt;https://discord.gg/wolfire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the curious, poll results are here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwA0gOrdZ9zyqPvD5vB0xj_2OYV9ijrJkUFgVqq1Flp3cqbg/viewanalytics"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwA0gOrdZ9zyqPvD5vB0xj_2OYV9ijrJkUFgVqq1Flp3cqbg/viewanalytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>kavika</author><guid>2394102381818941363</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 21:57:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Beta Updated (1523560849)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394102381818844714</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The SteamVR Beta has been updated with the following changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gamepads:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with gamepads going into “standby” mode even though buttons are being pressed on the gamepad.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;HTC Vive Pro:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Firmware update which improves audio quality.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Programmer Joe</author><guid>2394102381818844714</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 21:19:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Beta Updated (1523485324)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394102381815437027</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The SteamVR Beta has been updated with the following change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dashboard:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with some unreleased controllers not having a laser pointer in the dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Programmer Joe</author><guid>2394102381815437027</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 22:41:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Beta Updated (1523314681)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748814503055</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The SteamVR Beta has been updated with the following changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SteamVR Home:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;crash fixes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;General:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed occasional crash that occurred in settings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SteamVR Dashboard:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with some custom controller models preventing the laser pointer from appearing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vive Pro:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enabled support for night-mode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oculus Touch:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed the A and B buttons on the right touch controller.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Joe Prime</author><guid>2394101748814503055</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 23:14:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Updated (1512445023) - Hotfix</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748814324021</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
SteamVR has been hotfixed with the following changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;General:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed occasional crash that occurred in settings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SteamVR Dashboard:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with some custom controller models preventing the laser pointer from appearing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Programmer Joe</author><guid>2394101748814324021</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 22:03:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Beta Updated (1523037268)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748802882735</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The SteamVR Beta has been updated with the following changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;General:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issues with plugging in an HMD after SteamVR starts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SteamVR Tracking:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;SteamVR 2.0 basestations report channels in VRMonitor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved startup performance (time until bootstrap) for SteamVR 2.0 bases&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Programmer Joe</author><guid>2394101748802882735</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 18:04:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Friday Facts #237 - Rich  interactive text</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748802709681</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Hello,&lt;br /&gt;since 0.16 is stable we can assign more of our effort into the work on 0.17. One of those features planned for that release is the Rich &amp;amp; interactive text.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Having more text formatting options was one of the things we wanted for quite some time, and it is finally starting to become reality in the 0.17 branch.The initial motivation was to have more possibilities in the tutorial related texts, but it proved to be useful having it available globally in the game.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The current format for any text markup we use is [&amp;lt;type&amp;gt;=&amp;lt;value&amp;gt;], but it might change somehow before 0.17 hits the public. This feature is being developed by wheybags, and it is progressing forward quite steadily.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Basic text formating - font and color&lt;/h2&gt;The obvious option is to allow changing text color:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/b6e7080d3b90b681d82b36b3cf2e94136a1860f8.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;and to allow to change font:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/c8c572e4111fbf452b4fd6d7f49182821a1b199e.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Images - icons&lt;/h2&gt;Since we already have a system to specify icons by the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://lua-api.factorio.com/latest/Concepts.html#SpritePath"&gt;SpritePath&lt;/a&gt;, we can use it as well:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/61696aba705e6f0166bdea8d3e6c6930e7b19ae9.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The cool thing about this, is that all these concepts work on basically all places where text is used, so you can use it in the station name for example:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/fa36a0e30a31760cfdfa9f39d7a45944f8eca28c.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;or even save names (although, I needed to add a possibility to use &amp;quot;.&amp;quot; instead of &amp;quot;/&amp;quot; in sprite path resolution to make it possible):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/1d2746549bf42a83c8e301e12545747f3d37948d.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;or blueprint names:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/1d2746549bf42a83c8e301e12545747f3d37948d.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Element references&lt;/h2&gt;The next planned step will be to make it possible to allow this not only to be used as icons, but as references to the actual items, so the syntax would be something like:[item=straight-rail] or [recipe=advanced-oil-processing]. When used in the chat, it should allow the reader to hover over the icon and get a tooltip of the corresponding game element. When used with technology, it could allow the user to open the mentioned technology by clicking the reference icon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;More advanced usages&lt;/h2&gt;This brings us to the more advanced possibilities, like linking a map position as a clickable icon in the text (something like [gps=&amp;lt;position&amp;gt;]), referencing your armor, so other&amp;#39;s can just hover it in the text and see it. Specifying target to specific train you want to mention and mainly, being able to reference blueprints this way, something like [blueprint=&amp;lt;blueprint string&amp;gt;] can you to show some specific setup in a chat, and others could be able to get the blueprint by just clicking on the icon if they want to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I would be quite curious to see what other type of usages of this can you come up with, let us know on the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://forums.factorio.com/59401"&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Klonan</author><guid>2394101748802709681</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:55:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March Map Jam - Jam is now complete, come play some mods!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748800720682</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Overgrowth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The March map jam, &amp;quot;The Protagonist Dies at the End,&amp;quot; is now complete. Everyone is invited to come play the new mods, and vote on their two favorites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can check out the jam entries here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=25000&amp;requiredtags%5B0%5D=march2018jam&amp;actualsort=mostrecent&amp;browsesort=mostrecent&amp;p=1"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=25000&amp;requiredtags%5B0%5D=march2018jam&amp;actualsort=mostrecent&amp;browsesort=mostrecent&amp;p=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We had 15 entries in total, and a lot of work was put in. Several entries focused on making a single map. Several others chose to make multi-level campaigns, and one entry is a new game mode!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Voting for the winner has now begun. Please play as many of the entries you can before casting your vote.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everyone gets two votes, and voting will be open until April 12th (7 days in total):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://goo"&gt;https://goo&lt;/a&gt; .gl/forms/QSn7L80WJ6p5KPk32&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Link is to the poll. The link is separated since it said &amp;quot;link removed&amp;quot; without it. Copy/paste the link, and remove the extra space)</description><author>kavika</author><guid>2394101748800720682</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 03:42:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Update 322 Live on Steam!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748799073153</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Natural Selection 2&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://unknownworlds.com/ns2/files/2018/04/322-blog.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Update 322 is now live on Steam! This update is primarily a maintenance patch. Over the last few months lots of new systems and features have been introduced to the game and with those additions have come some small issues and strange new bugs. Hopefully this update will address those reported issues and get us back on solid ground. The dev team continues its work on the UGC conversion from Steam Workshop which is slated for 323. Always more to come, including something very special that could come with 323 as well, so stay tuned!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gameplay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved sentries slightly (contributed by Nin)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Prevent beeping noise while attacking and for 1.5 seconds afterwards&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Speed up barrel swivel when it has a target so you&amp;#39;re not getting shot at by a sentry facing the other way&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Add a delay after shooting at a target before starting to swivel and scan again&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Always show tracers from sentries so that players better know where they are getting shot at from&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Sentries will prioritize players over other things, and will shoot at the closest players. Previously, they would prioritize anything that wasn&amp;#39;t a cyst.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Hydras do not block each other’s line of sight anymore (contributed by Katzenfleisch)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tweaks / Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tweaked some marine pickup icons to appear more stylistically consistent.  (Thanks Sinakuwolf!)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Metabolize is no longer a switchable weapon.  This means you cannot accidentally switch to it any longer, and can only use it via the MovementModifier key.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Drifter Eggs can now be issued orders that will be carried out by the drifter when it hatches.  Before, drifters could only be issued rally-points.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;AI movers such as ARCs and movable alien structures like Crags would move on top of players, sometimes trapping them.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Tweaked the infestation shader slightly to better hide the hard edges of infestation circles.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Don’t show team resources for the Ready Room team at the scoreboard.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that servers could get stuck in a infinite loop while filling teams up with bots.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that bots were not removed properly after they got kicked.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where ARCs would sometimes leave collision ghosts behind in PredictWorld.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that the &amp;quot;They Came From Behind!&amp;quot; achievement was granted in some incorrect circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that dying in an Exosuit would cause players to lose their unused grenades.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where some commander buttons would not work if multiple entities were selected, despite the button being visible.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where sometimes the lines connecting queued orders in the commander interface would be connected in the wrong order.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where a marine&amp;#39;s welder and mines could be &amp;quot;stolen&amp;quot; from them at the map origin if that player was inside an exosuit.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the build tool would be stuck building if the player picked up a welder while they were building a structure.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where players could be stuck attacking during a concede sequence.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the wrong tech point would be visible during a concede sequence.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where MACs could not be told to repair destroyed power nodes.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where MACs would sometimes disregard their orders to move to some previous location.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where sometimes clicking the &amp;quot;refresh&amp;quot; button in the server browser would cause the game to crash.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where deploying an ARC would prevent all future corrosion damage to the ARC, including after un-deploying the ARC.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a script error occuring if an Onos died while using stampede.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that gorges couldn’t recycle the second tunnel entrance they placed (contributed to Katzenfleisch)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a script error that occured if a marine had no active weapon (contributed to Katzenfleisch)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed various text positioning/visibility bugs of the GUIChat (contributed by Person8880)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that the marine commander action notifications below the minimap often did not  display the correct location name.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed the reflections in ns2_veil.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Editor    &lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exposed antialiasing and ambient occlusion settings for the map Editor.&lt;/li&gt;      &lt;li&gt;Changed some popup messages to be console messages instead.&lt;/li&gt;        &lt;li&gt;Added debug utility methods to simplify dealing with upvalues (locals inside method/file scope) (contributed by Las)    &lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Please read core/lua/DebugUtility.md for more details!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>WasabiOne</author><guid>2394101748799073153</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 16:46:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Friday Facts #236 - Building a rollup</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2383968106573226825</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
As you are probably already aware, some of our team members are going to attend PAX East in Boston next week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We figured we need some representative prints for our booth, but what to put there? We could have just made a big mega high resolution render of the player character or some other entity, but that would not tell the viewer much about what the game is about. So we thought it would be much better to &amp;quot;just&amp;quot; take a giant screenshot of a working factory, print it, and done! Now of course it’s much more complicated than that…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first obvious hurdle is that you need a savegame to take this screenshot of. So you go and try to take a bunch of random saves on your disk, you open them and find that it’s not so easy to just find a factory which would look nice. Such a factory needs to show enough of the various things to represent the game, can fit the logo somewhere, and must be large enough to fill about 275x185 tiles (3x2 meters at 150dpi taken at game zoom 2)&amp;#8230; one square in the following picture is a chunk (32x32 tiles)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/911f9b99eb45adb9547461290f7a78dd502b452b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Luckily I just had a savegame which was easy to adapt to those requirements, but I would like to ask the question, how does one build such a factory in general? That’s what I have been trying to figure out for a long time now. As some of you may have already noticed, I enjoy constructing very organic factories, a part of which eventually turns into a crazy mess. A mess as crazy as Factorio itself, representing what your will brain look like after playing Factorio.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/479c38365b0bc48047e11f46fea6f4375775652e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I find this to be a good opportunity to be a bit more specific and see a few examples to put it into more context&amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Building for big screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;It’s the year 2015 and pretty much every factory I had built so far eventually arrived to the problem that in order to expand it, I would have to severely modify or destroy large portions of it. I hate to just throw away all the work that I did on my belt knots, so the outcome would usually be that I just stop playing that map and start over.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Example 1, codename: MessFort:&lt;/h2&gt;Once I made a factory that was my largest so far. It used Bobs productivity modules level 7 with a stupid amount of productivity bonus, possible to put into any recipe, and without decreasing the speed of the machine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This alone may sound ridiculous but what it did was allow me to focus on just having fun adding more and more things to the factory, while caring about throughput much less, especially in situations where I could just add better modules to existing factories, leaving more ingredients for other things, allowing me to build even more production lines.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course sooner or later the furnace area would just not be enough and expanding it on the spot would be a pain, so I just started a new dedicated factory just for smelting like many factories do. Trains brought the necessary things and later on I added another factory for circuits and the factory kept being happy. Eventually I dropped under 40 UPS and didn’t want to continue any more. It’s worth mentioning that there was no space science or infinite research back then, so there was little incentive to continue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Discoveries&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mixed belts (different item on each belt half) are a huge amount of fun to work with, and add more visual variety.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Automating as many different recipes as feasible is one step towards a nice looking base.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/8e98b13728ff2e70c807a53a42cb23ee7762e874.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Example 2, codename: SpaceScienceBase&lt;/h2&gt;In the second half of 2016, I started a new factory. Learning from the past discoveries, I wanted to embrace the concept of replacing production lines for intermediates with train stations which would import these items.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Producing those intermediates however required a large rail system outside of the main belt cluster. This gave the factory a lot more expandability and I had spent more time on this map (160 hrs) than any before by a large margin. Like all nice things, the amount of effort directly influences how nice is the result going to be, as with the outer train network expanding, the main base also continued to grow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Discoveries&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having rails inside of the factory adds a lot of depth by breaking the monotonous assembling machine + belt mess.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pipes and oil-related entities are awesome to have in the base so that not everything is an assembling machine.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/c1cee79d6ac496ddab0a946a7d3e6d0e216213f5.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Examples 3 and 4, Codenames: TrainMaze and MOAR&lt;/h2&gt;In the following several months I would try to start a few new maps with different factories and different concepts, but each time something just wasn’t going in the right direction and eventually I would recognize that it’s not &amp;quot;The One&amp;quot; and lose interest in it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/fd1064386fc155ec6cf188043fee80dd3dea01f3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was starting to feel like it was only a matter of luck, and I only made the SpaceScienceBase look awesome by accident as I couldn’t deliberately achieve the same again. I kept thinking about what it is that makes it stand out, what are the differences from the other two, for example:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disabling biters or minimizing military removes many recipes to automate, and easily leads to a less interesting factory.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Too many straight and rectangular patterns just look visually uninteresting.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Preparing all setups for beacon rows from the beginning forces a lot of straight predictable lines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Horizontal production rows of machines generally look better than vertical columns, but having some vertical columns is good for variety.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/cf5a59f8f4fbd869c70bb616afcfcad8d945bc71.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I believe a part of the problem was how I focused on efficiency by preparing for whole rows of beacons for everything (especially the vertical ones), or how I separated the oil and rail related entities from the core of the main factory. Everything just ended up being straight and boring.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Example 5: GridLock&lt;/h2&gt;So eventually I started a new map with all of those things in mind. I made a rough plan for myself what I would like it to end up, and then tried to follow it. The rail system would be extremely expandable but use both single and dual headed trains for variety, the main factory would automate literally every single recipe in the game, and I would try to keep things as organic as possible. I could have tried harder to put more pipe and nuclear related entities in the middle of the factory&amp;#8230; perhaps next time I guess.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here you can see it grow:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://youtu.be/UJPFUQhnXS8"&gt;https://youtu.be/UJPFUQhnXS8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When I was building, I saved over 300 iterative versions of the map. The timelapse is then created by taking a screenshot in each of those saves, and in post-production they are blended together so that it looks smoother.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I found out that we need a screenshot of these dimensions just shortly before the logo appears on the map. You can see not much had to change, except all the terrain under the whole screenshot area was manually reworked in the map editor. This gave me a bunch of ideas of what we need to do to make the map editor better - both for our use with scenarios and campaign, and for our players.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you are interested in reading more about how the base works or downloading the savegame, you can proceed to the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://imgur.com/a/FmoBY"&gt;imgur album&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/6a85790698543f8ec117de70d6fea3d99367f9ce.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The final result is a trio of rollups totalling 3 meters in width and 2 meters in height. This whole thing has been quite an experience for me. Building a factory and doing my own fiddling is great, but building a factory, sitting down with Albert (our art director), thinking how to improve the general visual composition of it, making it fit the requirements etc. was just outright amazing. Just the part where I needed to put the logo and remove a bunch of train stations, cut many belts and reconnect them, was a very cool challenge. If I started again I would have probably done a few things differently, but something would probably be wrong if I didn’t feel like that. Overall I must say I am quite satisfied with the result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/b94606f3b23b56891fe37e87e5bcb88ea2b90af1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Imagine a friend of yours is trying to introduce you to this game, shows this screenshot to you and says: &amp;quot;Hey, this is the game I have been repeatedly telling you about lately&amp;#8230;&amp;quot; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://forums.factorio.com/59207"&gt;What would be your response?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Klonan</author><guid>2383968106573226825</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 13:50:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guacamelee! 2 Coming to Steam  Drinkbox 10th Anniversary Sale</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2383968106573195903</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Guacamelee! Gold Edition&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We&amp;#39;re excited to announce that Guacamelee! 2 will be coming to Steam!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you&amp;#39;re thinking of picking up the game, we&amp;#39;d love it if you could add us to your Steam Wishlist. Every person helps!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/534550/Guacamelee_2/"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/app/534550/Guacamelee_2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In celebration of this, as well as Drinkbox Studios upcoming 10th anniversary, we&amp;#39;ve decided to put all of our games on sale for 90% off! Check out the discounts here: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/search/?developer=DrinkBox%20Studios"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/search/?developer=DrinkBox%20Studios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;3 Drinkbox Studios</description><author>grahams</author><guid>2383968106573195903</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 13:38:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Price change</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2383968106573187651</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Dear all,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Version 0.16 has become stable, and this means that there is one last step for us to reach the 0.17 which will probably become 1.0 version. Then Factorio will finally step out of the Early Access zone. This will take some months but the roadmap is clear for us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We feel that now is a good time to adjust the price of the game. The price of the game has been growing steadily together with the game becoming bigger, more stable and polished. After careful consideration, we have decided to set the new price of the game to 30 USD (or your regional equivalent). This change will become effective as of 16th of April 2018. This is the final Factorio price update, unless something unforeseen happens, so it will also be the price for the game for 1.0 release.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As you probably know we have a strict no sale policy. The game will not go on sale on Steam or any other platform. This basically means that purchasing before the 16th of April 2018 is the only way to buy the game cheaper than the increased release price.&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Klonan</author><guid>2383968106573187651</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 13:35:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - March 30, 2018</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2383968106572359536</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/27357479/4a07e59ea6312d895de9e1652fcfa74cfa2a1d5f.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This update addresses issues with HiDPI displays and display scaling, bots and adds a new cvar for use in add-ons. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix marine bots collision group. Fixes issue where marines were teleporting through elevators, and falling to the ground below the ship at the start of rd-til8comcenter.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add rd_queen_hud_suppress_time Cvar. It is used to suppress the Swarm Queen&amp;#39;s health HUD if not damaged for this long seconds (-1 to always show).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix title of Bonus Mission 5.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix bots don&amp;#39;t get into train in tft3Spaceport map&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve nodegraph in tft3Spaceport&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update reactivedrop.exe with HiDPI aware flag. This should resolve numerous issues with HiDPI displays or when Windows text and apps scaling is set to be above 100%. Previously users have had game window opened in a size(resolution) that is bigger than user&amp;#39;s monitor resolution and thus were unable to change the resolution and any options(because most of UI was off screen).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;We&amp;#39;re also looking for a person capable of drawing new promotion icons which fit the original Alien Swarm style. If you feel you&amp;#39;re up for the task please create a new discussion in our &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://steamcommunity.com/app/563560/discussions/2/"&gt;feedback subforum&lt;/a&gt; where we can discuss the details. Feel free to submit your designs and ideas for the new promotion icons.</description><author>Rayman1103</author><guid>2383968106572359536</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 08:05:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tinker Time beta updated!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365953485471855062</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Awesomenauts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/d9fd955a7a5293eaf0a400777230c05ff0e821a8.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hey everyone, we just released an update for the Awesomenauts 4.6: Tinker Time beta! Catch the full patch notes for this Beta compared to the current live version below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some of the important changes in this Beta compared to the previous Beta is that Commander Rocket no longer resets the charges on his Salvo when using Rocket Launch, some additional tweaks to Derpl and Sentry, and further changes to Professor M. Yoolip!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please share your feedback &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.awesomenauts.com/forum/viewforum.php?f=19"&gt;on our forums&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/cf19c3b5917941055204147d2b4745161cdff74c.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commander Rocket&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Currently too safe and very hard to catch, Rocket needs to be easier to punish&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rocket Launch, no longer knocks back enemies.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Base Health, reduced from 1150 to 1100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laser Trap is too unreliable, doing either too much damage or none at all. These changes should make its effect more reliable while also making placement a little bit more skillful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, time between damage ticks increased from 0.2 to 0.3.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, damage per tick increased from 60 to 90.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, rotation speed increased by 50%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, laser length reduced by 10%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, no longer has deployment time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, duration reduced from 4 to 3 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some upgrade adjustments based on the above changes. These are intended to keep Rocket brawling closer to his Laser Trap.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Profanity filters, now increases trap duration by 2 seconds for 160 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Borgo Cigar cutter, CMDR Rocket gets a shield which reduces 30% of the incoming damage as long as he is nearby a deployed laser trap.
&lt;em&gt;This upgrade is still too strong and mandatory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Box of Cirean cigars, damage per particle per stage reduced from 20 to 16.
&lt;em&gt;His Rocket Launch no longer deals damage to turrets, but his turret push is still too intense. Adjusting the numbers and making them more consistent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charged Salvo, damage modifier against droids increased from 75% to 80%&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charged Salvo, damage modifier against turrets reduced from 100% to 80%.
&lt;em&gt;This upgrade was a holdover from a time where Rocket’s Laser Trap had a lot more uptime. The intention for this replacement is to enable Rocket to be a bit better at brawling and allowing him to stay a bit closer to the fight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Head in Jar, now adds 16% damage to Charged Salvo when firing a single rocket, two stages for 175 solar each.
&lt;em&gt;Part of his safety comes from his relatively high ranged base attack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charged Salvo, range reduced by 20%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medal Booster Pack, range increase reduced from 25% to 20%.
&lt;em&gt;Combining Rocket Launch and a full Charged Salvo at melee range provides too much damage, too easily. At the same time we want to stimulate him to get more into the thick of the fight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rocket Launch, now deals between 150 and 350 damage, depending on how long the rocket has been flying.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mother of Bombs, after using Rocket Launch without hitting an enemy, your next Charged Salvo shot will deal 100 more damage for 170 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/823d399cc943558129d3bb1f405c248306662d21.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Derpl&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Considered too strong specifically on Ribbit and Starstorm, these tweaks attempt to adjust him without affecting his general performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Siege mode, Derpl is no longer immune to CC during the transformation out of siege mode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Combustion lava lamp, size increase reduced from 22% to 18%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Falling acceleration reduced by 20%.
&lt;em&gt;Traps can be very oppressive, maxing out at full 2.4 seconds of no gameplay for the receiving party. Their long lifetime also stimulates camping gameplay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trap, snare duration reduced from 1.6 to 1.2 seconds&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trap, now also slows for 25% for 2.4 seconds. (extenting 1.2 seconds beyond the snare)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trap, base lifetime reduced from 11 to 9 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Empowered Grid, snare increase per stage reduced from 0.4 to 0.3 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lead casing, the silence now has a fixed duration of 2.4 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trap, now charges in the middle of Derpl instead of having an arming time when placed.
&lt;em&gt;Some base attack adjustments to better balance the row and take the above changes into account.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fat Cat, cooldown increased from 4 to 5 seconds, price increased from 185 to 195.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kitty Catsuit, price decreased from 175 to 150 solar per stage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;CAT package, price decreased from 175 to 150 solar per stage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bat Catsuit, now deals 100% increased damage against Nauts who are snared or slowed, no longer works with Fat Cat.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Long Cat, now works with Fat Cat.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/306d6f4cd9cfb2e4744d49e424863f0562d72426.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dizzy&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dizzy is currently a bit too strong. But she&amp;#39;s also very finicky, and has a lot of weak upgrades.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Multi Dash, time between dashes increased from 0.3 to 0.4 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Multi Dash, damage per dash increased from 150 to 160.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Walkbot Pro, speed up dash reload time by 30% when you are near to enemies.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Explosive Clone, cooldown increased from 6 to 7 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Backstage pass, increase the range of your Multi Dash by 25% when you have the maximum amount of dashes charged.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Matching Glittery Dungarees, now reduces the cooldown for the next Explosive Clone by 3 seconds when it hits an enemy Awesomenaut.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Purple Prince&amp;quot; lipstick, now also slows enemies when they leave the bubble as well as when they are hit by the explosion.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bubble shot, size increased by 50%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Graffiti artist, price increased from 165 to 190.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tipi teal, merged to one stage of 30% range and speed increase for 140 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/89e6d6a97346b9e10bb82ea3b76823a8a1089bdc.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ix&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ix generally still brings too much to the table overall, great displace move, solid heals, invincibility frames, excellent mobility and strong brawling. In order to nudge him more towards his role his brawling should be reduced.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Refract, cooldown increased from 9 to 10.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Radiate, damage per Scatter reduced from 15 to 12.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mammoth hair scarf, ally speed bonus increased from 12% to 15% per stage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tree hugger, ally damage boost increased from 12% to 15% per stage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Personality Crystal, range increase reduced from 35% to 30%.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/92056c0875f58423dbc8774bae1acad1ef54924d.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Lonestar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ribbit snail slime, fixed that the healthpack would time out if it fell for too long.
&lt;em&gt;Since these aren’t that much better than regular boots, they also don’t have to cost much more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rocket boots, solar price reduced from 160 to 140.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Base speed, increased by 4%.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/32af7797f04668c4503d32c67c12e724841d75e0.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Max Focus&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This item has its use, but it&amp;#39;s too weak and expensive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;From pond to podium, merged into one stage which adds 30% range and speed for 200 solar.
&lt;em&gt;The homing upgrade looks cool, but doesn&amp;#39;t do much. Here is a replacement proposal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;UFO spotted, now gives +50% speed during Scene Illumination for 160 solar.
&lt;em&gt;This upgrade is just a bit too expensive, especially given the next change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sadak mysteries, price reduced from 195 to 175 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Removing the stacking will reduce the need to combo with Sadak.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Brutalities of the Kraken, damage increased from 120 to 135 per stage, no longer stacks with Sadak mysteries.
&lt;em&gt;This item is just a bit too expensive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rob Bourgogne, price reduced from 180 to 160 per stage.
&lt;em&gt;This item was overnerfed shortly after launch, because the skill was too strong to begin with at the time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hairy King, size increase increased from 10% to 15%, price increased from 175 to 200 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Some overpriced items.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don Steward, price per stage reduced from 175 to 140 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pete Jennirks, price reduced from 240 to 200 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Incriminating dirt, price reduced from 180 to 150 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Flying camera, price reduced from 210 to 150 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Meanwhile, this one&amp;#39;s underpriced.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hidden microphone, price increased from 170 to 200 solar.
&lt;em&gt;This item is the strongest on the row, it doesn&amp;#39;t need to stack further.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Galactic police scanner, no longer stacks with incriminating dirt, price increased from 180 to 220 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/ed41d63c6b924f52411cec848bbdf99405c2cae4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nibbs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Firebreath, fixed that after being Cocooned by Genji during Firebreath she wouldn&amp;#39;t resume after the Cocoon wears off.
&lt;em&gt;Some price adjustments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Skull dunduns, price reduced from 200 to 180.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eye of Coba, price reduced from from 215 to 190.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dragon Speaker Idol, now has two stages of +10% attack speed each, at 150 solar per stage.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/6531b00b86ae6b0bdbc084cc9daad93c01a40cfd.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Professor Milton Yoolip&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Some adjustments to improve the item balance for the gaze row.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Beard Trimming Fork, price reduced from 165 to 130 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Syrup Pouring Robot, maximum lifesteal increased from 120 to 150 per stage.
&lt;em&gt;Some changes to make Dinos more reliable at base.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Summon Robo Dinos, now jump at enemies at base.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Summon Robo Dinos, damage per bite reduced from 80 to 75.
&lt;em&gt;Now this upgrade has become useless.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Holo Pet Food, now reduces the damage dealt by Nauts who have been bitten by 15% for 1.5 seconds.

&lt;strong&gt;Qi’Tara&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Made Qi&amp;#39;Taras seven star strike visual only in front of Qi&amp;#39;Tara to represent the area where damage was being applied better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that she couldn’t use Chakram Shift to teleport while using Seven Star Strike when the Salty Seal upgrade was bought.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Made Qi&amp;#39;Taras seven star strike visual only in front of Qi&amp;#39;Tara to represent the area where damage was being applied better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that the Lily of the Isle projectiles would spawn at her feet during Seven Star Strike.
&lt;em&gt;Qi’Tara deals too much damage during Seven Star Strike, and too little outside of it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seven star strike, attack speed increase reduced from 40% to 30%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poisonous blade, direct damage increased from 45 to 50.
&lt;em&gt;Her relationship with speed feels disjointed, where attacking slows her down but Seven Star Strike speed her up etc. These changes also tie in with the issue above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poisonous Blade, removed movement penalty when attacking.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seven Star Strike, removed speed bonus during the ability.
&lt;em&gt;With the changes above, this upgrade has now become useless. This change will make Qi’Tara’s damage output more reliable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chilasi Chakram, now speeds up the damage over time of Poisonous blade by 20% for 160 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Since the bug was fixed where this upgrade doubled your damage, this upgrade has become too weak&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lily of the Isle, projectile speed and range increased by 30%.
&lt;em&gt;Salty Seal makes Qi’Tara almost unstoppable, this change should make counterplay possible again&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Salty Seal, now cleanses all slows, snares and chains at the start of Seven Star Strike.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Salty Seal, now activates a shield that blocks 100 damage and provides immunity against slows, stuns, snares, chains, gravity and time warps as long as it’s active.
&lt;em&gt;Other tweaks and adjustments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seven star strike, now also gives a 10% lifesteal effect.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Baby plumbin oil, additional lifesteal reduced from 30% to 15% for 175 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rakki Comb, merged to one stage which adds 200% damage vs. droids for 155 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/c3e6b9ea5315191e6b97f4d8f5951b5c8162cf62.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Raelynn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Iron Rifle, fixed that the shield didn’t last long enough to protect the entire charge duration.
&lt;em&gt;This weak upgrade has some heavy competition on the row.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Monkey hand, range increase increased from 25% to 40%.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/7a582ca443e88ea8625584a74d664a6f6567dd19.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Rocco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Birdseed donuts, cooldown reduction when hit increased from 2 to 4 seconds, duration increase increased from 1 to 2 seconds.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/01394ae6ab660d8f2b8eecb87756a5579245d737.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Scoop&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;His base attack is a bit too weak in general&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sword Strike, Slash damage increased from 100 to 105, Cleave lifesteal increased from 20% to 30%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Banner of the Triple Scoop, price per stage reduced from 130 to 100.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Halberd of Justice, bonus damage reduced from 25% to 22%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Titanium Coneshield, price increased from 130 to 150 solar per stage.
&lt;em&gt;Other tweaks and adjustments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Brutally Whipped Cream, price reduced from 200 to 180 per stage.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/713fb830953afd54abcf5557ac9a64e88e95c9a4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sentry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that Sentry’s Beacon no longer emitted a phone interference sound.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that Starstorm statue didn&amp;#39;t affect Bug detector.
&lt;em&gt;Reducing his efficiency of laying down mines in choke-points which has little to no counter-play.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mines, damage while stationary reduced from 80 to 70.
&lt;em&gt;With this change in mind, a counter-buff to help him land reliable damage output in close ranged scenarios.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mines, damage on direct hit increased from 80 to 90.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Projectile speed of mines increased by 15%.
&lt;em&gt;Camouflage tent is currently emphasizing passive play. This change will reward aggressive use of his AA by increasing his chase potency and reliability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Camouflage tent, now increases projectile speed and range by 15%, one stage for 175 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Drive-over skulls is also providing a lot of easy chip damage and can be replaced with a more active timing based auto-attack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drive-over skulls, now deals +75% direct damage when not firing for 1.5s.
&lt;em&gt;Currently Black Hole Sun feels inconsistent and very hard to avoid, and if avoided it lingers for a whole 1.5s. This is an attempt at making BHS a more reliable ability and feel more fair on both ends. Starting with rewarding precision and aim on Sentry&amp;#39;s end while allowing enemies to dodge the skill easier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, projectile distance increased by 10%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, projectile speed increased by 10%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, size of black hole reduced by 15%.
&lt;em&gt;The next set of changes are both aimed at compensating for the size reduction but also to reduce the duration of BHS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, minimum gravity increased by 8%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, maximum gravity increased by 5%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, duration of black hole reduced from 1.5s to 1.2s.
&lt;em&gt;With these changes aside, his shield charging up also adds up a lot of time where he&amp;#39;s difficult to punish. Reducing his shield duration both allows him for using his black hole quicker, while also being vulnerable faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shield duration reduced from 2s to 1.5s.
&lt;em&gt;With less up-time of his shields, his base shield scaling could be increased to fulfill his tanky role. This allows him to tank a little extra in fights and reward aggressive play.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, Base shield increased from 20% to 25%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Microfilm, shielding reduced from 10% to 8%, price reduced to 140 solar per stage.
&lt;em&gt;Some Sentry&amp;#39;s just leave their beacon sitting somewhere in order to reveal or permanently put pressure on an area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Teleport Beacon, times out after 45 seconds.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/533ccae8a301b7a6bcef4fbf5a4f4d898dd7768d.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Skree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Made separate spawnpoints for Sawblade and Spare blade, and moved them apart a little.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sawblade, now deals direct damage instead of damage over time.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/033fc68a9b5c59a6506c8ae4255a147a60ccc750.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Smiles&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Smiles has been overnerfed in the last few updates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Base health, increased from 1550 to 1650.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trapper’s hook, cooldown reduced from 10 to 8 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bush fire, range increased by 25%.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/36aa2148c877b5ffaaec29de1e2eb29778af0b34.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Swiggins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poolboy, price reduced from 240 to 210 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/04d99daf1b3c440ab3cc1dcc537d922ea50d6a19.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Yuri&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Uranium spikes, price increased from 125 to 150 per stage.&lt;/li&gt;</description><author>Mitaki</author><guid>2365953485471855062</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 15:37:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Get nostalgic and play with the classic gloves in Q.U.B.E. 2!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365953485471675897</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/31518971/9ac4712dd1e3e09d9ac2d061186bea071ef40988.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Get nostalgic and play with the classic Q.U.B.E. gloves equipped in Q.U.B.E. 2! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re pleased to announce that the classic Q.U.B.E. glove skin will be available today at 5PM GMT with the Season Pass. Fans of the first game will recognise the iconic gloves and be able to play with them in Q.U.B.E. 2 - you’ll also be able to switch between the old and new style during gameplay. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The classic glove skin is currently only for PC at this time and will be available in the Season Pass on Steam. Grab the season pass here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/822094/QUBE_2_Season_Pass/"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/app/822094/QUBE_2_Season_Pass/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks!</description><author>Toxic Games</author><guid>2365953485471675897</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:26:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capture Stunning HD Shots with Nvidia Ansel in Q.U.B.E. 2</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982533009108</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
For those of you with Nvidia graphics cards, Ansel is fully integrated in Q.U.B.E. 2 so you can capture stunning HD shots like this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/31518971/dfbd4754ff2950e28f5e42c3f0d02886e953fa91.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/31518971/8edfb6d067df0637d74e91d69f96ac0661d32197.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can view the full HD versions here:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://images.nvidia.com/geforce-com/international/images/geforce-experience/gdc-2018/qube-2-nvidia-ansel-003-3840x2160.jpg"&gt;https://images.nvidia.com/geforce-com/international/images/geforce-experience/gdc-2018/qube-2-nvidia-ansel-003-3840x2160.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://images.nvidia.com/geforce-com/international/images/geforce-experience/gdc-2018/qube-2-nvidia-ansel-007-3840x2160.jpg"&gt;https://images.nvidia.com/geforce-com/international/images/geforce-experience/gdc-2018/qube-2-nvidia-ansel-007-3840x2160.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks!</description><author>Toxic Games</author><guid>2365952982533009108</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 17:18:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - March 23, 2018</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982531910171</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/27357479/b6fd1ef5dadafd08cbcb218525cd0176f442cf0d.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This update brings bug fixes and a new VScript function for use in add-ons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix vindicator and devastator shotgun shell ejection. Previously only one shotgun shell was ejected after multiple shots. Now each shot ejects an empty shotgun shell.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix aliens crowding on an incapacitated marine&amp;#39;s body. When marine is incapacitated and other marines are not around aliens were piling up around the incapacitated body.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix grenade launcher&amp;#39;s grenade colliding with bot marines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make npc_cscanner not collide grenade launcher&amp;#39;s grenades and players&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix drones warping through marines in ASBI challenge&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added the following VScript function for CBaseEntity. PrecacheModel( string modelPath ) //Precache a model after the map has loaded.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix asw_buzzer SpeedScale. It&amp;#39;s now possible to change the m_fSpeedScale for the buzzer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix Take A Break being greyed out on servers which have lobby disabled&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Dmitriy</author><guid>2365952982531910171</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 10:00:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Watch the Accolades Trailer for Q.U.B.E. 2 </title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982525759202</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/31518971/8fd8df70d05ab5c85de8b3df356e7f8c06071bc4.gif"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&amp;#39;re proud to release our accolades trailer for Q.U.B.E. 2 which includes recent review scores and quotes from publications such as Destructoid, Gamespot and IGN.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The game has been praised by both press and players so thank you all for your support! Watch the full version here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://youtu.be/mttDXi8T6Hs"&gt;https://youtu.be/mttDXi8T6Hs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope you enjoy watching it and feel free to check out the game yourself if you haven&amp;#39;t already! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/359100/QUBE_2/"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/app/359100/QUBE_2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks!</description><author>Toxic Games</author><guid>2365952982525759202</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 17:09:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Announcing Oddworld: Abe's Origins</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982525493905</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Hello Oddworld fans!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&amp;#39;re delighted to announce Oddworld: Abe&amp;#39;s Origins, a new art book from Indie By Design that charts the visual and development history of our classic titles, like Oddworld: Abe&amp;#39;s Oddysee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3953414/cc1168aa3b97117cdf5d39e6ba7486227dc7a062.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you&amp;#39;d like to read more about the project, please check it out here - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1869209521/oddworld-abes-origins-book-and-game-collection"&gt;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1869209521/oddworld-abes-origins-book-and-game-collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oddworld: Abe&amp;#39;s Origins will also include both Abe&amp;#39;s Oddysee and Abe&amp;#39;s Exoddus on a special physical PC release on DVD ROM, complete with instruction manual.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3953414/f155acb2059db5d6854c1efadfc864172c359067.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope you like the project!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, your friends at Oddworld and Indie By Design.</description><author>Oddworld Admin</author><guid>2365952982525493905</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 15:23:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Play Sapienza for FREE!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982525116509</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for HITMAN™&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.akamai.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/4679451/7b7c8eb82e46f1a435aec02fddbcb8e26b1b0bd1.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Spring has arrived and it’s time to travel somewhere sunny! Your destination is Sapienza and everyone is invited via the HITMAN Spring Pack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The HITMAN Spring Pack is a completely FREE download and includes the entire Sapienza location (Episode 2). It&amp;#39;s yours to keep permanently and all of your progress will carry through to the full game when you buy the Game of the Year Edition - just make sure to download it before April 3rd!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You’ll get the main story mission, ‘World of Tomorrow’, 20 levels of Mastery (including weapon and item unlocks), more than 100 challenges, 7 achievements/trophies and ALL of the Escalation Contracts, Challenge Packs and Featured Contracts that we’ve released for Sapienza. On top of all that, any Elusive Targets that are re-activated in Sapienza will also be playable through the Spring Pack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/236870/HITMAN/"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/app/236870/HITMAN/&lt;/a&gt;</description><author>TravisIOI</author><guid>2365952982525116509</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 12:53:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hotfixes for 1.2 patch out now</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982523849147</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Overgrowth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
1.2.1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Updated Steam API DLLs. This may fix some compatibility issues&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.2.2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix performance bug when Steam is running at same time as game (for some people this is as big as a 30% performance boost)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixes to several Therium-2 levels&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix to &amp;lt;ControlScript&amp;gt; functionality in character XML&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Removed unused SDL game controller haptic subsystem initialization (fixes crash on Launch on Linux)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make error non-fatal when failing to fully initialize a detected game controller&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.2.3&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix crash in hotfix 1.2.2 when launching game with 0 workshop mods installed (whoops!)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Known issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is an issue for some people where you try to launch the game and both the game and Steam crash. We&amp;#39;re still investigating the cause of this, but we believe this is due to the Steam shader pre-cache feature.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To work around this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;Steam -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Shader Pre-Cache -&amp;gt; uncheck Enable Shader Pre-Cache&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Delete this folder: C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\steamapps\shadercache\25000&lt;/li&gt;</description><author>kavika</author><guid>2365952982523849147</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 04:28:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Last Chance for the 20% off Discount from Q.U.B.E. 2</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2982945658367136359</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
It&amp;#39;s now less than 24 hours for you to pick up Q.U.B.E. 2 with the 20% launch discount on Steam. It ends tomorrow at 5PM GMT so grab it while you can!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/4959436/c71738b0b59e906438e629d35a132957eb8254af.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks!&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Toxic Games</author><guid>2982945658367136359</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 21:13:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March Map Jam - The Protagonist Dies at the End</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2982945658361759358</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Overgrowth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;With the new 1.2 patch, it&amp;#39;s time to start a map jam!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edit: The jam is now complete. Come here to see the announcement, find the list of new mods, and to cast your vote for your favorite! &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/gid/103582791430184966/announcements/detail/1663392709273977374"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/gid/103582791430184966/announcements/detail/1663392709273977374&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Starting on the 18th of March, anyone who would like to participate has two weeks to create a map with the level editor using the theme given to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The theme of the map jam is &lt;strong&gt;Protagonist Dies At The End&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The deadline is March 30th.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For tutorials on how to create a map in the level editor, check here:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://steamcommunity.com/app/25000/discussions/0/1697167355219210068/"&gt;Steam forum post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLuNY3k_ozhofaucF0mq043_QAj8eEgXzV"&gt;Youtube playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://wiki.wolfire.com/index.php/Editor_Interface"&gt;Wolfire wiki page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For discussion about the map jam, join &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://discord.gg/wolfire"&gt;the official Wolfire Discord&lt;/a&gt;, and check out the #map-jam-march-2018 channel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Rules:
- You can make any kind of map you want, as long as it fits the theme.
- All maps have to be completed by March 30th.
- It should be uploaded to the Workshop, but your level can also be uploaded here through Discord.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Interpret the theme in any way you want, and most importantly, have fun!</description><author>kavika</author><guid>2982945658361759358</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 09:30:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>