<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Steam Game News</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/?feed=mygames</link><description>All of your Steam games' news, combined!</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 01:13:35 GMT</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 21:00:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Unknown Pleasures: The five best new games on Steam</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2758894130302757654</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Steam&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/04/unknownpleasures18-04-13-620x320.png" alt="I can&amp;#039;t think of a good caption because I keep getting distracted by these bloody ants faffing about in my room." width="620" height="320" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-534541" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infants. Infants everywhere. Ooh, look at me, I&amp;#8217;m like a human but smaller and I&amp;#8217;m allowed to scream and climb on stuff if I want to, oooh. End of term holidays are when you&amp;#8217;re supposed to be indoors playing games, not studying or going outside like some sort of peon. Bah. Wake me up when they&amp;#8217;re all back in school juggling cats or bouncer baiting, or whatever this week&amp;#8217;s Fear The Yoof thing is.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, I bet they don&amp;#8217;t even know what &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/unknown-pleasures/"&gt;Unknown Pleasures&lt;/a&gt; is named after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pointing out what used to be grass this week: naive snipers, murine nomads, and a little blobby blob that boings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/16/unknown-pleasures-the-five-best-new-games-on-steam/#more-534539" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Sin Vega)</author><guid>2758894130302757654</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 21:00:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Awesomenauts 4.6 to Launch April 18th!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2758894130301474635</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Awesomenauts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/d9fd955a7a5293eaf0a400777230c05ff0e821a8.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;Get ready! Awesomenauts 4.6: Tinker Time will release on Steam this Wednesday!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The upcoming update includes a lot of balance tweaks to Derpl Zork, Qi&amp;#39;Tara, Commander Rocket, Dizzy, Sentry X-58, and others, as well as a number of quality of life changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped out during the Beta and shared feedback. For launch celebrations, a discussion of the changes included in the update, and some games, tune in to the Streamisho this Wednesday at 17:00 EU / 16:00 UK / 11AM ET / 8AM PT over at &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://Twitch.TV/RonimoGames"&gt;Twitch.TV/RonimoGames&lt;/a&gt;!</description><author>Mitaki</author><guid>2758894130301474635</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 13:07:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Terraria spin-off Otherworld cancelled three years after it was announced</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/eurogamer/2758894130300925891</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/b&gt; for Terraria&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://cdn.gamer-network.net/2018/articles/2018-04-16-10-15/-1523870140136.jpg/EG11/resize/300x-1/format/jpg/1967301.jpg" alt=""/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terraria spin-off Otherworld has been cancelled three years after it was announced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terraria: Otherworld was announced in February 2015 as a spin-off from the hugely popular Terraria series. It was intended to task players with purifying the world of the Corruption by finding and activating purifying towers that push back the spread. The idea was that it would include more strategy and RPG elements, such as a new tower defense mechanic, as well as a skill tree.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A year ago, &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2017-04-05-terraria-company-ditches-spin-off-maker-after-troubled-development"&gt;Terraria owner Re-Logic rebooted Otherworld&lt;/a&gt; after dumping Dutch developer Engine Software in favour of Pipeworks, a studio that did Terraria re-write work on console and mobile. This after what sounded like a troubled development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2018-04-16-terraria-spin-off-otherworld-cancelled-three-years-after-it-was-announced"&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2758894130300925891</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 09:39:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ken Levineless Bioshock in development at secret 2K studio</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2758894130295224782</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for BioShock&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/04/12-620x300.jpg" alt="12" width="620" height="300" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-534765" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Irrational Games was dismantled in 2014, the future of the &lt;a href="http://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/bioshock"&gt;Bioshock&lt;/a&gt; IP was left twisting in the wind. It certainly wasn&amp;#8217;t going to fall on former studio head Ken Levine, as he departed to run a smaller studio called &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2017/02/24/ghost-story-games/"&gt;Ghost Story Games&lt;/a&gt; which would have nothing near the production scale required to take on a new time-period magic-potion exercise in the violence of political ideologies and/or golf. But as part of a much larger 2K expose written this week over at &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/how-the-makers-of-mafia-iii-lost-their-way-1825242177"&gt;Kotaku&lt;/a&gt;, it appears news has leaked regarding a Bioshock title in development at a super secret 2K studio. Or at least, you know, previously super secret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/14/ken-levineless-bioshock-in-development-at-secret-2k-studio/#more-534761" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Brock Wilbur)</author><guid>2758894130295224782</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 19:17:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Terraria spin-off Otherworld has been cancelled</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2758894130294437594</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Terraria&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terraria: Otherworld has had a rough old time since developer Re-Logic &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/terraria-otherworld-is-a-new-terraria-game-but-its-not-a-sequel/" target="_blank"&gt;announced it in 2015&lt;/a&gt;. A year later it &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/terraria-otherworld-is-still-happening-but-its-been-revamped/" target="_blank"&gt;was revamped&lt;/a&gt;, and last year co-developer Engine Software was &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/terraria-otherworld-update-reveals-a-new-development-partner/" target="_blank"&gt;dropped from the project&lt;/a&gt;. So it&amp;apos;s not entirely surprising that the game&amp;#x2014;which was a more focused, strategic spin-off of Terraria&amp;#x2014;has now been cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://forums.terraria.org/index.php?threads/this-is-the-end-otherworld-development-cancelled.68594/" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, Re-Logic explained that Otherworld was a long way behind schedule, and still far short of the game the team wanted it to be. &amp;quot;Taking the massive amount of work that would be remaining to complete along with the extensive time it would take to get that done, and how that would greatly interfere with the pursuit of other projects on behalf of Re-Logic, it becomes clear that this leaves things in a very undesirable state,&amp;quot; it said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;At some point, we have to be honest with ourselves and realize that Otherworld simply is never going to reach its potential in any sort of reasonable time or fashion.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It admitted that it shouldn&amp;apos;t have announced the project at such an early stage, and that it will only talk about games &amp;quot;in which we are fully confident in regards to timing&amp;quot; in the future. It also said it was a mistake to partly outsource development to another team, and that future projects are likely to be kept in-house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Otherworld will never see the light of day, some of its best ideas will make it into the studio&amp;apos;s future games, Re-Logic said. Finally, it said that the cancellation will not impact the active development of Terraria, which continues as planned.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2758894130294437594</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 14:22:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Friday Facts #238 - The GUI update (Part II)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2758894130292085714</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The GUI update (Part II) - Technology tree&lt;/h2&gt;Today we will speak a bit about the work in progress of the Technology tree, and the main GUI style/philosophy evolution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The visual style is evolving and becoming more mature. The aim is to be as functional as possible, and also be pleasant to interact with, always having in mind the limitations of making it work in our engine. This is why we bet for a neutral and sober look that helps to focus on the relevant elements, without the distraction of possible decorative elements. This is not easy to decide, because the tradition of video-games is very rich in decorative GUI elements, and I&amp;#39;m sure that many of you would prefer having screws and rust in the corners of the metal panels and cables hanging everywhere in the GUI. Me too. Sometimes. I believe that once the GUI is completely functional, there will be some minimal decoration and this kind of fantasy, but this will be another chapter if it ever happens.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are paying a lot of attention to the readability in general, according to the AAA standards of the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_Content_Accessibility_Guidelines"&gt;WCAG&lt;/a&gt;. So the contrast with the panels and the font is increased quite a lot compared to &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://factorio.com/blog/post/fff-212"&gt;previous mock-ups&lt;/a&gt; by simply using a &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://contrastchecker.com/"&gt;contrast checker&lt;/a&gt;. Also the font size is increased by 2pt so it is more comfortable to read. Anyway, the user will have control of the font size in the options menu.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bear in mind that the next mock-ups are a work in progress, and we still developing our standards, so some colours and solutions can vary through further iterations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Getting to the point - Research queue&lt;/h2&gt;This picture shows the actuality of the state of the technology tree:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/e705d0b5738c0d9d5d314f70b98d50d9307ecab2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As you can see in the top left frame we added a new functionality. In this panel you can organize the order of your researches and see the progress in real time.&lt;br /&gt;The player will be able to cancel a queued technology just by hovering the card and pressing the cancel button. This progress is attached to the card, and will also be visible in the tree itself.&lt;br /&gt; See the screen below. The fluid wagon has been researched and you can see this in the tree and in the queue.&lt;br /&gt;By using the principle that, when the GUI tells you about some element, it always tries to use this very element, not a representation of it in another frame of the screen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/24f4855125ca23145ff7708486600424afb5ebc7.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Featured Technology&lt;/h2&gt;The index of technologies remains as it is, but the position of the Featured technology frame is now attached to the tech tree, next to the technology itself. The link between the type of technology and info or interactions related to it, are physically tied. We are trying as much as possible to interact with the elements in situ, trying not to open unnecessary frames or pop ups of any kind and lose our visual focus.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/3d80016ae0e87807b57bb66ee2fb9e0764524acd.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/b48d966896ed4fa4cfe81574f22b67bb00a3ba47.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/3d80016ae0e87807b57bb66ee2fb9e0764524acd.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/a0898b23a4d337db0fab31d8d22a06cdf5fff20e.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The same happens with the research/queue button. It is placed on top of the featured technology and wraps it with a color indicating it&amp;#39;s state, and providing the possible interaction. When the technology is researched, or unavailable, the button appears pressed and the color changes.&lt;br /&gt;The color code of the cards remains as before, we have just added a new orange state. Yellow for available, orange for queued, red unavailable, and green researched.As said above, tonalities may change in future, but this is pretty much it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/f1e55a9a1ed6609d377ab018a50a4f6da7e8a08c.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The opposition&lt;/h2&gt;As this is a dev blog post, it might be nice to show you some internal part of the process. The thing is, that my domain is mainly programming and gameplay, and Alberts domain is graphics. GUI is often something in between, so the two views on the subject tend to be hard to agree on occasionally. In situations like this, and I can tell you that there were a lot of these over the years, we are able to argue for quite some time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The proposal comes to me and the inevitable discussion about how is the GUI actually going to be implemented. I really love the overall change of the looks, it suddenly looks so much better and professional. But obviously, different people have different priorities, and are used to different things in UI.&lt;br /&gt;I personally had problem understanding, that the &lt;em&gt;Queue&lt;/em&gt; button is actually a button on a first glance. I&amp;#39;m used to the standard (not only in Factorio), that a confirmation button is in the right bottom corner of every window. I am also used to the fact that text button just looks the same everywhere, so I can recognize that it is a button instantly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a reference I would like to show the blueprint confirm.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/91c214c87da9dc7ed634b28bf2fa27ee609f81eb.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was never designed by Albert, and will be touched by the UI changes in 0.17, but it might be a good lesson about standards for us anyway. It is the confirm like window, that doesn&amp;#39;t have the confirmation button as a text button in the right bottom corner. It has a sprite button in the top right corner instead. We have it in the game for quite some time, so we should be used to it, but I still feel like I&amp;#39;m lost for split of second when this window appears and I would actually prefer if it was standardized.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I understand that there is very good reason to have the proposal done this way, both graphically and logically, and I&amp;#39;m aware that Alberts understands the importance of standardisation more than me. We might just have different views on what is the more important principle when these come into conflict. It might be interesting to see what has the reader to say.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Epilogue&lt;/h2&gt;As you can see, the GUI re-design tries to be very respectful to the current one, making changes only when is very clear to us that is for the best of Factorio, and not for the sake of changes. I&amp;#39;d like to talk about more subjects, like multi-resolution, HR tile-set, modularity, animations, other mechanics and some more GUI philosophy, but it&amp;#39;s late and there are more Fridays.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;#39;m very curious to see what you think about it in the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://forums.factorio.com/59598"&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt;.</description><author>Klonan</author><guid>2758894130292085714</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:46:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sandbox spinoff Terraria: Otherworld has been cancelled</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2758894130291960662</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Terraria&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-534535" src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/04/terr-620x300.jpg" alt="Terraria" width="620" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Terraria developers Re-Logic have announced that they&amp;#8217;re pulling the plug on &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/terraria-otherworld/"&gt;Terraria: Otherworld&lt;/a&gt;. First unveiled three years ago, it promised a more adventure-focused spin on the  platforming/building  sandbox mega-hit &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/terraria/"&gt;Terraria&lt;/a&gt;, with more of a focus on fighting, defending your bases, and navigating complex environments. The project has looked a bit wonky for some time now, and last year &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2017/04/05/terraria-otherworld-switches-to-new-developer/"&gt;development duties changed hands&lt;/a&gt;, but it&amp;#8217;s still sad to see it canned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/13/sandbox-spinoff-terraria-otherworld-has-been-cancelled/#more-534527" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Dominic Tarason)</author><guid>2758894130291960662</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 21:25:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March Map Jam Winner</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394102381818941363</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Overgrowth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The map jam polls are now over.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our winner, with 32 votes was &lt;strong&gt;Halzoid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check out the winning entry here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1350624857"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1350624857&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The rest of the maps were also great, and worth checking out. Here&amp;#39;s a link to all the entries: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=25000&amp;requiredtags%5B0%5D=march2018jam&amp;actualsort=mostrecent&amp;browsesort=mostrecent&amp;p=1"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=25000&amp;requiredtags%5B0%5D=march2018jam&amp;actualsort=mostrecent&amp;browsesort=mostrecent&amp;p=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We will be having another map jam in a few months. If you didn&amp;#39;t get a chance to participate in this jam, you have some time to practice up for the next one. See this post for several up-to-date editor tutorials: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/25000/discussions/0/1697167355219210068/"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/app/25000/discussions/0/1697167355219210068/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can also join the official Wolfire Discord to get notified ahead of time when the next jam is going to happen, and to get help learning the editor. &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://discord.gg/wolfire"&gt;https://discord.gg/wolfire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the curious, poll results are here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwA0gOrdZ9zyqPvD5vB0xj_2OYV9ijrJkUFgVqq1Flp3cqbg/viewanalytics"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwA0gOrdZ9zyqPvD5vB0xj_2OYV9ijrJkUFgVqq1Flp3cqbg/viewanalytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>kavika</author><guid>2394102381818941363</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 21:57:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Beta Updated (1523560849)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394102381818844714</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The SteamVR Beta has been updated with the following changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gamepads:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with gamepads going into “standby” mode even though buttons are being pressed on the gamepad.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;HTC Vive Pro:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Firmware update which improves audio quality.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Programmer Joe</author><guid>2394102381818844714</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 21:19:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How The Chinese Room rebuilt Dear Esther for a live tour</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2394102381818446769</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Dear Esther&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese Room cofounder and composer Jessica Curry summarises her initial pitch for a live performance of &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/dear-esther-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Dear Esther&lt;/a&gt; in a typically humorous manner: &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;ve had this possibly really bad and commercially unviable idea&amp;#x2014;how would you feel about it?!&amp;quot; She was speaking with the Barbican&amp;apos;s Contemporary Music Programmer, Chris Sharp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea came during a Film, Archive and Music Lab (FAMLAB) week Curry was attending. &amp;quot;They were talking about composers and how they work with silent film in terms of putting that into a concert experience,&amp;quot; she says. She began to ponder that in relation to her expertise in videogame music.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sharp has previously summed up the Barbican&amp;#x2019;s work as &amp;#x2018;Slightly Insane Ideas Made Reality&amp;#x2019;, so Curry&amp;#x2019;s proposal would seem a perfect fit for that remit. &amp;quot;They were amazing from start to finish,&amp;quot; she says of the Barbican. &amp;quot;They were really creatively on board with it but also incredibly practical, because what we quickly discovered is that it was technically really challenging.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the key challenges was that the live performance would require Dear Esther to be rebuilt. The most obvious reasons are that, for a live show with live narration and music, the existing music and narration needed to be stripped from the game. &amp;quot;I thought it can&amp;#x2019;t be that hard but you know what it&amp;#x2019;s like with game development&amp;#x2014;you change one thing and everything starts crashing around you!&amp;quot; says Curry. The game was five years old by then and The Chinese Room had to relearn the processes and idiosyncracies of the original in order to tweak it. &amp;quot;The QA involved in that was massive because so many dependencies had changed,&amp;quot; explains Curry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rewired&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conductor and actor also needed the game to provide cues for the different pieces of music or segments of script required. That meant re-evaluating how the tripwires in the game&amp;#x2014;the triggers for things like segments of dialogue&amp;#x2014;worked. In the original game the idea is that you get a different experience each time you play because there are a huge number of possible permutations.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#x2019;s fine when you have code handling those responses. When it&amp;#x2019;s a human on stage the limitations are different. Fellow Chinese Room cofounder Dan Pinchbeck thus needed to create a version of the script which catered to the limits of a human performer and to the fact that attendees would likely only attend one performance.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ask about the logistics of the tripwires given you&amp;#x2019;d need to factor in a few extra seconds for a human to respond to a prompt from the game. &amp;quot;Now you&amp;#x2019;re beginning to understand the fresh hell I led everybody into!&amp;quot; laughs Curry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;#x2019;t just figuring out cues and removing elements of audio. Invisible walls had to be added a week before the initial show to prevent the player falling off cliffs during a performance. There was also a long discussion about whether to keep or remove the game&amp;#x2019;s loading screens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curry tells me it was a conscious choice to leave the loading screens in. The idea was &amp;quot;to not apologise for it being a game&amp;quot; and instead to celebrate it. That&amp;#x2019;s how it worked for me, but others found it jarring. It&amp;#x2019;s a peculiarly technological moment in a very human performance.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In general, decisions about what to change and how were governed by whether they helped create a live version of the existing game experience rather than a separate, perhaps more theatrical, entity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That said, in game form Curry had been able to exert absolute control over how Dear Esther sounded at any given point. As a live performance, she had to figure out how to separate out the elements so they still worked cohesively but could be differentiated by the listeners. Each venue also introduced differences to the sound and the team had mere hours to figure out how to adapt each night.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having an experienced crew helped, as did a sound engineer with both live expertise and a more detached perspective: &amp;quot;Sometimes, because I knew the soundtrack so well in my head it was almost like I couldn&amp;#x2019;t hear a new version of it,&amp;quot; Curry says. &amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Centre stage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human player is another performance element which has changed over the tour. By the final UK date the PC monitors had gone from being side-on to facing the audience and the player was now lit in the same manner as the musicians. Curry and the team are still tinkering with that presentation for the international dates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Live performance also introduces the possibility that part of the show will break. As a result there are two projectors and two computers in place, plus a screenshot to cut to in the event of some tech failure and emergency music specifically written by Curry to cover downtime.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stresses aside, the resulting Dear Esther tour has been a rewarding and rejuvenating experience for Curry. The close-knit team offered a protective, nurturing environment, and the instant positive feedback of a live audience enthralled by her work has been a delight.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether the success here is transferrable to other live games events is a difficult question. Dear Esther is about 75 minutes long, was made on a tight budget with one narrator and few musicians, and is the product of a studio that&amp;#x2019;s interested in removing traditional &amp;#x2018;play&amp;#x2019; elements from games. It&amp;#x2019;s suited to a live show in ways that hundred-hour epics with action sequences and full orchestral scores aren&amp;#x2019;t. Regardless, Dear Esther&amp;#x2019;s live tour was a technologically fascinating and emotionally rewarding experience.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2394102381818446769</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 18:33:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Podcast: Bad games with a great story</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2394102381818426507</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for The Walking Dead&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-533873" src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/04/podcast-dreamfall-1b-620x319.jpg" alt="podcast-dreamfall-1b" width="620" height="319" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit down at the boiling pot, stranger. Let me tell you a tale. A sordid tale, full of fascinating lands and captivating characters. A story of wonder and flame, strangeness and warmth. Would you like to hear it? Great. Just play this rubbish cover shooter for a half hour. I   ll start the introduction when you hit the first checkpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the RPS podcast, the &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/the-rps-electronic-wireless-show/"&gt;Electronic Wireless Show&lt;/a&gt;. This week we   re discussing some great stories that come packaged with terrible games. &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/12/podcast-bad-games-with-a-great-story/#more-533849" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (RPS)</author><guid>2394102381818426507</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 18:00:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The best spy games on PC</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2394102381817941786</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Gunpoint&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spies come in many forms, so the best spy games on PC could be tense games about intrigue and infiltration, or high octane adventures starring a special agent. It would be good to see more games focusing on spycraft, espionage, and subterfuge, but we can make do with putting on some cool glowing goggles to infiltrate a base. Here are some of our favourite games starring awesome spies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alpha Protocol&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gloriously janky RPG from Obsidian that casts you as crack spy Michael Thorton. This was a brave attempt to combine Mass Effect style conversation and branching plot systems with a cover-based shooter. The combat side of things is a mess, so it&amp;#x2019;s worth looking up the different weapon classes so you know which disciplines to avoid (I found pistols worked well enough). It&amp;#x2019;s worth playing through the dodgy action to roleplay your favourite flavour of spy&amp;#x2014;pick your JB: Jason Bourne, James Bond, or Jack Bauer.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best thing about Alpha Protocol is the branching plot. The alliances you choose will change the order you visit each continental hub, and can have a huge impact on the characters you meet and the endings you unlock.&amp;#x2014;Tom Senior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This classic stealth sandbox came out 13 years ago, but still perfectly captures the thrill of being an action movie covert agent. It&amp;#x2019;s like Hitman, but you have cooler gadgets and the ability to suspend yourself above guards by doing the splits.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is Sam Fisher&amp;#x2019;s finest hour thanks to Michael Ironside&amp;#x2019;s performance and a darkly humourous script. Chaos Theory features some exceptional level design, and a decent co-op campaign that encourages you to co-ordinate sweet simultaneous takedowns from the shadows. &amp;#x2014;Tom Senior&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No One Lives Forever&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the few spy games to draw influence from the cheesy Man From Uncle meets Austin Powers 1960s idea of a spy adventure. As the glamorous Cate Archer you fight through jump out of planes, race bikes, scuba to sunken ships and other antics you might expect from Roger Moore era Bond. Every mission is different, and the whole adventure is played for laughs. It&amp;#x2019;s a difficult game to get hold of, and tough to get fully working on current machines, but it goes down as a great spy game in the PC gaming canon.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#x2014;Tom Senior&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SpyParty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paranoia is an important part of being a spy. Your cover could be blown at any moment, and the consequences are drastic. In fact someone could be watching you through a high-powered scope &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;. SpyParty captures this feeling in a series of small scenes&amp;#x2014;a party in a pub, a penthouse party, a boat party (spies love to party). One player plays a sniper, assessing the scene for any signs of spy-like behaviour. The other player is the spy. As the spy you have to blend in with NPCs as naturally as you can while you saunter around completing secret objectives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the spy you can see the sniper&amp;#x2019;s targeting laser moving through the room. It&amp;#x2019;s terrifying to see it flick from one side of the room to your forehead after you make a sloppy move. On the plus side you can see when the sniper is obsessed with innocent NPCs and use them as cover to plant that bug you need to win.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#x2014;Tom Senior&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Invisible, Inc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infiltrate high-security environments as a group of specialists in this hybrid of stealth game, turn-based strategy and roguelike. Get in, run the job, then get out again, and use your agents&amp;apos; different abilities to make it happen. This is a meticulous spy game where every wrong move can cost you dearly (you can rewind a turn if you&amp;apos;ve messed up that badly), but every well-executed strategy will make you feel like a badass.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best thing about Invisible Inc is that you can customise the parameters of a campaign to your preferences&amp;#x2014;adjust the amount of credits you get, how long each campaign goes on for and how many guards you can expect to find in each mission. Even though it gets real tricky, the difficulty is very much in your control. On additional playthroughs, you&amp;apos;ll unlock new agents who provide you with a different power base.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#x2014;Samuel Roberts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Covert Action&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sid Meier&amp;#x2019;s spy game was remarkably ambitious for 1990. You investigate randomly generated missions by infiltrating facilities, planting bugs, stealing files, tailing suspects and decrpting codes. Each of these activities has its own minigame. To decrypt a code you have to decode a scrambled message under time pressure. To infiltrate a building you pick a loadout, slip into the premises and start photographing documents with a microcamera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It looks ropey by today&amp;#x2019;s standards, but Covert Action has remarkable breadth of scope that few games attempt today. There&amp;#x2019;s a reason for that, perhaps. Sid Meier was unhappy with the disparate nature of the Covert Action&amp;#x2019;s minigames, and felt as though the activities detracted from the overall mission, which involved tracking down spies in a network to find the mastermind.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#x2014;Tom Senior&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;KGB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set in Russia during the last days of the Soviet Union, this brutally difficult point-and-click adventure sees you investigating corruption within the KGB&amp;#x2014;at least to begin with. Over the course of the game, protagonist Maksim, a KGB captain, finds himself swept up in a conspiracy involving the murder of a former agent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x2019;s from 1992 so it&amp;#x2019;s hardly the most slick or accessible of adventures, but its depiction of Cold War espionage is brilliantly done and uncompromisingly realistic in places. There are numerous ways to suddenly die, including being executed for speaking out of turn to your superiors. KGB was also released on CD-ROM under the name Conspiracy, featuring FMV cutscenes that starred Donald Sutherland as Maksim&amp;#x2019;s late father.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#x2014;Andy Kelly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Gunpoint&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steal secrets in (former PC Gamer staffer) Tom Francis&amp;apos;s stealthy puzzle/platformer, where you play a spy who can hack and control different parts of a building&amp;apos;s security system. What I remember liking about Gunpoint more than anything is its length&amp;#x2014;you&amp;apos;ll clear it in about three or four hours, but in that time you&amp;apos;ll go from being shot dead a bunch of times by guards to perfecting its systems and skilfully bounding in and out of buildings. It&amp;apos;s perfectly paced, with no unnecessary levels or dull bits.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you like immersive sims, this reframes most of their core elements into a 2D game. Plus you can smash your little spy guy through windows, which feels really good.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#x2014;Samuel Roberts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Metal Gear Solid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Tactical Espionage Action&amp;#x201D; is Metal Gear Solid&amp;#x2019;s tagline. In some ways the first game captures the spy fantasy better than the rest of the series, because in MGS Snake is an underdog rather than a legendary battlefield soldier. Snake&amp;#x2019;s hushed conversations with his handlers over intercom create a sense that you&amp;#x2019;re camped behind enemy lines, and it&amp;#x2019;s a dedicated stealth game. The worst thing you can do is get spotted by a guard. That brash alert noise is burned into my brain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x2019;s a good introduction to Kojima&amp;#x2019;s brainverse. Expect bizarre bosses and a tendency to reach through the fourth wall. The spy fantasy starts to falter when you get into the extraordinary melodrama of the finale, but overall it&amp;#x2019;s a clever spy game that stands up today. Now we just need the brilliant Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater to make the leap to PC.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#x2014;Tom Senior&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Neon Struct&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cyberpunk spy thriller that pays homage to Deus Ex, Neon struct is a slick heist game that challenges you to complete missions non-lethally. You have a bunch of sci-fi gadgets that can scramble gadgets and turn lights off at range, but its best move is a totally silent slide move that can get you out of trouble.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You explore city hubs between missions. That&amp;#x2019;s where you buy gadgets and stims that make you invisible in short bursts. It&amp;#x2019;s a neat little spy game with a stylish low-fi look, though Andy found the sparse sound design offputting in &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/neon-struct-review/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;our review&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&amp;#x2014;Tom Senior&amp;#xA0;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2394102381817941786</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 15:07:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The creators of Spelunky and Getting Over It talk about Sexy Hiking and 'B-games'</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2394102381815455359</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Spelunky&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sexy Hiking, by Jazzuo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexy Hiking was the original game about having to climb obstacles with a hammer controlled by a mouse. It was infuriatingly difficult. Back in August of 2007 Derek Yu, now known as the creator of Spelunky, wrote it up for his website &lt;a href="https://www.tigsource.com/2007/08/13/sexy-hiking/" target="_blank"&gt;TIGSource&lt;/a&gt;, saying &amp;quot;every new area seems totally impossible at first, and there is NOTHING THERE TO HELP YOU SAVE YOUR OWN GRIT.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This strange game about a cartoon man with floating hands was made by an enigma from Poland known as &amp;quot;Jazzuo&amp;quot;. Jazzuo released a string of B-grade games online, small and ugly and odd things with control schemes that seemed designed by aliens. While rarely remembered today, they were an important influence on the indie games that would follow&amp;#x2014;most obviously Sexy Hiking&amp;apos;s spiritual sequel Getting Over It with Bennett Foddy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We asked Yu and Foddy to talk us through the strange world of Jazzuo, and B-games in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting Over It with Bennett Foddy, by Bennett Foddy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PC Gamer: How did you get into Jazzuo&amp;apos;s games? What was the first one?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bennett Foddy:&lt;/strong&gt; I read about Sexy Hiking on Derek Yu&amp;#x2019;s TIGSource website back in, oh, 2007 or so. Even then it had been out for a number of years, but Derek revived it with this post. As he anticipated, it was an extremely controversial title in the TIGSource community. Adam Saltsman (of Canabalt and Overland fame) called it &amp;quot;the single worst game I have ever played&amp;quot;. Honestly, at the time I dismissed the game, but it became something of a meme among indie game developers, and I never really forgot about it. Years later, I changed my opinion of the game when I showed it to my students at NYU, as part of a class on games by European developers, and I realized how timeless the design was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think Getting Over It is great because it brought outsider art to the masses in a respectful way. But it's still worth experiencing the original&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Derek Yu&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derek Yu:&lt;/strong&gt; The things I loved about Sexy Hiking are what I assume people love about Getting Over It now&amp;#x2014;a unique and frustrating challenge coupled with a bizarre premise. Sexy Hiking does beat Getting Over It in one particular category, however, and that&amp;apos;s the title. While &amp;quot;Getting Over It&amp;quot; is a good name and Bennett was, for a long time, considered an expert namer of games on the TIGSource Forums, I think even he would agree that &amp;quot;Sexy Hiking&amp;quot; is one of the best game names of all time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BF:&lt;/strong&gt; Definitely one of the best titles! Other than Sexy Hiking, the best ones are Sexy Hand and GM Golf. Be careful, some of his games are in extremely poor taste!&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;GM golf challenge, by Jazzuo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the most essential ones to play&amp;#x2014;what&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;the Jazzuo canon&amp;apos;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DY:&lt;/strong&gt; He created another game in 2007 called &lt;a href="https://forums.tigsource.com/index.php?topic=485.0" target="_blank"&gt;Hermies the game&lt;/a&gt; that was very similar in concept to 2016&amp;apos;s Genital Jousting. I have no idea if the creators of Genital Jousting played Hermies, but either way it&amp;apos;s proof that Jazzuo was ahead of his time. He made the game for the TIGSource B-Games Competition (which was partly inspired by him) and it won 4.5% of the votes but did not win the competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What makes Jazzuo&amp;apos;s games so special to me is how raw they are. When I play a game by him or a similar creator, it always feels intimate and honest. As a game developer, it&amp;apos;s tempting to start obsessing over polish and making sure the player has a nice, comfortable time, and his games are a reminder that we&amp;apos;re also artists trying to express something of ourselves. I think Getting Over It is great because it brought outsider art to the masses in a respectful way. But it&amp;apos;s still worth experiencing the original, since there are some aspects that can&amp;apos;t be polished without losing something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BF:&lt;/strong&gt; People also talk very fondly about his Star Wars Episode VII, but it&amp;#x2019;s not online anymore and I haven&amp;apos;t tried it. I recommend his other &amp;apos;Sexy&amp;apos; game, Sexy Hand II, which is a golf game with a similarly unusual control scheme, and GM Golf which is like a fusion of Sexy Hiking and Sexy Hand. He made games that were completely unconnected to this series, but personally I think his experimentation with mouse controls led to the most timeless work.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Star Wars Episode VII, by Jazzuo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bennett, how did those students at NYU react to Sexy Hiking? And what is it you hope they get out of it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;BF:&lt;/strong&gt; They reacted in much the same way as indie developers did in 2007&amp;#x2014;they were polarized. Some of them became angry at it and refused to continue playing it, a few were captivated by it. I have showed so many old games to students, and honestly usually they can only take a dry academic interest because norms of user interaction and game design have moved on so much from the 80s and 90s. If they get really engaged in playing a game for enjoyment you know it must be timeless. Those games are really in the minority&amp;#x2026; obviously people still enjoy Mario and Mega Man, but it&amp;apos;s a real joy to me if I can find timeless games that American students are entirely unaware of: Alexei Pajitnov&amp;apos;s &lt;a href="http://www.mobygames.com/game/shawl" target="_blank"&gt;Shawl&lt;/a&gt;, David Braben&amp;apos;s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zarch" target="_blank"&gt;Zarch&lt;/a&gt;, Mike Singleton&amp;apos;s &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2012-10-21-dream-a-little-bigger-the-legacy-of-mike-singleton" target="_blank"&gt;Lords of Midnight&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elasto Mania, by Bal  zs R  zsa&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is it about Sexy Hiking in particular that appealed to you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BF&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;apos;m a big fan of messy, realtime physics puzzle games, going back to &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/how-a-17-year-old-community-is-keeping-elasto-mania-alive/" target="_blank"&gt;Elasto Mania&lt;/a&gt; (the original Trials physics game) and &lt;a href="https://www.fun-motion.com/physics-games/ski-stunt-simulator/" target="_blank"&gt;Ski Stunt Simulator&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;apos;s a huge area of inspiration in my own work. But more than that Sexy Hiking just makes a very arresting first impression; there&amp;apos;s something really unusual about how it looks, even though the quality is very low. I&amp;apos;m a big believer in the power of games that have an original and powerful &amp;apos;first screenshot&amp;apos;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes people who make B-movies end up becoming almost folk heroes, like Ed Wood or Tommy Wiseau, but that doesn&amp;apos;t seem to happen in games. We don&amp;apos;t have the same appreciation for B-games we have for B-movies. Why do you think that is?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;...the other god of B-game development from Jazzuo's period is MDickie, whose magnum opus is The You Testament, a game about Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Bennett Foddy&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DY:&lt;/strong&gt; Videogames are still young compared to movies and it takes time to foster that kind of appreciation. But Jazzuo is certainly a folk hero to a lot of people in the indie game community and there&amp;apos;s a YouTube video of someone beating Sexy Hiking which has over 128,000 views as I&amp;apos;m writing this. Hopefully Getting Over It will keep bringing him to people&amp;apos;s attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BF:&lt;/strong&gt; Culturally we just don&amp;apos;t recognize the individuals who make games, even in the cases of solo-authored games. Of course there are exceptions, like Jonathan Blow or the great Japanese auteur designers, but generally game reviews and previews don&amp;apos;t talk at all about the designers, game players don&amp;apos;t know who the designers are, and game designers work actively to make sure their identities are invisible in their games and sometimes even in the credits. This is one of the main reasons I decided to insert myself in Getting Over It with Bennett Foddy.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jazzuo&amp;apos;s a bit of an enigma, having disappeared from games entirely. Would you like to follow in his footsteps some day, just move on and leave a baffling legacy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BF:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, times are different, and I have given enough interviews now that I think people would have a pretty good idea of who I was and what I was trying to do, if I suddenly broke contact and moved to the mountains. But no, I hope to potter along making games, most of which will be pretty unpopular.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DY:&lt;/strong&gt; I plan on staying in games for a long time, but I understand wanting to dissociate from the industry at times. I try to only read and interact with the parts of gaming that are positive for me mentally. I realize that I&amp;apos;m fortunate to be able to do so&amp;#x2014;not everyone has that luxury. A baffling legacy sounds awesome, though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The You Testament, by MDickie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some other B-games you think are interesting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BF:&lt;/strong&gt; I think the other god of B-game development from Jazzuo&amp;apos;s period is MDickie, whose magnum opus is &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/crap-shoot-the-you-testamen" target="_blank"&gt;The You Testament&lt;/a&gt;, a game about Jesus. Other than that, well&amp;#x2026; B-game is a pretty loosely defined term, which blends into other groupings like &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kusoge" target="_blank"&gt;kusoge&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, and I think the heart of it is games that are deliberately unpolished. I love Pajitnov and Pokhilko&amp;apos;s &lt;a href="http://www.mobygames.com/game/magnetic-crane" target="_blank"&gt;Magnetic Crane&lt;/a&gt; from 1989, but it predates developers who thought of themselves as making B-games. I like that Cactus game &lt;a href="http://cactusquid.blogspot.com.au/2009/11/dungeon.html" target="_blank"&gt;Dungeon&lt;/a&gt;, and Messhof&amp;apos;s game &lt;a href="http://cargocollective.com/messhof/You-Found-The-Grappling-Hook" target="_blank"&gt;You Found the Grappling Hook&lt;/a&gt;. I love the Japanese B-Game &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fMIwpFwZCN8" target="_blank"&gt;Super Panda Ball&lt;/a&gt;, kind of like a B-game version of Zany Golf. And I guess even though it costs money, we could also count Justin Smith&amp;apos;s &lt;a href="https://captaingames.itch.io/rsss" target="_blank"&gt;Realistic Summer Sports Simulator&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favorite games of all time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DY:&lt;/strong&gt; I highly recommend checking out the work of Ikiki, MDickie, and thecatamites. If I had to pick a game from each to try first, it would be &lt;a href="https://www.tigsource.com/2007/06/11/nikujin/" target="_blank"&gt;Nikujin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.mdickie.com/prev_hardtime.htm" target="_blank"&gt;Hard Time&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://gamejolt.com/games/space-funeral/3492" target="_blank"&gt;Space Funeral&lt;/a&gt;, respectively. Ikiki&amp;apos;s &lt;a href="https://www.tigsource.com/2007/06/14/hakaiman/" target="_blank"&gt;Hakaiman&lt;/a&gt; is also great and was a major inspiration for Hotline Miami.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2394102381815455359</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 22:45:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Beta Updated (1523485324)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394102381815437027</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The SteamVR Beta has been updated with the following change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dashboard:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with some unreleased controllers not having a laser pointer in the dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Programmer Joe</author><guid>2394102381815437027</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 22:41:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The best and worst boss fights in PC gaming</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2394102381815165303</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for METAL GEAR SOLID V: THE PHANTOM PAIN, Undertale&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boss fights are great. Except when they&amp;apos;re terrible! &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/boss-fights-good-or-bad/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Things got heated&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when the PC Gamer staff debated whether the boss fight is good design or an antiquated videogame trope, so we decided to present our strongest evidence for each case. First up: a collection of our favorite bosses, the battles that have stuck with us for years. On page two, the list of shame: a whole bunch of bad, stupid bosses we hated fighting but love talking shit about. They all deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Master, Fallout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jody: &lt;/strong&gt;I&amp;apos;ve finished Fallout twice and never defeated The Master by just straight-up shooting him in the eyes or whatever other bits he has&amp;#x2014;he&amp;apos;s a mutant lump of flesh so unfathomable if you try for an aimed shot half of him is just labeled &amp;quot;???&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first time I made it to the end of Fallout it was with a sneaky, high-agility character who stealthed around his base and set off a nuke in it. The second time it was with a diplomatic, high-charisma type who talked the Master to death, choosing conversation options that exposed his flawed philosophy, made him realize his own monstrosity, and led him to suicide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;apos;s an option to just attack if you want to take the Master on with pulse grenades and a real big gun if that&amp;apos;s your thing, but the fact you don&amp;apos;t have to is what makes the climax of Fallout so great. Plenty of people hate bosses, so making them optional seems like such an obvious kindness it&amp;apos;s baffling that 21 years later it&amp;apos;s still uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Argus mech, Vanquish&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wes:&lt;/strong&gt; Japanese videogames have been chasing what I&amp;apos;ll call the Macross Aesthetic for decades: an overwhelming, awe-inspiring flurry of missiles crisscrossing the sky, white smoke arcing behind them. For years this was mainly a thing in 2D games: bullet hell SHMUPs and the incredible &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iWht7Eq9fEQ"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bangai-o&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Vanquish&amp;apos;s Argus mech, while a pretty straightforward &amp;quot;shoot the weak point&amp;quot; battle, is one of my favorite boss fights of all time because it completely delivers on the promise of translating the Macross missile explosion into 3D. And it looks unbelievably cool doing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deal the Argus mech enough damage, and it&amp;apos;ll stop firing at you with its cannon to unleash a volley of hundreds of missiles. It&amp;apos;s a stunning moment, but it&amp;apos;s also a perfect embodiment of what Vanquish is as a game. It&amp;apos;s a melding of over-the-top, distinctly anime Japanese action with the conventions of an American third-person shooter. In other words, there&amp;apos;s a cliche, gruff American antihero, but he wears power armor and kicks giant missile-spewing mechs so hard they explode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Artorias of the Abyss, Dark Souls&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin: &lt;/strong&gt;Artorias of the Abyss reads like a Dark Souls boss. He&amp;apos;s a tragic figure both emblematic of and integral to the overarching story of the Abyss DLC, and he&amp;apos;s characterized through NPC dialogue and descriptions embedded in weapons and armor. You don&amp;apos;t want to kill him, but he&amp;apos;s too far gone and you have no choice. That&amp;apos;s classic Dark Souls. But at the same time, he doesn&amp;apos;t &lt;em&gt;feel &lt;/em&gt;like a Dark Souls boss, and that&amp;apos;s what makes him so great.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the bosses in the original game are slow, lumbering monsters that you fight by nipping at their heels until they fall over. Artorias is the total opposite. He&amp;apos;s a relatively small but still incredibly imposing knight, and he moves wildly and quickly. His form and figure have been distorted by the abyss, but he&amp;apos;s still got the moves. You spend the entire game plinking away at behemoths in the 19 seconds it takes them to wind up an attack, and here comes Artorias with some freakin&amp;apos; front-flips. He fights like you, the player. He rolls like you, swings like you, retreats like you. He&amp;apos;s a refreshing, relentless wake-up call who gives you zero breathing room and feels like a Bloodborne or Dark Souls 3 boss, and I wouldn&amp;apos;t have it any other way.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r0VJ0Ub8fXA"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Jubileus, The Creator, Bayonetta&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin:&lt;/strong&gt; How else could a game as stylish and over-the-top as Bayonetta end if not in a galactic punchup? At this point in the game, you&amp;apos;re picking basic enemies out of your teeth and scraping titan-sized mini-bosses off your heels. Then Jubileus, the biggest of the big bads, descends from on high with a dozen health bars and multiple forms just askin&amp;apos; for an ass-kickin&amp;apos;.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jubileus is cleaner and more varied than most giant bosses, which have a tendency to play themselves. She has several distinct forms with unique attacks that expose cleverly placed weak points, and she gets better and better as you whittle her down. The level around you changes. Different weapons excel at damaging certain parts. It&amp;apos;s a long fight but it earns its runtime, and Jeanne&amp;apos;s role as partner manages to tie a climactic bow on the game&amp;apos;s otherwise tangled story.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She&amp;apos;s a great &lt;em&gt;final&lt;/em&gt; boss too, a delicious mix of everything Bayonetta does right: bonkers vehicle sections, short and forgiving quick-time events, dramatic camera angles and, of course, unforgettable finishers. I can think of no better way to send off one of Platinum Games&amp;apos; finest than pile-driving a god into the sun.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flowey, Undertale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wes Fenlon: &lt;/strong&gt;What a hell of an ending. Undertale is a game that constantly upsets your expectations, but its final boss&amp;#x2014;not exactly the &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; final boss, but that&amp;apos;s part of what makes the encounter so good&amp;#x2014;breaks away from Undertale&amp;apos;s aesthetic, and really from its reality. The fight tears at the structure of the game, making you survive an intense gauntlet, tempting you again and again to break from pacifism, before finally setting you up to play through parts of Undertale again to see the true ending. That ultimate battle is more emotionally affecting, but the first encounter with Flowey is where Undertale truly shows off how brilliantly it can execute on its meta ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QHDPr07hyzs"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dragonslayer Ornstein and Executioner Smough, Dark Souls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joe: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#xA0;I&amp;apos;ve killed Gwyn loads of times. I&amp;apos;ve both lit and walked away from the final bonfire. I&amp;apos;ve tackled Lordran&amp;apos;s brilliantly designed world in multiple configurations. I&amp;apos;ve watched countless walkthroughs and let&amp;apos;s plays. And yet no matter how many times I complete From Software&amp;apos;s gothic action role-player Dark Souls, I can never,&lt;em&gt; ever&lt;/em&gt;, beat Dragonslayer Ornstein and Executioner Smough on my first attempt without the help of Solaire.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I love it. I love the anticipation of trekking through Anor Londo, and stocking up for the big fight. I love swapping polite exchanges with the Giant Blacksmith as I upgrade my lightning halberd. I love grinding out a few extra souls levels with the Royal Sentinels that guard the boss arena. I love concocting an ill-conceived strategy in my head beforehand. I love saying to myself: &amp;quot;This is it. This is the moment I finally defeat these bastards first time without the help of the sunbro&amp;quot;, before inevitably peeling my splattered face from the forum&amp;apos;s floor thereafter.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You see, no matter how many times I&amp;apos;m floored by Ornstein and Smough, the fact that I&amp;apos;m yet to topple them on my lonesome gives me an excuse to return to one of my favourite games. With two hulking baddies&amp;#x2014;and one final form nemesis&amp;#x2014;this fight&amp;apos;s scope for change and incidental moments makes it, for me at least, near impossible to predict. It&amp;apos;s fast, it&amp;apos;s frantic, and no matter how many tries it takes, I&amp;apos;m yet to feel a similar sense of accomplishment from any other game.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, Dark Souls Remastered is just around the corner too. We go again, boys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mr Freeze, Batman: Arkham City&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samuel: &lt;/strong&gt;The bosses in the Arkham series are uneven, but the second game showed considerable progress over the first, which mostly featured repetitive encounters with larger enemies. Mr Freeze is a smartly-designed battle, letting the player use each technique at Batman&amp;apos;s disposal once&amp;#x2014;electricity, explosives and so on&amp;#x2014;before Victor Fries remembers that method and it can&amp;apos;t be repeated.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worse than that, he&amp;apos;s iced up the gargoyles so there&amp;apos;s no hiding from him above, which is a key part of your arsenal when trying to play Arkham stealthily. You&amp;apos;re stuck on the ground with Mr Freeze as he stalks you. A former colleague of mine compared it to a great Metal Gear boss fight, and he&amp;apos;s right&amp;#x2014;it&amp;apos;s similarly tricksy and demands clever thinking from the player. &amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MpxrkbVZwHY"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Monster Zoo, Dungeons of Dredmor&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evan: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#xA0;Can a room be a boss? I submit that a room can be a boss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uZU0g7edxuI"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#xA0;Jack Krauser, Resident Evil 4&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samuel: &lt;/strong&gt;Resident Evil 4 is one of very few games that gets away with QTEs, which have mostly died out in games over the past decade. Leon&amp;apos;s knife fight with Krauser is mostly cutscene-led, but it&amp;apos;s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uZU0g7edxuI"&gt;&lt;u&gt;a great example of the form&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#x2014;a tense sequence where you finally get to see the two characters face off.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The boss fight proper is great too, set in a maze of ruins where he&amp;apos;ll run at you with a knife, and it later escalates to a final battle on a precarious platform as Krauser mutates. Sometimes this encounter will transition into a QTE knife fight in-game, too, which is a nice touch. Resident Evil 4&amp;apos;s story is hokey but fun, and while you&amp;apos;re never quite emotionally invested, it&amp;apos;s fun to take the journey. You wait a long time to see Leon and Krauser finally face off, and the battle is exciting, over-the-top and even cinematic&amp;#x2014;it&amp;apos;s Resident Evil 4 at its best.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Transcendent One, Planescape: Torment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest failings of boss fights is how often they abandon the principles of the game they&amp;apos;re in, robbing you of agency or creativity in favor of a big arena slugfest or fancy cinematic. The opposite of that is Planescape: Torment, &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/best-rpgs-of-all-time/" target="_blank"&gt;maybe the best RPG of all time&lt;/a&gt;, which utterly commits to letting you talk your way out of conflict, up until the very end. There are a number of ways your encounter with The Transcendent One can end, including combat if that&amp;apos;s your wish. But dialogue, as always in Planescape, proves to be the more interesting option. Gaming rarely manages to get this philosophical, and even more rarely pulls it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Twisted Marionette, Guild Wars 2&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phil:&lt;/strong&gt; The Twisted Marionette was available for about a month during Guild Wars 2&amp;apos;s first update season. You can&amp;apos;t fight it anymore&amp;#x2014;you haven&amp;apos;t been able to fight it for over four years&amp;#x2014;but I still think it&amp;apos;s one of the best bosses I&amp;apos;ve defeated. Rather than an instanced encounter, the Marionette was an open world event that triggered every two hours. Players on the map would have to organise themselves into five lanes of (if you were lucky) around 25 players each. The fight had two main phases. The bulk of your time was spent in your lane, defending against waves of enemies. In addition, each lane took turns in the central chamber, where they were distributed across five mini-arenas&amp;#x2014;each with a Champion to defeat. Succeed, and one of the Marionette&amp;apos;s chains was cut. Fail, and you were one step closer to annihilation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If each lane succeeded, the battle was won and the Marionette would collapse. It felt elegant&amp;#x2014;requiring more coordination than just chipping away at a big monster&amp;apos;s health, but not so much that only the most hardcore servers had a shot of bringing it down. There was an arc&amp;#x2014;our server spent days unable to make the kill, but slowly started to refine our approach. We failed loads, but the process of learning, optimisation and eventually overcoming the challenge remains one of my favourite journeys within the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a  target="_blank"&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image via Speciesgame.com forums&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Aquifers, Dwarf Fortress&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wes Fenlon: &lt;/strong&gt;Yeah, goblins and elves and running out of booze are all bad news. But the truest enemy of any fortress builder is the mighty aquifer, an underground water source that can quickly and brutally flood your fortress if you don&amp;apos;t know how to deal with it. There&amp;apos;s an entire &lt;a href="http://dwarffortresswiki.org/index.php/DF2014:Aquifer"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Dwarf Fortress wiki page&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; devoted to aquifers and the strategies for defeating them. That&amp;apos;s a boss fight if I&amp;apos;ve ever seen one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Giant Terminator Baby, Mass Effect 2&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wes: &lt;/strong&gt;I&amp;apos;m not even going to dignify Mass Effect 2&amp;apos;s final boss with its proper name, such was its stupidity. The first Mass Effect culminated with a battle against an imposing, badass rogue agent whose role turns out to be more nuanced than pure evil, followed by a series of dramatic decisions that affected the fate of the Citadel. It was the perfect mix of action and roleplaying, exactly what Mass Effect should be. The second game, despite the overall brilliance of its suicide run final mission, decided to end with the equivalent of a Contra boss battle. A Contra boss battle that was too easy and looked absolutely ridiculous. When people complain about Mass Effect becoming too much of an action series, this fight is exhibit A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ivEih3gCdtU"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Arkham Knight drill fight, Batman: Arkham Knight&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jody: &lt;/strong&gt;The Arkham games had a couple of decent boss fights, but way more bad ones. They loved the kind where you have to lure some jacked-up beefy boy into charging, then dodge so he hits a wall instead. Arkham Knight managed to do the most drawn-out version of this, because you have to drive the goddamn Bat-Tank at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Arkham Knight attacks in the tunnels under Gotham, driving a digger drill like he&amp;apos;s a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MYepXKaS8YQ"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bananaman&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; villain. You have to lure him into sections wired with explosives, avoiding barriers and spinning fan blades, repeating this for what is probably just shy of 10 minutes but feels like hours. Meanwhile he shouts bland taunts like &amp;quot;You can&amp;apos;t hide!&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;ll find you!&amp;quot; to remind you that, after two games of Mark Hamill&amp;apos;s excellent Joker, now you&amp;apos;re up against a man who smolders with generic rage. I like the Arkham games, but they&amp;apos;re textbook examples of why 90 percent of boss fights could be dropped to no great loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image via Gameranx.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Zerst&amp;#xF6;rer Robots, Wolfenstein 2: The New Colossus&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin: &lt;/strong&gt;I&amp;apos;m generally a boss fight proponent, but Wolfenstein 2&amp;apos;s Zerst&amp;#xF6;rer Robots make a good case for cancelling bosses entirely. They simultaneously lack everything that makes Wolf 2 fun&amp;#x2014;multiple methods of approach, creative sightlines, playing execution leapfrog, satisfying feedback on kills&amp;#x2014;and exacerbate its biggest problems, like the way it sucks at telling you when you&amp;apos;re taking damage and where it&amp;apos;s coming from. &amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These robots have so much health and deal so much damage that you have no choice but to clear out the H-shaped airship you fight them on and take potshots from the interior tunnels, alternating exits each time. On higher difficulties at least, fighting them is a slow, repetitive process that isn&amp;apos;t even in the same hemisphere as fun. I played through the entire game a few notches above normal difficulty and loved the added challenge, but these piles of junk were so dragging and infuriating that I spitefully cranked the difficulty to easy just to get past them. And I&amp;apos;d do it again.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Se6RnbGl_c"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alma, F.E.A.R. 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wes: &lt;/strong&gt;What a piece of shit ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ghaul, Destiny 2&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin: &lt;/strong&gt;The final fight against Ghaul, leader of the Cabal&amp;apos;s Red Legion and the Darth Vader walrus-thing who destroyed the Tower, is a disappointment not just because of what is, but because of what it is not.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is&lt;/em&gt; a run-of-the-mill arena fight against a glorified Cabal Centurion. Ghaul himself is just a health bar with some knock-off powers. He&amp;apos;s removed from the fight most of the time, and whenever he does raise his ugly head you just one-shot him with your constantly refilled super. You spend more time fighting the basic enemies scattered around the ship, and doing so never feels climactic because the arena is boring, they&amp;apos;re the same old enemies and there aren&amp;apos;t even that many. Like, this is it, Red Legion. We are on your flagship. This is the final battle. The least you could do is bring the A-team.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the true misery of the fight is the cutscene that follows, in which Ghaul transforms into a much more interesting-looking plasma phantom and soars up to the Traveler. At this point, I&amp;#x2014;and by I, I mean everyone except the folks at Bungie apparently&amp;#x2014;thought, &amp;quot;Awesome, we get to kill him for real in the raid.&amp;quot; But no. He just melts right there, so instead we fight some random fat dude in the raid. Destiny YouTuber Datto said it best: &amp;quot;I want to fight the big thing.&amp;quot; Destiny 2 doesn&amp;apos;t let you fight the big thing, and that&amp;apos;s a bummer.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pinwheel, Dark Souls&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joe: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://darksouls.wikidot.com/pinwheel"&gt;&lt;u&gt;According to this Dark Souls wiki&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Pinwheel is: &amp;quot;A flying, multi-masked necromancer who stole the power of the Gravelord and reigns over the Catacombs. [It] spawns multiple copies of itself and attacks the player with projectile blasts.&amp;quot; All of which sounds pretty badass, right? Except in practice it&amp;apos;s not really like that. At all.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a game that prides itself on its challenging encounters, Pinwheel is an anomaly. This run in is not only easier than every other boss battle in Dark Souls, it&amp;apos;s easier than a fair whack of its standard enemies too. Its moveset is predictable, its cloned subordinates are a pain, and its drops&amp;#x2014;bar the Rite of Kindling&amp;#x2014;are rubbish. I almost lost the plot after my umpteenth death at the hands of Ornstein and Smough&amp;#x2014;yet the feeling of finally besting them was second to none. Pinwheel, on the other hand, robbed me of that eureka feeling by being so damn weak.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/darksouls/comments/155u5t/this_explains_why_pinwheel_is_so_easy/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;The suggestion&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that From Software expected players to invade the Catacombs early on goes a ways to explaining why Pinwheel in so underpowered later in the game, but the Catacombs itself is surely no place for pre-Anor Londo/Sen&amp;apos;s Fortress/Blighttown players. In any event, &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/this-dark-souls-mod-relocates-bonfires-npcs-enemies/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;FTRichter&amp;#x2019;s Prepare to Die Again mod&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reimagines a more formidable Pinwheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image via visualwalkthroughs.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fontaine, Bioshock&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wes: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;apos;s terrible. You have this great game, and then you end up fighting this giant nude dude. We didn&amp;apos;t have a better idea,&amp;quot; &lt;a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/glixel/features/inside-bioshock-video-game-series-with-ken-levine-w439921"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ken Levine once said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Well-put. Bioshock&amp;apos;s final battle ditched everything brilliant about the game to end with a cliche slugfest with a big muscular guy. The game clearly didn&amp;apos;t quite know where to go after the encounter with Andrew Ryan, but it definitely should&amp;apos;ve gone &lt;em&gt;somewhere else&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe force the player to sit through a reading of John Galt&amp;apos;s 80 page monologue from Atlas Shrugged? That would&amp;apos;ve been a better tonal fit, and a far greater challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N2n7_DSEAJA"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Eli, Metal Gear Solid 5&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samuel: &lt;/strong&gt;Hot damn, I hated this scrap with baby Liquid Snake where you couldn&amp;apos;t just use deadly weapons against him and be done with it. Fair enough, he&amp;apos;s a kid, but he&amp;apos;ll grow up to cause such trouble, what with the walking nuclear robots and inhabiting the mind of a man dressed &lt;a href="http://metalgear.wikia.com/wiki/Revolver_Ocelot"&gt;&lt;u&gt;a bit like a cowboy&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, you need to chase him around a beached ship until you can knock him out. And at that point, you&amp;apos;re &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; ready to do so.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of the boss fights in Metal Gear Solid 5 are that great, unfortunately, which is a shame for a series that has produced so many great ones in the past. MGS and MGS2, which both came to PC ages ago, have a slightly better hit rate, with the likes of Gray Fox in the former and Vamp in the latter. Luckily, The Phantom Pain is great at just about everything else.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BG9WVZ7zmog"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vaas, Far Cry 3&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris: &lt;/strong&gt;There&amp;apos;s a lot of bad boss fights in the Far Cry series, so it&amp;apos;s hard to pick just one. I&amp;apos;m going with Vaas because he&amp;apos;s probably the most enjoyable and memorable character in the series, and thus the crappy boss fight stings more than others because he frankly deserved a better sendoff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating a satisfying boss fight in a game where you&amp;apos;re essentially a superhero bristling with weapons and capable of withstanding tremendous amounts of damage yourself&amp;#x2026; it&amp;apos;s a challenge, really, because &lt;em&gt;you&amp;apos;re &lt;/em&gt;a damn boss. So, Ubisoft does what it always does when it&amp;apos;s painted itself into a corner: stuffs you full of drugs and makes you hallucinate. Welcome to a gloomy netherworld corridor paved with TV screens (for some reason) where Vaas after Vaas after Vaas run at you, die from a single bullet, and disappear into a puff of smoke. It&amp;apos;s not a test of endurance and skill, just patience. When every ghost Vaas is dead you get a cutscene where you do a cool hand-switching knife move that you can&amp;apos;t actually do in the game, then you watch him expire. You&amp;apos;re left with nothing other than a sense of disappointment and the sad fact that you&amp;apos;re still Jason Brody.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2394102381815165303</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 20:50:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Stardew Valley multiplayer could be ready in about a month </title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2394102381814282907</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Stardew Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2017/11/stardew-valley-multiplayer.jpg" title="Farmfriends." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long-awaited cooperative multiplayer mode is still on course to hit &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/stardew-valley/"&gt;Stardew Valley&lt;/a&gt; soon, going by what creator Eric &amp;#8220;ConcernedApe&amp;#8221; Barone has tapped out on the tweetosphere. Following &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/02/15/stardew-valleys-multiplayer-beta-expected-for-spring/"&gt;February&amp;#8217;s word&lt;/a&gt; that it was entering testing, Barone last night &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ConcernedApe/status/983762007466770433"&gt;offered&lt;/a&gt; the update: &amp;#8220;still making good progress on fixing bugs, if all goes well it should be ready in about a month&amp;#8221; on PC. Good, good. The plan had been to enter beta testing in spring and hell, I&amp;#8217;m not sure we&amp;#8217;ve even left winter yet. &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/11/stardew-valley-multiplayer-ready-in-about-a-month/#more-533789" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Alice O'Connor)</author><guid>2394102381814282907</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 14:46:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Steam overhauls privacy settings, locking SteamSpy out</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2394102381814144788</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Steam&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/04/steam.jpg" title="Steaming." width="620" height="310" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-533775" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valve have &lt;a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/1667896941884942467"&gt;overhauled&lt;/a&gt; the privacy settings for Steam user profiles, letting us hide more data and setting more of it to be hidden from strangers by default &amp;#8211; including the list of games you own. Good. More online platforms should default to hiding personal data. We can now hide our playtime on games if we want too, so our pals can e.g. see that we own The Binding of Isaac: Rebirth but not that we&amp;#8217;ve played it for e.g. 871 hours, in case we feel e.g. shame about that (not me: I&amp;#8217;ll tell you it&amp;#8217;s just that good).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does have the knock-on effect of locking out Steam Spy, the popular non-Valve site which scans vast numbers of public profiles to estimate how many people own a game and how much they play it. In a secretive industry, it&amp;#8217;s one of the few ways to have a sense of how well a game is doing. &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/11/steam-privacy-changes-block-steamspy/#more-533653" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Alice O'Connor)</author><guid>2394102381814144788</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 13:34:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Overkill's The Walking Dead shows off its second survivor</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2394102381813815236</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for The Walking Dead&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VNLzJuwKHFE"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overkill&amp;#x2019;s long-delayed but soon-to-appear cooperative zombie romp has been on the go for long enough so that someone really should have come up with a better name, one that won&amp;#x2019;t be confused with Telltale&amp;#x2019;s The Walking Dead. But maybe this is all part of the brand. AMC&amp;#x2019;s The Walking Dead, Telltale&amp;#x2019;s The Walking Dead, Overkill&amp;#x2019;s The Walking Dead. Before long we&amp;#x2019;ll all own a slice of the pie.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway! There&amp;#x2019;s a new trailer out, introducing one of the playable survivors, Maya. Her zombie apocalypse origin story is your typical slice of unrelenting misery porn. She gets stuck at work&amp;#x2014;we&amp;#x2019;ve all been there&amp;#x2014;when the undead attack, leading her and another doctor to fight back-to-back, struggling to survive against a tide of pesky cadavers. But oh no! Her friend gets bitten. We know how it goes from there.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maya&amp;#x2019;s spotlight is the second of two reveals so far. Her pal Aidan&amp;#x2019;s trailer is much more upbeat, however. Only kidding! It&amp;#x2019;s also very bleak.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/non_0jlOXew"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/overkills-the-walking-dead-confirmed-for-2016/"&gt;Two years of delays&lt;/a&gt; have tempered my enthusiasm, but unless Valve announces Left 4 Dead 3, Overkill&amp;#x2019;s The Walking Dead still might fill a big gap. It&amp;#x2019;s also a 4-player co-op FPS, though it introduces a base camp that can be protected and filled with supplies and survivors, too. And like Overkill&amp;#x2019;s other co-op FPS, Payday, each character comes with their own skill trees and roles.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Walking Dead is due out this autumn.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2394102381813815236</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 11:50:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Learning to walk (and work) again in Stardew Valley</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2394102381811910408</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Stardew Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a warm October night, I woke to find my leg felt like it was on fire. My ability to walk around had been deteriorating for the last month, to the point of being sent home from work. Eventually getting out of bed had become a herculean task, my knee swollen to unnatural size, and my back locking up at the slightest motion. At the unusually young age of 25, I was diagnosed with Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA), a chronic autoimmune disorder that aggressively attacks the body&amp;apos;s joints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though my doctors have told me I&amp;apos;ll recover with time, the past months have been an excruciating reevaluation of how I spend that time, and how much I took for granted the ability to hop from task to task. Unable to walk unassisted or return to my day job for the better part of a month, I fell into depression, lamenting my inability to focus on my work or the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until, that is, I visited the rolling pastures and shimmering beaches of Stardew Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With its rows of corn, baby chickens, and charming librarians to woo, Stardew Valley has uniquely tapped into the sense of pride that comes with a hard day&amp;apos;s&amp;#x2014;and a hard year&amp;apos;s&amp;#x2014;work. From the opening moments as you flee your dreary office job for the untamed fields of your late grandfather&amp;apos;s farm, Stardew Valley pins all your hopes and dreams on your willingness to work slowly towards a goal, one step at a time. It&amp;apos;s been instrumental in recentering my drive to get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the smartest thing the game does is push you out that cabin door with almost zero guidance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;apos;ve never been one for life simulators. The warm charm of early Harvest Moons couldn&amp;apos;t capture my Pokemon-obsessed attention, I enjoyed visiting friend&amp;apos;s homes in The Sims more than making my own, and the anthropomorphic debt collectors of Animal Crossing couldn&amp;apos;t sell me on a new mortgage. Why play out a normal life when you can live a high-flying fantasy? It&amp;apos;s an easy perspective to have, until your sense of normality is threatened or outright taken from you. Suddenly, the ability to build the ideal living space or the ideal routine is as much a fantasy as hunting robot dinosaurs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;apos;s see if this sounds familiar. It&amp;apos;s 6 a.m. and time to hop out of bed. You take a minute to check the weather, step out, breathe in the air, and then it&amp;apos;s off to your daily tasks. There&amp;apos;s the matter of what to do with your afternoon, but for now, those rows of tomatoes need watering, your chickens need feeding, and those eggs aren&amp;apos;t going to magically transform into mayonnaise themselves. As much as Stardew Valley&amp;apos;s activities are farm-based, its most universal diversion may be the moment you just stand on your porch, thinking of how much you can cram into the day&amp;apos;s schedule.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;apos;s one thing real life has over Stardew Valley&amp;apos;s small-town charm, it&amp;apos;s that my doctor is infinitely more available. But for those first few weeks, even my regular physician was stumped by my rapidly expanding kneecap. With my family insurance only covering one busy rheumatologist, the following weeks were a torturous blend of waiting, uncertainty, experimentation, and more waiting. After my leg was drained of inflammatory fluid, I was ordered two weeks off work&amp;#x2014;which only gave more time for aimless thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;apos;m sure the protagonist of Stardew Valley had their share of questions (both actual and existential) when they first arrived. A new stage of life, unfamiliar tools, and a feeling that nothing will ever be quite the same again. Perhaps the smartest thing the game does is push you out that cabin door with almost zero guidance. There&amp;apos;s the occasional letter from a neighbor, but other than that it&amp;apos;s on you to learn the steps to grow and maintain an entire farm, to say nothing of integrating into Stardew&amp;apos;s tight-knit community.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even after my diagnosis, and with the direction of a trained specialist, I still felt that uncertainty and inexperience gnawing at me. What does my immediate and long-term future look like? How will the medicine and tools given to me impact my physical and mental health? Is this something I&amp;apos;ll have to worry about forever?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And like Stardew Valley&amp;apos;s protagonist, I&amp;apos;ve come to find comfort in the small gains I make each day. In planting rows of corn I&amp;apos;m strapping myself in for one of the game&amp;apos;s lengthier waiting periods. At times, it can feel like the plants are mocking me, barely growing over the course of 24 hours. But after 14 long days of labor, I finally have these majestic stalks of gold. Since my social pursuits mainly consist of fawning over Penny the redhead tutor, I also grow a small grouping of poppy flowers just for her birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stardew Valley reminds me that the most meaningful goals are things you have to wholly dedicate yourself to&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many days, though, it&amp;apos;s not about some great payoff. Sometimes you just need to chop wood and chisel stone until you can&amp;apos;t anymore. Stardew takes it one step further with your energy meter, forcing you to calculate just how much you&amp;apos;ll need to save to make it home from your fishing trip. Any kind of personal upkeep is like that, really, laced with days and days of menial, repetitive actions meant to keep a simple wheel turning, hopefully with enough foresight to account for tomorrow&amp;apos;s work. From time to time I still need to remind myself that I&amp;apos;m not quite the semi-invincible man I once was, bounding upstairs for a fourth time because I forgot my keys or hustling from customer to customer at my day job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stardew Valley&amp;apos;s cycle of honest living has become my (hopefully temporary) fantasy, but it&amp;apos;s also grounded me in reality in a way no game had the chance to before. The thrill I get from hiking into town for the annual festival or exploring the beaches for treasure&amp;#x2014;simply moving about my day at an energetic pace&amp;#x2014;is one that still feels like something I can eventually return to in real life. And sure, those fantasies are something that can explored in any game with a wide enough world to journey through, but coupled with my responsibilities as a caretaker of self and soil, Stardew Valley reminds me that the most meaningful goals are things you have to wholly dedicate yourself to, even when their fruits are but bumps in the earth.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A seed becomes a farm, an unexpected encounter becomes a loving bond, and with enough work, an injury becomes a distant memory.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2394102381811910408</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 23:12:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Stardew Valley's multiplayer update "should be ready in about a month"</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/eurogamer/2394101748817906984</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/b&gt; for Stardew Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://cdn.gamer-network.net/2018/articles/2018-04-10-22-28/stardew-valleys-multiplayer-update-should-be-ready-in-about-a-month-1523395736752.jpg/EG11/resize/300x-1/format/jpg/1966168.jpg" alt=""/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stardew Valley creator Eric "ConcernedApe" Barone has offered a new update on the farming sim's long-awaited multiplayer mode, revealing that it "should be ready in about a month".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The news comes &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ConcernedApe/status/983762007466770433" target="_blank"&gt;via a tweet posted earlier today&lt;/a&gt;, in which Barone noted that the team is "still making good progress on fixing bugs", and that next month's expected finish date would be hit provided that "all goes well". Barone later clarified that the tweet was specifically in reference to Stardew Valley's PC, Mac, and Linux versions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in February, when Barone &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2018-02-16-stardew-valley-creator-says-new-multiplayer-features-are-done-still-hopeful-of-spring-beta"&gt;last spoke&lt;/a&gt; of Stardew Valley's next major update, work on all planned features - that is, the &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2017-11-15-stardew-valley-is-getting-new-single-player-content-after-all"&gt;new single-player story content&lt;/a&gt;, and as well as the highly anticipated co-operative multiplayer mode - was said to be "done".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2018-04-10-stardew-valleys-multiplayer-update-should-be-ready-in-about-a-month"&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2394101748817906984</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 22:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Stardew Valley multiplayer 'should be ready in about a month,' creator says </title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2394101748817372559</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Stardew Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stardew Valley multiplayer could be finished as early as next month, according to a recent &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ConcernedApe/status/983762007466770433" target="_blank"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; from creator Eric Barone. &amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/stardew-valley-multiplayer-update-is-in-qa-beta-expected-in-spring/" target="_blank"&gt;In February,&lt;/a&gt; publisher Chucklefish said the multiplayer update has entered QA testing. &amp;quot;Work on the new features is done, and we&amp;#x2019;ve sent all the new text off to be translated into the different languages,&amp;quot; Barone said at the time, adding that a public beta should be available for spring, which is consistent with today&amp;apos;s update.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/stardew-valley-multiplayer-mod/" target="_blank"&gt;you can play modded multiplayer right now.&lt;/a&gt; It just takes a little elbow grease.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2394101748817372559</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 18:12:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Beta Updated (1523314681)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748814503055</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The SteamVR Beta has been updated with the following changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SteamVR Home:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;crash fixes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;General:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed occasional crash that occurred in settings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SteamVR Dashboard:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with some custom controller models preventing the laser pointer from appearing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vive Pro:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enabled support for night-mode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oculus Touch:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed the A and B buttons on the right touch controller.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Joe Prime</author><guid>2394101748814503055</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 23:14:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Updated (1512445023) - Hotfix</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748814324021</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
SteamVR has been hotfixed with the following changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;General:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed occasional crash that occurred in settings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SteamVR Dashboard:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with some custom controller models preventing the laser pointer from appearing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Programmer Joe</author><guid>2394101748814324021</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 22:03:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wormhole Wars is the Portal arena deathmatch of your dreams</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2394101748809080591</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Portal&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/04/WWars-pic-2-620x300.png" alt="WWars-pic-2" width="620" height="300" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-532975" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every game needs to reinvent the wheel. Or even involve themselves in this business of wheels. Sometimes you need only grab a few universally beloved things and jam them together. If you had an arena multiplayer shooter that combined the best levels of Halo with the constant world-bending of Portal and added a dash of the best parts of Overwatch, well, that&amp;#8217;s what &lt;a href="http://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/wormhole-wars"&gt;Wormhole Wars&lt;/a&gt; looks like it wants to be. And that&amp;#8217;s what I want it to be too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/08/wormhole-wars-is-the-portal-arena-deathmatch-of-your-dreams/#more-532973" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Brock Wilbur)</author><guid>2394101748809080591</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 10:11:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SteamVR Beta Updated (1523037268)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748802882735</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for SteamVR&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The SteamVR Beta has been updated with the following changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;General:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed issues with plugging in an HMD after SteamVR starts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SteamVR Tracking:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;SteamVR 2.0 basestations report channels in VRMonitor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved startup performance (time until bootstrap) for SteamVR 2.0 bases&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Programmer Joe</author><guid>2394101748802882735</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 18:04:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Friday Facts #237 - Rich  interactive text</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748802709681</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Hello,&lt;br /&gt;since 0.16 is stable we can assign more of our effort into the work on 0.17. One of those features planned for that release is the Rich &amp;amp; interactive text.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Having more text formatting options was one of the things we wanted for quite some time, and it is finally starting to become reality in the 0.17 branch.The initial motivation was to have more possibilities in the tutorial related texts, but it proved to be useful having it available globally in the game.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The current format for any text markup we use is [&amp;lt;type&amp;gt;=&amp;lt;value&amp;gt;], but it might change somehow before 0.17 hits the public. This feature is being developed by wheybags, and it is progressing forward quite steadily.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Basic text formating - font and color&lt;/h2&gt;The obvious option is to allow changing text color:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/b6e7080d3b90b681d82b36b3cf2e94136a1860f8.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;and to allow to change font:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/c8c572e4111fbf452b4fd6d7f49182821a1b199e.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Images - icons&lt;/h2&gt;Since we already have a system to specify icons by the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://lua-api.factorio.com/latest/Concepts.html#SpritePath"&gt;SpritePath&lt;/a&gt;, we can use it as well:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/61696aba705e6f0166bdea8d3e6c6930e7b19ae9.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The cool thing about this, is that all these concepts work on basically all places where text is used, so you can use it in the station name for example:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/fa36a0e30a31760cfdfa9f39d7a45944f8eca28c.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;or even save names (although, I needed to add a possibility to use &amp;quot;.&amp;quot; instead of &amp;quot;/&amp;quot; in sprite path resolution to make it possible):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/1d2746549bf42a83c8e301e12545747f3d37948d.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;or blueprint names:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/1d2746549bf42a83c8e301e12545747f3d37948d.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Element references&lt;/h2&gt;The next planned step will be to make it possible to allow this not only to be used as icons, but as references to the actual items, so the syntax would be something like:[item=straight-rail] or [recipe=advanced-oil-processing]. When used in the chat, it should allow the reader to hover over the icon and get a tooltip of the corresponding game element. When used with technology, it could allow the user to open the mentioned technology by clicking the reference icon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;More advanced usages&lt;/h2&gt;This brings us to the more advanced possibilities, like linking a map position as a clickable icon in the text (something like [gps=&amp;lt;position&amp;gt;]), referencing your armor, so other&amp;#39;s can just hover it in the text and see it. Specifying target to specific train you want to mention and mainly, being able to reference blueprints this way, something like [blueprint=&amp;lt;blueprint string&amp;gt;] can you to show some specific setup in a chat, and others could be able to get the blueprint by just clicking on the icon if they want to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I would be quite curious to see what other type of usages of this can you come up with, let us know on the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://forums.factorio.com/59401"&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Klonan</author><guid>2394101748802709681</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:55:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Unknown Pleasures: A doughty dozen new Steam games</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2394101748802740222</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Steam&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/04/unknownpleasures-mar-2018-620x320.png" alt="If you don&amp;#039;t immediately try to kill all the friendly NPCs, you&amp;#039;re doing it wrong." width="620" height="320" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-531239" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/unknown-pleasures/"&gt;Unknown Pleasures&lt;/a&gt; has been on unplanned hiatus as I have been grotesquely ill. The lack of communication or cover was entirely my fault, and I apologise for that unreservedly (and extend further thanks to the Hivemind for their extraordinary patience). I&amp;#8217;m sorry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, hang on, Adam&amp;#8217;s leaving. I can blame him! It was Adam, everyone! Shake your indignant fists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a bumper of 12 games this week, and then we&amp;#8217;ll be back to normal.  So, assaulting our ailing bodies this week: third party candidates, pugilistic ducks, and a JRPG that wait where are you going no come on, be fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/06/unknown-pleasures-a-doughty-dozen-new-steam-games/#more-531237" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Sin Vega)</author><guid>2394101748802740222</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:00:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Steam Machines aren t exactly flying off the shelves but Valve are sticking with Linux</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2394101748801597035</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Steam&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com//images/14/jan/alienwaresteam.jpg" title="An old, old Steam Machine." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steam Machines went nowhere, Valve have basically said (I&amp;#8217;m paraphrasing a touch), but nah, don&amp;#8217;t sweat it, they are still committed to improving gaming on Linux. After shuffling Steam Machines deeper into the labyrinth of Steam&amp;#8217;s website menus, and the ensuing cybersquawking over Valve having done a thing, they&amp;#8217;ve reflected a little on their PC branding partnership and the Linux-based SteamOS beneath it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Given that this change has sparked a lot of interest, we thought it&amp;#8217;d make sense to address some of the points we&amp;#8217;ve seen people take away from it,&amp;#8221; Valve&amp;#8217;s Pierre-Loup Griffais &lt;a href="http://steamcommunity.com/app/221410/discussions/0/1696043806550421224/"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. Internet, eh? &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/06/steam-machines-arent-exactly-flying-off-the-shelves-but-valve-are-sticking-with-linux/#more-532161" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Alice O'Connor)</author><guid>2394101748801597035</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 09:24:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March Map Jam - Jam is now complete, come play some mods!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748800720682</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Overgrowth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The March map jam, &amp;quot;The Protagonist Dies at the End,&amp;quot; is now complete. Everyone is invited to come play the new mods, and vote on their two favorites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can check out the jam entries here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=25000&amp;requiredtags%5B0%5D=march2018jam&amp;actualsort=mostrecent&amp;browsesort=mostrecent&amp;p=1"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=25000&amp;requiredtags%5B0%5D=march2018jam&amp;actualsort=mostrecent&amp;browsesort=mostrecent&amp;p=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We had 15 entries in total, and a lot of work was put in. Several entries focused on making a single map. Several others chose to make multi-level campaigns, and one entry is a new game mode!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Voting for the winner has now begun. Please play as many of the entries you can before casting your vote.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everyone gets two votes, and voting will be open until April 12th (7 days in total):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://goo"&gt;https://goo&lt;/a&gt; .gl/forms/QSn7L80WJ6p5KPk32&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Link is to the poll. The link is separated since it said &amp;quot;link removed&amp;quot; without it. Copy/paste the link, and remove the extra space)</description><author>kavika</author><guid>2394101748800720682</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 03:42:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Update 322 Live on Steam!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2394101748799073153</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Natural Selection 2&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://unknownworlds.com/ns2/files/2018/04/322-blog.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Update 322 is now live on Steam! This update is primarily a maintenance patch. Over the last few months lots of new systems and features have been introduced to the game and with those additions have come some small issues and strange new bugs. Hopefully this update will address those reported issues and get us back on solid ground. The dev team continues its work on the UGC conversion from Steam Workshop which is slated for 323. Always more to come, including something very special that could come with 323 as well, so stay tuned!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changelog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gameplay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved sentries slightly (contributed by Nin)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Prevent beeping noise while attacking and for 1.5 seconds afterwards&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Speed up barrel swivel when it has a target so you&amp;#39;re not getting shot at by a sentry facing the other way&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Add a delay after shooting at a target before starting to swivel and scan again&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Always show tracers from sentries so that players better know where they are getting shot at from&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Sentries will prioritize players over other things, and will shoot at the closest players. Previously, they would prioritize anything that wasn&amp;#39;t a cyst.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Hydras do not block each other’s line of sight anymore (contributed by Katzenfleisch)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tweaks / Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tweaked some marine pickup icons to appear more stylistically consistent.  (Thanks Sinakuwolf!)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Metabolize is no longer a switchable weapon.  This means you cannot accidentally switch to it any longer, and can only use it via the MovementModifier key.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Drifter Eggs can now be issued orders that will be carried out by the drifter when it hatches.  Before, drifters could only be issued rally-points.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;AI movers such as ARCs and movable alien structures like Crags would move on top of players, sometimes trapping them.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Tweaked the infestation shader slightly to better hide the hard edges of infestation circles.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Don’t show team resources for the Ready Room team at the scoreboard.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that servers could get stuck in a infinite loop while filling teams up with bots.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that bots were not removed properly after they got kicked.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where ARCs would sometimes leave collision ghosts behind in PredictWorld.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that the &amp;quot;They Came From Behind!&amp;quot; achievement was granted in some incorrect circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that dying in an Exosuit would cause players to lose their unused grenades.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where some commander buttons would not work if multiple entities were selected, despite the button being visible.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where sometimes the lines connecting queued orders in the commander interface would be connected in the wrong order.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where a marine&amp;#39;s welder and mines could be &amp;quot;stolen&amp;quot; from them at the map origin if that player was inside an exosuit.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the build tool would be stuck building if the player picked up a welder while they were building a structure.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where players could be stuck attacking during a concede sequence.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the wrong tech point would be visible during a concede sequence.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where MACs could not be told to repair destroyed power nodes.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where MACs would sometimes disregard their orders to move to some previous location.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where sometimes clicking the &amp;quot;refresh&amp;quot; button in the server browser would cause the game to crash.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where deploying an ARC would prevent all future corrosion damage to the ARC, including after un-deploying the ARC.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a script error occuring if an Onos died while using stampede.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that gorges couldn’t recycle the second tunnel entrance they placed (contributed to Katzenfleisch)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a script error that occured if a marine had no active weapon (contributed to Katzenfleisch)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed various text positioning/visibility bugs of the GUIChat (contributed by Person8880)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fixed that the marine commander action notifications below the minimap often did not  display the correct location name.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed the reflections in ns2_veil.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Editor    &lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exposed antialiasing and ambient occlusion settings for the map Editor.&lt;/li&gt;      &lt;li&gt;Changed some popup messages to be console messages instead.&lt;/li&gt;        &lt;li&gt;Added debug utility methods to simplify dealing with upvalues (locals inside method/file scope) (contributed by Las)    &lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Please read core/lua/DebugUtility.md for more details!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>WasabiOne</author><guid>2394101748799073153</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 16:46:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Factorio updates with heavy artillery and optimizations</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2383968628754439903</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-531693" src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/04/ss_540ca754647d925458f599576e968478f7db5d8a-620x300.jpg" alt="Factorio" width="620" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The horrifically compelling sci-fi construction sandbox &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/factorio/"&gt;Factorio&lt;/a&gt; received &lt;a href="https://www.factorio.com/blog/post/016-stable"&gt;another major update&lt;/a&gt;  over the holidays, bringing much-needed performance improvements to the game along with adding a whole new subset of heavyweight military technologies. This update also marks the start of the final stretch of development, with Wube Software announcing that &lt;a href="https://www.factorio.com/blog/post/016-price-change"&gt;the price of the game will be increasing to $30&lt;/a&gt; later this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/04/03/factorio-updates-with-heavy-artillery-and-optimizations/#more-531679" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Dominic Tarason)</author><guid>2383968628754439903</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 19:36:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The best and worst in-game books and codexes</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2383968106583431139</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Deus Ex: Human Revolution&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literature&amp;#x2019;s had a pretty good run, much of it without any fancy graphics and animations and particle effects to bolster the words. Games love text too. Text is cheap. You can paint a picture of galactic chaos or epic history in about the same time it takes to type &amp;#x2018;and then something cool happened&amp;#x2019;, without having to spend the next week designing armour and creating 3D characters to act it out. Yet despite centuries of practice, most games still haven&amp;#x2019;t worked out how to present all this (which let&amp;#x2019;s face it, is often there more for the writers&amp;#x2019; satisfaction than our actual enjoyment) in a punchy, satisfying way. What works? What doesn&amp;#x2019;t? Let&amp;#x2019;s take a quick look at some of the ways games have handled books, letters, codexes and more.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deus Ex: Human Revolution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when you don&amp;#x2019;t affect a world that much, it&amp;#x2019;s nice when it pretends. News stories are one of the best and cheapest ways to both highlight your achievements, and reframe them in interesting ways, from acts of heroism to outright terrorism. Human Revolution wrapped them in one of the sleekest packages for this&amp;#x2014;the Picus Daily Standard. At once a chance to see what was taking place out of your sphere, and see the effect of your adventures on the world. While even a few years later, the futuristic look feels distinctly retro compared to iPad news apps, to say nothing of whatever direct-brain interfaces we&amp;#x2019;ll likely have by the time of Deus Ex&amp;#x2019;s dark not-too-distant-future, Picus keeps it pretty, keeps it punchy, and above all, keeps it brief.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deus Ex: Mankind Divided&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, but when it comes to eBooks, things aren&amp;#x2019;t so smooth. Look at this. Even the original Kindle would wince at these datapad layouts, complete with non-slidable panels, slow refresh rate, poor quality fonts and typography, and non-consistent use of glows. Sure, it&amp;#x2019;s readable, but it&amp;#x2019;s hard to imagine anyone wanting to, even before factoring in that in the wasteful future of Deus Ex you apparently need a new device for every Wikipedia entry. The crappy quality of this design only stands out more amongst Mankind Divided&amp;#x2019;s otherwise superbly rendered future, where everything you encounter seems to have emerged fully formed from the brain of a maverick product genius. This, meanwhile, feels like a first attempt at customising Twine.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fallout 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the not-too-distant future, who needs books? We&amp;#x2019;ll have computers! Specifically, ghastly green teletype machines that would be tolerable for simple acts like opening doors, but could be much more of a nightmare if the cast of Five Nights At Freddy&amp;#x2019;s occasionally popped up for a jump-scare. The horrible font. The clackering of the text. The endless pages that try their best &amp;#xA0;to tell stories of post-apocalyptic horror, despite being locked in an interface that would make even a hardened wasteland explorer decide that whatever happened probably doesn&amp;#x2019;t matter that much. Even accounting for the 50s vibe of the rest of the game, these are hideous technological throwbacks that knife their own storytelling in the back. The closest they come to being appropriate to the setting is that in using them, the living definitely envy the dead.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Skyrim / Ultima&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#x2019;s an RPG shelf without a few strangely short books that probably don&amp;#x2019;t need hundreds of pages and a stiff leather jacket? While RPGs have always been wise enough to realise that most players will accept this deviation from reality, it&amp;#x2019;s still interesting to look at the differences between these two great franchises. Skyrim for instance clearly assumes that all of Tamriel&amp;#x2019;s readers are half-blind&amp;#x2014;or possibly playing on a television screen&amp;#x2014;leading to very slow-paced tales on glorified flashcards. Ultima meanwhile wanted you to squint. But at least Ultima had the advantage that unless a book was specifically screaming &amp;#x2018;crucial plot element&amp;#x2019;, it was most likely to be flavour, sparing you tediously flicking through shelves in the hope of finding a boost to one of your skills. At least both franchises keep their tongues firmly in their cheeks, whether it&amp;#x2019;s The Elder Scrolls&amp;#x2019; obsession with the Lusty Argonian Mage, or Ultima&amp;#x2019;s fine line of joke books, occasional explosive booby-trap pranks, and the revelation that wise Lord British, founder of Britannia&amp;#x2019;s favourite story is &amp;#x201C;Hubert the Lion&amp;#x201D;. Can&amp;#x2019;t sleep without it, apparently...&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A controversial one here, perhaps, but Mass Effect is one of the games where the built-in Codex arguably makes the world less enjoyable. The game does a fantastic job of introducing everything that&amp;#x2019;s actually important without relying on it as a crutch, with the dry writing and endless unlockable pages of SF guff coming across as homework rather than a gripping read. Do we really need to know, for example, the origins of every last whiffle-bolt supplier on the Citadel? No. It&amp;#x2019;s just not that important. Save it for the design bible and tie-in books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While there are a few interesting flourishes, including Codex entries based on what the universe thinks rather than necessarily the actual truth, the Hitch-Hiker&amp;#x2019;s Guide To The Galaxy it is not. And ironically, it shows the difference itself, in the form of Mass Effect 2&amp;#x2019;s fantastic Shadow Broker DLC and the unlockable files within, which actually do give you a chance to peer at your party&amp;#x2019;s dirty little secrets. Jack&amp;#x2019;s secret love of poetry. Miranda&amp;#x2019;s online dating life. Tali&amp;#x2019;s repeated installation of a suit tool called &amp;#x2018;Nerve Stim Pro&amp;#x2019;. Oh, the blackmail opportunities...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dishonored 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dishonored is a great example of how just a little thing can really annoy. Its text isn&amp;#x2019;t difficult to read, the font is pretty well chosen, if not exactly conveying the sense of a written document in the same way as many other games with this level of texture and detail, but does it really have to sway back and forth while you&amp;#x2019;re reading? There&amp;#x2019;s a time for ambient animation to breathe life into a scene, and a time to make the player feel slightly sea-sick. No. Scratch that. True for the first, not so much for the second. Swish&amp;#x2026; swish&amp;#x2026; it&amp;#x2019;s an effect applied to all the menus and other data screens and really contributes to making reading the lore an unpleasant experience. A shame, because that lore is actually interesting. Dunwall and Karnaca are two of gaming&amp;#x2019;s best cities, and their depth and backstory is fascinating. If you can stand to actually read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Longest Journey and Life Is Strange&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;apos;m bundling these together because they do the same basic concept&amp;#x2014;the primary text in the game is our main character&amp;#x2019;s diary. This serves several purposes, including offering a potted version of the story if you dip away for a while and forget things, but most importantly giving us a direct look inside their head. It&amp;#x2019;s a technique that only works if you actually like the main character, but fortunately that&amp;#x2019;s not a problem for either series and its charismatic leading ladies. In particular, it&amp;#x2019;s a way of bridging the gap between our perception of the game, as an untouchable god-figure, and theirs, as someone for whom all these moral decisions are actual life-changing events. Simply seeing the game from that perspective is enough to make everything carry that much more weight, and it doesn&amp;#x2019;t hurt that they&amp;#x2019;re fun reads too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What separates The Witcher from most in-game codexes is its sense of character, with everything being described from the perspective of in-game poet, lover and occasional sidekick Dandelion. The nature of the game also rewarded taking the time to dip into the Codex, given that for a travelling monster-slayer, knowledge is power, and never took away from the fact that while us as players might not know our drowners from our necrophages, Geralt himself was always able to be a reliable source of information and provide the condensed version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Realms of the Haunting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#x2019;s a retro classic, sadly not helped by the low-resolutions of the mid-90s. Nothing damages the mood of an otherwise well-made document like peering at it through a letter-box and finding it more poorly compressed than an old JPEG from a lost Geocities page. It&amp;#x2019;s not quite as bad blown up to full screen though, and even with its technical problems, it demonstrated how to write documents that actually fit the world and contributed to the lore without feeling like extracts from the design bible. Most took the form of letters between the characters, their identities not always immediately obvious, and turning the relatively simple battle between good and evil at the heart of the story into an epic tale of Faustian deals, ancient cults, doomed love, and a deep mythology stretching between multiple worlds. The visual look certainly didn&amp;#x2019;t hurt, with everything presented as aged pages, hand-drawn maps and messily scrawled journals. And if you didn&amp;#x2019;t like them, you got to burn several of them as part of a puzzle. Splendid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Neverhood&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you really, really want to make sure nobody misses your game&amp;#x2019;s lore, there&amp;#x2019;s always the Hall of Records&amp;#x2014;aka The Place Where Basically All The Game&amp;#x2019;s Backstory Is, as carved onto the walls of a corridor that takes about five minutes to trudge through even if you ignore all of the words. Oh, and when you get to the other end? You have to walk back, obviously. You know it&amp;#x2019;s good stuff when even a game&amp;#x2019;s own wiki states, and we quote, &amp;#x201C;it is suggested by most not to read all of it.&amp;#x201D; Truly great literature. Who could ask for anything less?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But of course, these are just a few cases. Which games have convinced you to pause saving the world to flick through a good book, and when has that background just been so much blah? It&amp;#x2019;s fun to get lost in backstory, just as long as the writers aren&amp;#x2019;t too obsessed with their own lore.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2383968106583431139</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 09:31:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Telltale teases The Walking Dead's final season with a nostalgic Clementine callback</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2383968106574421318</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for The Walking Dead&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telltale said last year that the final season of its Walking Dead adventure series would be &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/the-wolf-among-us-season-2-and-telltales-walking-dead-finale-are-coming-next-year/"&gt;out in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, and so it will be: The studio tweeted the first tease of the last season earlier today with an image that very deliberately hearkens back to the game&amp;apos;s first season.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;apos;s a haunting callback, with a grown-up Clementine filling the shoes of man-with-an-axe Lee Everett, who bravely fought to keep her alive through the first season. Season four will also see the &lt;a href="https://telltale.com/news/2017/11/prepare-for-the-end-with-the-walking-dead-collection-available-december-5th-/?_ga=2.84926745.1426935565.1522438072-1134174869.1522438072"&gt;return of Gary Whitta&lt;/a&gt;, the former PC Gamer EIC who for some reason left all this fame and fortune behind to go do &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/former-pc-gamer-editor-and-walking-dead-writer-is-writing-a-star-wars-film/"&gt;something else&lt;/a&gt;. He wrote the fourth episode of season one, and will serve as a story consultant for the final season.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telltale said that the first proper look at the final season will be reveal at 12:30 pm ET on April 6 at its PAX East panel, which will also be viewable &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/telltalegames"&gt;on Twitch&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2383968106574421318</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 21:27:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Where The Water Tastes Like Wine was a 'commercial disaster,' dev says in painful post</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2383968106574118560</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Gone Home&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Where The Water Tastes Like Wine&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story adventure game &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/where-the-water-tastes-like-wine-review/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where The Water Tastes Like Wine&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; struggled critically and flopped commercially, lead developer Johnnemann Nordhagen said today in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@johnnemann/where-the-water-tastes-like-wine-postmortem-211a1f9d791a" target="_blank"&gt;a post-mortem of the game&lt;/a&gt;, in which he argues that its difficulties don&amp;apos;t bode well for experimental indie games.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Commercially, it&amp;#x2019;s a disaster,&amp;quot; Nordhagen said. &amp;quot;I can&amp;#x2019;t discuss exact numbers, but in the first few weeks fewer people bought the game than I have Twitter followers, and I don&amp;#x2019;t have a lot of Twitter followers.&amp;quot; (At the time of writing, Nordhagen has 4,272 followers.)&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although Nordhagen received support from publisher Good Shepherd to complete and market the game, Where The Water Tastes Like Wine has yet to break even. &amp;quot;So far, I have made $0 from the game,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot;That may look like a high number, but consider that it took four years to make&amp;#x200A;&amp;#x2014;&amp;#x200A;that works out to approximately $0/year &amp;#x2026; And then once you factor in the ~$140,000 I spent paying my contractors and collaborators for the game, you begin to see that maybe it wasn&amp;#x2019;t, financially speaking, worth it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where The Water Tastes Like Wine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Joking aside&amp;#x200A;&amp;#x2014;&amp;#x200A;that&amp;#x2019;s dismal. And terrifying,&amp;quot; Nordhagen said. &amp;quot;At the end of the day it&amp;#x2019;s astounding that a game that got this much attention from the press, that won awards, that had an all-star cast of writers and performers, that had a bizarre celebrity guest appearance(!) failed this hard. It scares me.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I   m not sure that games like this one can continue to be made in the current market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Johnnemann Nordhagen&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Nordhagen, it&amp;apos;s evidence of a growing trend for indie games: quality, acclaim, and attention aren&amp;apos;t guarantees of success. &amp;quot;That last part should be worrying for anyone in the indie games industry,&amp;quot; Nordhagen said. &amp;quot;[Where The Water Tastes Like Wine] could have been a non-commercial game, but it would have had to be very different. It would be far less polished, it wouldn&amp;#x2019;t have had the collaborators that it did, I could not have paid people who couldn&amp;#x2019;t afford to work for revenue share or for the love of the game (thus, I fear, cutting out some of the most valuable voices that this game was a platform for). I could have developed it as a side project, but it took me four years as is. Basically, I&amp;#x2019;m not sure that games like this one can continue to be made in the current market.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nordhagen also discussed the development factors he believes contributed to Where The Water Tastes Like Wine&amp;apos;s uphill battle. For example, it received relatively little playtesting, especially close to launch, and it abruptly lost both of its main artists mid-development. &amp;quot;I didn&amp;#x2019;t originally have the knowledge I needed to tackle many of the issues I encountered during development,&amp;quot; he said, adding that the game itself &amp;quot;was too much to take on as a solo dev, and especially too much to take on as a commercial product.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gone Home&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nordhagen previously worked as lead programmer on Gone Home, which was well-received when it released in 2014. Encouraged by Gone Home&amp;apos;s success, Nordhagen was optimistic about Where The Water Tastes Like Wine. However, in 2018, he&amp;apos;s unsure if creating games like these is even feasible. &amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;In 2014, starting a similar project seemed like a good creative and financial risk,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot;Four years later, making any commercial game at all seems like a bad idea, and taking on the risk of an experimental, ambitious game like Where the Water Tastes Like Wine sounds terrifying.&amp;quot; &amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;2013 I think was a very different time for smaller indie games&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Steve Gaynor&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writer and designer Steve Gaynor, who also worked on Gone Home, made a similar point about experimental games &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/fullbrights-steve-gaynor-on-tacoma-and-the-changing-state-of-indie/" target="_blank"&gt;when we spoke to him&lt;/a&gt; following the release of Fullbright&amp;apos;s Tacoma, a delightful narrative-driven game whose sales paled in comparison to Gone Home&amp;apos;s at launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I think there were a lot of things about Gone Home&amp;#x2019;s launch that were kind of &amp;apos;lightning in a bottle,&amp;apos;&amp;quot; Gaynor said. &amp;quot;2013 I think was a very different time for smaller indie games coming out that were kind of reaching into the triple-A fidelity space. Also I think that we were lucky to be responding to what I think was a real desire for more games that were less violent or more focused on story or whatever. And so yeah, Tacoma&amp;#x2019;s release I think has been a much more realistic version of what launching a game is usually like.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tacoma&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nordhagen&amp;apos;s post-mortem focuses on the game&amp;apos;s development and reception, but he&amp;apos;s not the only member of the team to look back on Where The Water Tastes Like Wine. Lead editor &lt;a href="https://blog.lauramichet.com/2018/03/04/where-the-water-tastes-like-wine-postmortem/" target="_blank"&gt;Laura Michet wrote a lengthy analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the herculean task of coordinating the game&amp;apos;s many writers, and several writers, like Emily Short, have explored &lt;a href="https://emshort.blog/2018/03/27/where-the-water-tastes-like-wine-2/" target="_blank"&gt;how they wrote their individual characters&lt;/a&gt;. You can find more analyses in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@johnnemann/where-the-water-tastes-like-wine-postmortem-211a1f9d791a" target="_blank"&gt;Nordhagen&amp;apos;s post.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2383968106574118560</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 19:35:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Friday Facts #236 - Building a rollup</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2383968106573226825</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
As you are probably already aware, some of our team members are going to attend PAX East in Boston next week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We figured we need some representative prints for our booth, but what to put there? We could have just made a big mega high resolution render of the player character or some other entity, but that would not tell the viewer much about what the game is about. So we thought it would be much better to &amp;quot;just&amp;quot; take a giant screenshot of a working factory, print it, and done! Now of course it’s much more complicated than that…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first obvious hurdle is that you need a savegame to take this screenshot of. So you go and try to take a bunch of random saves on your disk, you open them and find that it’s not so easy to just find a factory which would look nice. Such a factory needs to show enough of the various things to represent the game, can fit the logo somewhere, and must be large enough to fill about 275x185 tiles (3x2 meters at 150dpi taken at game zoom 2)&amp;#8230; one square in the following picture is a chunk (32x32 tiles)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/911f9b99eb45adb9547461290f7a78dd502b452b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Luckily I just had a savegame which was easy to adapt to those requirements, but I would like to ask the question, how does one build such a factory in general? That’s what I have been trying to figure out for a long time now. As some of you may have already noticed, I enjoy constructing very organic factories, a part of which eventually turns into a crazy mess. A mess as crazy as Factorio itself, representing what your will brain look like after playing Factorio.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/479c38365b0bc48047e11f46fea6f4375775652e.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I find this to be a good opportunity to be a bit more specific and see a few examples to put it into more context&amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Building for big screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;It’s the year 2015 and pretty much every factory I had built so far eventually arrived to the problem that in order to expand it, I would have to severely modify or destroy large portions of it. I hate to just throw away all the work that I did on my belt knots, so the outcome would usually be that I just stop playing that map and start over.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Example 1, codename: MessFort:&lt;/h2&gt;Once I made a factory that was my largest so far. It used Bobs productivity modules level 7 with a stupid amount of productivity bonus, possible to put into any recipe, and without decreasing the speed of the machine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This alone may sound ridiculous but what it did was allow me to focus on just having fun adding more and more things to the factory, while caring about throughput much less, especially in situations where I could just add better modules to existing factories, leaving more ingredients for other things, allowing me to build even more production lines.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course sooner or later the furnace area would just not be enough and expanding it on the spot would be a pain, so I just started a new dedicated factory just for smelting like many factories do. Trains brought the necessary things and later on I added another factory for circuits and the factory kept being happy. Eventually I dropped under 40 UPS and didn’t want to continue any more. It’s worth mentioning that there was no space science or infinite research back then, so there was little incentive to continue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Discoveries&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mixed belts (different item on each belt half) are a huge amount of fun to work with, and add more visual variety.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Automating as many different recipes as feasible is one step towards a nice looking base.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/8e98b13728ff2e70c807a53a42cb23ee7762e874.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Example 2, codename: SpaceScienceBase&lt;/h2&gt;In the second half of 2016, I started a new factory. Learning from the past discoveries, I wanted to embrace the concept of replacing production lines for intermediates with train stations which would import these items.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Producing those intermediates however required a large rail system outside of the main belt cluster. This gave the factory a lot more expandability and I had spent more time on this map (160 hrs) than any before by a large margin. Like all nice things, the amount of effort directly influences how nice is the result going to be, as with the outer train network expanding, the main base also continued to grow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Discoveries&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having rails inside of the factory adds a lot of depth by breaking the monotonous assembling machine + belt mess.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pipes and oil-related entities are awesome to have in the base so that not everything is an assembling machine.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/c1cee79d6ac496ddab0a946a7d3e6d0e216213f5.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Examples 3 and 4, Codenames: TrainMaze and MOAR&lt;/h2&gt;In the following several months I would try to start a few new maps with different factories and different concepts, but each time something just wasn’t going in the right direction and eventually I would recognize that it’s not &amp;quot;The One&amp;quot; and lose interest in it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/fd1064386fc155ec6cf188043fee80dd3dea01f3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I was starting to feel like it was only a matter of luck, and I only made the SpaceScienceBase look awesome by accident as I couldn’t deliberately achieve the same again. I kept thinking about what it is that makes it stand out, what are the differences from the other two, for example:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disabling biters or minimizing military removes many recipes to automate, and easily leads to a less interesting factory.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Too many straight and rectangular patterns just look visually uninteresting.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Preparing all setups for beacon rows from the beginning forces a lot of straight predictable lines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Horizontal production rows of machines generally look better than vertical columns, but having some vertical columns is good for variety.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/cf5a59f8f4fbd869c70bb616afcfcad8d945bc71.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I believe a part of the problem was how I focused on efficiency by preparing for whole rows of beacons for everything (especially the vertical ones), or how I separated the oil and rail related entities from the core of the main factory. Everything just ended up being straight and boring.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Example 5: GridLock&lt;/h2&gt;So eventually I started a new map with all of those things in mind. I made a rough plan for myself what I would like it to end up, and then tried to follow it. The rail system would be extremely expandable but use both single and dual headed trains for variety, the main factory would automate literally every single recipe in the game, and I would try to keep things as organic as possible. I could have tried harder to put more pipe and nuclear related entities in the middle of the factory&amp;#8230; perhaps next time I guess.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here you can see it grow:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://youtu.be/UJPFUQhnXS8"&gt;https://youtu.be/UJPFUQhnXS8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When I was building, I saved over 300 iterative versions of the map. The timelapse is then created by taking a screenshot in each of those saves, and in post-production they are blended together so that it looks smoother.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I found out that we need a screenshot of these dimensions just shortly before the logo appears on the map. You can see not much had to change, except all the terrain under the whole screenshot area was manually reworked in the map editor. This gave me a bunch of ideas of what we need to do to make the map editor better - both for our use with scenarios and campaign, and for our players.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you are interested in reading more about how the base works or downloading the savegame, you can proceed to the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://imgur.com/a/FmoBY"&gt;imgur album&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/6a85790698543f8ec117de70d6fea3d99367f9ce.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The final result is a trio of rollups totalling 3 meters in width and 2 meters in height. This whole thing has been quite an experience for me. Building a factory and doing my own fiddling is great, but building a factory, sitting down with Albert (our art director), thinking how to improve the general visual composition of it, making it fit the requirements etc. was just outright amazing. Just the part where I needed to put the logo and remove a bunch of train stations, cut many belts and reconnect them, was a very cool challenge. If I started again I would have probably done a few things differently, but something would probably be wrong if I didn’t feel like that. Overall I must say I am quite satisfied with the result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/12002589/b94606f3b23b56891fe37e87e5bcb88ea2b90af1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Imagine a friend of yours is trying to introduce you to this game, shows this screenshot to you and says: &amp;quot;Hey, this is the game I have been repeatedly telling you about lately&amp;#8230;&amp;quot; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://forums.factorio.com/59207"&gt;What would be your response?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Klonan</author><guid>2383968106573226825</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 13:50:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guacamelee! 2 Coming to Steam  Drinkbox 10th Anniversary Sale</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2383968106573195903</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Guacamelee! Gold Edition&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We&amp;#39;re excited to announce that Guacamelee! 2 will be coming to Steam!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you&amp;#39;re thinking of picking up the game, we&amp;#39;d love it if you could add us to your Steam Wishlist. Every person helps!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/534550/Guacamelee_2/"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/app/534550/Guacamelee_2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In celebration of this, as well as Drinkbox Studios upcoming 10th anniversary, we&amp;#39;ve decided to put all of our games on sale for 90% off! Check out the discounts here: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/search/?developer=DrinkBox%20Studios"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/search/?developer=DrinkBox%20Studios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;3 Drinkbox Studios</description><author>grahams</author><guid>2383968106573195903</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 13:38:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Price change</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2383968106573187651</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Factorio&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Dear all,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Version 0.16 has become stable, and this means that there is one last step for us to reach the 0.17 which will probably become 1.0 version. Then Factorio will finally step out of the Early Access zone. This will take some months but the roadmap is clear for us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We feel that now is a good time to adjust the price of the game. The price of the game has been growing steadily together with the game becoming bigger, more stable and polished. After careful consideration, we have decided to set the new price of the game to 30 USD (or your regional equivalent). This change will become effective as of 16th of April 2018. This is the final Factorio price update, unless something unforeseen happens, so it will also be the price for the game for 1.0 release.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As you probably know we have a strict no sale policy. The game will not go on sale on Steam or any other platform. This basically means that purchasing before the 16th of April 2018 is the only way to buy the game cheaper than the increased release price.&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Klonan</author><guid>2383968106573187651</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 13:35:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - March 30, 2018</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2383968106572359536</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/27357479/4a07e59ea6312d895de9e1652fcfa74cfa2a1d5f.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This update addresses issues with HiDPI displays and display scaling, bots and adds a new cvar for use in add-ons. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix marine bots collision group. Fixes issue where marines were teleporting through elevators, and falling to the ground below the ship at the start of rd-til8comcenter.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add rd_queen_hud_suppress_time Cvar. It is used to suppress the Swarm Queen&amp;#39;s health HUD if not damaged for this long seconds (-1 to always show).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix title of Bonus Mission 5.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix bots don&amp;#39;t get into train in tft3Spaceport map&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve nodegraph in tft3Spaceport&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update reactivedrop.exe with HiDPI aware flag. This should resolve numerous issues with HiDPI displays or when Windows text and apps scaling is set to be above 100%. Previously users have had game window opened in a size(resolution) that is bigger than user&amp;#39;s monitor resolution and thus were unable to change the resolution and any options(because most of UI was off screen).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;We&amp;#39;re also looking for a person capable of drawing new promotion icons which fit the original Alien Swarm style. If you feel you&amp;#39;re up for the task please create a new discussion in our &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://steamcommunity.com/app/563560/discussions/2/"&gt;feedback subforum&lt;/a&gt; where we can discuss the details. Feel free to submit your designs and ideas for the new promotion icons.</description><author>Rayman1103</author><guid>2383968106572359536</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 08:05:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Superb stealth game Mark of the Ninja is getting remastered </title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2383968106570677430</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Mark of the Ninja&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sZ7ogfkR3hQ"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark of the Ninja: Remastered will freshen up &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/mark-of-the-ninja-review/" target="_blank"&gt;one of our all-time favorite stealth games&lt;/a&gt; later this year, developer Klei Entertainment announced.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A standout even among Klei Entertainment&amp;apos;s sterling repertoire, Mark of the Ninja originally released in 2012, and while its cartoony art has aged well, Klei reckons it could do with a tune-up. So for the remaster, they&amp;apos;re targeting &amp;quot;fully redone 4K visuals for both gameplay and cutscenes along with enhanced audio and new particle effects.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The remaster will also come with the content from Mark of the Ninja&amp;apos;s Special Edition DLC. That includes a new level, two new items, a suite of non-lethal takedowns, and a heaping helping of developer commentary.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Klei hasn&amp;apos;t shared much else on the remaster, but in a follow-up &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/klei/status/978701598259011584" target="_blank"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;, the studio did note they&amp;apos;re &amp;quot;working out reward paths for existing players depending on if they own the regular games vs also owning the special edition.&amp;quot; So it&amp;apos;s possible existing Mark of the Ninja owners will receive some sort of discount or in-game compensation.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks, &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/28/mark-of-the-ninja-remastered-pc-confirmed/" target="_blank"&gt;RockPaperShotgun&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2383968106570677430</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 20:53:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tinker Time beta updated!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365953485471855062</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Awesomenauts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/d9fd955a7a5293eaf0a400777230c05ff0e821a8.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hey everyone, we just released an update for the Awesomenauts 4.6: Tinker Time beta! Catch the full patch notes for this Beta compared to the current live version below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some of the important changes in this Beta compared to the previous Beta is that Commander Rocket no longer resets the charges on his Salvo when using Rocket Launch, some additional tweaks to Derpl and Sentry, and further changes to Professor M. Yoolip!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please share your feedback &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.awesomenauts.com/forum/viewforum.php?f=19"&gt;on our forums&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/cf19c3b5917941055204147d2b4745161cdff74c.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commander Rocket&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Currently too safe and very hard to catch, Rocket needs to be easier to punish&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rocket Launch, no longer knocks back enemies.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Base Health, reduced from 1150 to 1100&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laser Trap is too unreliable, doing either too much damage or none at all. These changes should make its effect more reliable while also making placement a little bit more skillful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, time between damage ticks increased from 0.2 to 0.3.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, damage per tick increased from 60 to 90.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, rotation speed increased by 50%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, laser length reduced by 10%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, no longer has deployment time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laser Trap, duration reduced from 4 to 3 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some upgrade adjustments based on the above changes. These are intended to keep Rocket brawling closer to his Laser Trap.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Profanity filters, now increases trap duration by 2 seconds for 160 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Borgo Cigar cutter, CMDR Rocket gets a shield which reduces 30% of the incoming damage as long as he is nearby a deployed laser trap.
&lt;em&gt;This upgrade is still too strong and mandatory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Box of Cirean cigars, damage per particle per stage reduced from 20 to 16.
&lt;em&gt;His Rocket Launch no longer deals damage to turrets, but his turret push is still too intense. Adjusting the numbers and making them more consistent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charged Salvo, damage modifier against droids increased from 75% to 80%&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charged Salvo, damage modifier against turrets reduced from 100% to 80%.
&lt;em&gt;This upgrade was a holdover from a time where Rocket’s Laser Trap had a lot more uptime. The intention for this replacement is to enable Rocket to be a bit better at brawling and allowing him to stay a bit closer to the fight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Head in Jar, now adds 16% damage to Charged Salvo when firing a single rocket, two stages for 175 solar each.
&lt;em&gt;Part of his safety comes from his relatively high ranged base attack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charged Salvo, range reduced by 20%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medal Booster Pack, range increase reduced from 25% to 20%.
&lt;em&gt;Combining Rocket Launch and a full Charged Salvo at melee range provides too much damage, too easily. At the same time we want to stimulate him to get more into the thick of the fight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rocket Launch, now deals between 150 and 350 damage, depending on how long the rocket has been flying.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mother of Bombs, after using Rocket Launch without hitting an enemy, your next Charged Salvo shot will deal 100 more damage for 170 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/823d399cc943558129d3bb1f405c248306662d21.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Derpl&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Considered too strong specifically on Ribbit and Starstorm, these tweaks attempt to adjust him without affecting his general performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Siege mode, Derpl is no longer immune to CC during the transformation out of siege mode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Combustion lava lamp, size increase reduced from 22% to 18%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Falling acceleration reduced by 20%.
&lt;em&gt;Traps can be very oppressive, maxing out at full 2.4 seconds of no gameplay for the receiving party. Their long lifetime also stimulates camping gameplay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trap, snare duration reduced from 1.6 to 1.2 seconds&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trap, now also slows for 25% for 2.4 seconds. (extenting 1.2 seconds beyond the snare)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trap, base lifetime reduced from 11 to 9 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Empowered Grid, snare increase per stage reduced from 0.4 to 0.3 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lead casing, the silence now has a fixed duration of 2.4 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trap, now charges in the middle of Derpl instead of having an arming time when placed.
&lt;em&gt;Some base attack adjustments to better balance the row and take the above changes into account.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fat Cat, cooldown increased from 4 to 5 seconds, price increased from 185 to 195.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kitty Catsuit, price decreased from 175 to 150 solar per stage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;CAT package, price decreased from 175 to 150 solar per stage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bat Catsuit, now deals 100% increased damage against Nauts who are snared or slowed, no longer works with Fat Cat.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Long Cat, now works with Fat Cat.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/306d6f4cd9cfb2e4744d49e424863f0562d72426.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dizzy&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dizzy is currently a bit too strong. But she&amp;#39;s also very finicky, and has a lot of weak upgrades.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Multi Dash, time between dashes increased from 0.3 to 0.4 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Multi Dash, damage per dash increased from 150 to 160.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Walkbot Pro, speed up dash reload time by 30% when you are near to enemies.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Explosive Clone, cooldown increased from 6 to 7 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Backstage pass, increase the range of your Multi Dash by 25% when you have the maximum amount of dashes charged.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Matching Glittery Dungarees, now reduces the cooldown for the next Explosive Clone by 3 seconds when it hits an enemy Awesomenaut.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Purple Prince&amp;quot; lipstick, now also slows enemies when they leave the bubble as well as when they are hit by the explosion.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bubble shot, size increased by 50%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Graffiti artist, price increased from 165 to 190.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tipi teal, merged to one stage of 30% range and speed increase for 140 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/89e6d6a97346b9e10bb82ea3b76823a8a1089bdc.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ix&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ix generally still brings too much to the table overall, great displace move, solid heals, invincibility frames, excellent mobility and strong brawling. In order to nudge him more towards his role his brawling should be reduced.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Refract, cooldown increased from 9 to 10.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Radiate, damage per Scatter reduced from 15 to 12.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mammoth hair scarf, ally speed bonus increased from 12% to 15% per stage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tree hugger, ally damage boost increased from 12% to 15% per stage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Personality Crystal, range increase reduced from 35% to 30%.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/92056c0875f58423dbc8774bae1acad1ef54924d.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Lonestar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ribbit snail slime, fixed that the healthpack would time out if it fell for too long.
&lt;em&gt;Since these aren’t that much better than regular boots, they also don’t have to cost much more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rocket boots, solar price reduced from 160 to 140.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Base speed, increased by 4%.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/32af7797f04668c4503d32c67c12e724841d75e0.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Max Focus&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This item has its use, but it&amp;#39;s too weak and expensive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;From pond to podium, merged into one stage which adds 30% range and speed for 200 solar.
&lt;em&gt;The homing upgrade looks cool, but doesn&amp;#39;t do much. Here is a replacement proposal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;UFO spotted, now gives +50% speed during Scene Illumination for 160 solar.
&lt;em&gt;This upgrade is just a bit too expensive, especially given the next change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sadak mysteries, price reduced from 195 to 175 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Removing the stacking will reduce the need to combo with Sadak.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Brutalities of the Kraken, damage increased from 120 to 135 per stage, no longer stacks with Sadak mysteries.
&lt;em&gt;This item is just a bit too expensive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rob Bourgogne, price reduced from 180 to 160 per stage.
&lt;em&gt;This item was overnerfed shortly after launch, because the skill was too strong to begin with at the time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hairy King, size increase increased from 10% to 15%, price increased from 175 to 200 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Some overpriced items.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don Steward, price per stage reduced from 175 to 140 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pete Jennirks, price reduced from 240 to 200 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Incriminating dirt, price reduced from 180 to 150 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Flying camera, price reduced from 210 to 150 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Meanwhile, this one&amp;#39;s underpriced.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hidden microphone, price increased from 170 to 200 solar.
&lt;em&gt;This item is the strongest on the row, it doesn&amp;#39;t need to stack further.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Galactic police scanner, no longer stacks with incriminating dirt, price increased from 180 to 220 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/ed41d63c6b924f52411cec848bbdf99405c2cae4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nibbs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Firebreath, fixed that after being Cocooned by Genji during Firebreath she wouldn&amp;#39;t resume after the Cocoon wears off.
&lt;em&gt;Some price adjustments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Skull dunduns, price reduced from 200 to 180.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eye of Coba, price reduced from from 215 to 190.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dragon Speaker Idol, now has two stages of +10% attack speed each, at 150 solar per stage.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/6531b00b86ae6b0bdbc084cc9daad93c01a40cfd.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Professor Milton Yoolip&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Some adjustments to improve the item balance for the gaze row.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Beard Trimming Fork, price reduced from 165 to 130 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Syrup Pouring Robot, maximum lifesteal increased from 120 to 150 per stage.
&lt;em&gt;Some changes to make Dinos more reliable at base.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Summon Robo Dinos, now jump at enemies at base.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Summon Robo Dinos, damage per bite reduced from 80 to 75.
&lt;em&gt;Now this upgrade has become useless.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Holo Pet Food, now reduces the damage dealt by Nauts who have been bitten by 15% for 1.5 seconds.

&lt;strong&gt;Qi’Tara&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Made Qi&amp;#39;Taras seven star strike visual only in front of Qi&amp;#39;Tara to represent the area where damage was being applied better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that she couldn’t use Chakram Shift to teleport while using Seven Star Strike when the Salty Seal upgrade was bought.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Made Qi&amp;#39;Taras seven star strike visual only in front of Qi&amp;#39;Tara to represent the area where damage was being applied better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that the Lily of the Isle projectiles would spawn at her feet during Seven Star Strike.
&lt;em&gt;Qi’Tara deals too much damage during Seven Star Strike, and too little outside of it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seven star strike, attack speed increase reduced from 40% to 30%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poisonous blade, direct damage increased from 45 to 50.
&lt;em&gt;Her relationship with speed feels disjointed, where attacking slows her down but Seven Star Strike speed her up etc. These changes also tie in with the issue above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poisonous Blade, removed movement penalty when attacking.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seven Star Strike, removed speed bonus during the ability.
&lt;em&gt;With the changes above, this upgrade has now become useless. This change will make Qi’Tara’s damage output more reliable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chilasi Chakram, now speeds up the damage over time of Poisonous blade by 20% for 160 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Since the bug was fixed where this upgrade doubled your damage, this upgrade has become too weak&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lily of the Isle, projectile speed and range increased by 30%.
&lt;em&gt;Salty Seal makes Qi’Tara almost unstoppable, this change should make counterplay possible again&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Salty Seal, now cleanses all slows, snares and chains at the start of Seven Star Strike.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Salty Seal, now activates a shield that blocks 100 damage and provides immunity against slows, stuns, snares, chains, gravity and time warps as long as it’s active.
&lt;em&gt;Other tweaks and adjustments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seven star strike, now also gives a 10% lifesteal effect.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Baby plumbin oil, additional lifesteal reduced from 30% to 15% for 175 solar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rakki Comb, merged to one stage which adds 200% damage vs. droids for 155 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/c3e6b9ea5315191e6b97f4d8f5951b5c8162cf62.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Raelynn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Iron Rifle, fixed that the shield didn’t last long enough to protect the entire charge duration.
&lt;em&gt;This weak upgrade has some heavy competition on the row.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Monkey hand, range increase increased from 25% to 40%.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/7a582ca443e88ea8625584a74d664a6f6567dd19.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Rocco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Birdseed donuts, cooldown reduction when hit increased from 2 to 4 seconds, duration increase increased from 1 to 2 seconds.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/01394ae6ab660d8f2b8eecb87756a5579245d737.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Scoop&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;His base attack is a bit too weak in general&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sword Strike, Slash damage increased from 100 to 105, Cleave lifesteal increased from 20% to 30%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Banner of the Triple Scoop, price per stage reduced from 130 to 100.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Halberd of Justice, bonus damage reduced from 25% to 22%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Titanium Coneshield, price increased from 130 to 150 solar per stage.
&lt;em&gt;Other tweaks and adjustments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Brutally Whipped Cream, price reduced from 200 to 180 per stage.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/713fb830953afd54abcf5557ac9a64e88e95c9a4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sentry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that Sentry’s Beacon no longer emitted a phone interference sound.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed that Starstorm statue didn&amp;#39;t affect Bug detector.
&lt;em&gt;Reducing his efficiency of laying down mines in choke-points which has little to no counter-play.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mines, damage while stationary reduced from 80 to 70.
&lt;em&gt;With this change in mind, a counter-buff to help him land reliable damage output in close ranged scenarios.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mines, damage on direct hit increased from 80 to 90.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Projectile speed of mines increased by 15%.
&lt;em&gt;Camouflage tent is currently emphasizing passive play. This change will reward aggressive use of his AA by increasing his chase potency and reliability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Camouflage tent, now increases projectile speed and range by 15%, one stage for 175 solar.
&lt;em&gt;Drive-over skulls is also providing a lot of easy chip damage and can be replaced with a more active timing based auto-attack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drive-over skulls, now deals +75% direct damage when not firing for 1.5s.
&lt;em&gt;Currently Black Hole Sun feels inconsistent and very hard to avoid, and if avoided it lingers for a whole 1.5s. This is an attempt at making BHS a more reliable ability and feel more fair on both ends. Starting with rewarding precision and aim on Sentry&amp;#39;s end while allowing enemies to dodge the skill easier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, projectile distance increased by 10%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, projectile speed increased by 10%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, size of black hole reduced by 15%.
&lt;em&gt;The next set of changes are both aimed at compensating for the size reduction but also to reduce the duration of BHS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, minimum gravity increased by 8%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, maximum gravity increased by 5%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, duration of black hole reduced from 1.5s to 1.2s.
&lt;em&gt;With these changes aside, his shield charging up also adds up a lot of time where he&amp;#39;s difficult to punish. Reducing his shield duration both allows him for using his black hole quicker, while also being vulnerable faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shield duration reduced from 2s to 1.5s.
&lt;em&gt;With less up-time of his shields, his base shield scaling could be increased to fulfill his tanky role. This allows him to tank a little extra in fights and reward aggressive play.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Black Hole Sun, Base shield increased from 20% to 25%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Microfilm, shielding reduced from 10% to 8%, price reduced to 140 solar per stage.
&lt;em&gt;Some Sentry&amp;#39;s just leave their beacon sitting somewhere in order to reveal or permanently put pressure on an area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Teleport Beacon, times out after 45 seconds.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/533ccae8a301b7a6bcef4fbf5a4f4d898dd7768d.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Skree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Made separate spawnpoints for Sawblade and Spare blade, and moved them apart a little.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sawblade, now deals direct damage instead of damage over time.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/033fc68a9b5c59a6506c8ae4255a147a60ccc750.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Smiles&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Smiles has been overnerfed in the last few updates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Base health, increased from 1550 to 1650.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trapper’s hook, cooldown reduced from 10 to 8 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bush fire, range increased by 25%.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/36aa2148c877b5ffaaec29de1e2eb29778af0b34.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Swiggins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Poolboy, price reduced from 240 to 210 solar.

&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3948077/04d99daf1b3c440ab3cc1dcc537d922ea50d6a19.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Yuri&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Uranium spikes, price increased from 125 to 150 per stage.&lt;/li&gt;</description><author>Mitaki</author><guid>2365953485471855062</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 15:37:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Get nostalgic and play with the classic gloves in Q.U.B.E. 2!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365953485471675897</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/31518971/9ac4712dd1e3e09d9ac2d061186bea071ef40988.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Get nostalgic and play with the classic Q.U.B.E. gloves equipped in Q.U.B.E. 2! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re pleased to announce that the classic Q.U.B.E. glove skin will be available today at 5PM GMT with the Season Pass. Fans of the first game will recognise the iconic gloves and be able to play with them in Q.U.B.E. 2 - you’ll also be able to switch between the old and new style during gameplay. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The classic glove skin is currently only for PC at this time and will be available in the Season Pass on Steam. Grab the season pass here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/822094/QUBE_2_Season_Pass/"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/app/822094/QUBE_2_Season_Pass/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks!</description><author>Toxic Games</author><guid>2365953485471675897</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:26:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mark Of The Ninja: Remastered sneaking onto PC too</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2365953485471612937</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Mark of the Ninja&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/03/mark-of-the-ninja-remastered.jpg" title="Go ninja! Go ninja! Go!" width="620" height="300" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-530523" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swell side-scrolling stealth game &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/mark-of-the-ninja/"&gt;Mark Of The Ninja&lt;/a&gt; is being snazzed up for the release of a &amp;#8216;Remastered&amp;#8217; edition. The game is largely hidden in the shadows for now, but developers Klei Entertainment say it &amp;#8220;will feature fully redone 4K visuals for both gameplay and cutscenes along with enhanced audio and new particle effects&amp;#8221;. Having announced Mark Of The Ninja: Remastered for Nintendo Switch last week, Klei last night confirmed that yup, it is coming to PC too. Here, see this cinematic trailer. &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/28/mark-of-the-ninja-remastered-pc-confirmed/#more-530483" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Alice O'Connor)</author><guid>2365953485471612937</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 13:31:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Vermintide: taking the torch of Left 4 Dead from its cold, undead hands</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2365953485468687575</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Left 4 Dead, Left 4 Dead 2&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-530315" src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/03/vermintideleft4dead1-620x311.png" alt="vermintideleft4dead1" width="620" height="311" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I   d wager most folk around these parts devoured &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/left-4-dead/"&gt;Left 4 Dead&lt;/a&gt; back in the day, just as I did. Valve   s    28 Days Later with your friends    infected my life for a good year, and a bigger, better sequel one year later only strengthened the disease. But as Valve haven   t really been in the business of making games for a good few years &amp;#8211; &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2018-03-10-hooray-valve-is-going-to-start-shipping-games-again"&gt;hopefully, that   s about to change&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; and while it felt like Left 4 Dead was going to change the world back in (oh no) 2008, for a long time nothing filled the rotten hole where my heart used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, until Fatshark   s rowdy rat-smash, &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/warhammer-vermintide-2/"&gt;Vermintide&lt;/a&gt;. The four vs the world setup and the UI were highly reminiscent of Left 4 Dead, and what are Gutter Runners and Pack Masters if not reskinned Hunters and Smokers? But there was much more to that game than swapping out zombies for skaven. With both series  now/still on their second games, let   s look at how Vermintide ran with the legacy of Left 4 Dead, while managing to forge its own identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/27/vermintide-taking-the-torch-of-left-4-dead-from-its-cold-undead-hands/#more-530295" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Natalie Clayton)</author><guid>2365953485468687575</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 18:00:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How QUBE and QUBE 2 went from student project to whip-smart indie puzzle games</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2365953485466362604</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, three games design students at Newport University were thrown together and given six weeks to create their final project. But none of them knew how to code. &amp;quot;We learnt everything from scratch,&amp;quot; says Dan Da Rocha, one of the trio. &amp;quot;It was always going to be a student project&amp;#x2014;a portfolio piece to go and get a job at a large studio.&amp;quot; Soon it was something much bigger, and two years later the group released the game on Steam, where it would go on to reach more than 200,000 players.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What they created in those six weeks was an early version of &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/239430/QUBE_Directors_Cut/" target="_blank"&gt;Q.U.B.E.&lt;/a&gt;, a first-person puzzle game about manipulating blocks in a 3D environment. They showed it off at their graduation, and their lecturers and the assortment of gathered developers were impressed. Mike Bithell, creator of &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/220780/Thomas_Was_Alone/" target="_blank"&gt;Thomas Was Alone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/365770/Volume/" target="_blank"&gt;Volume&lt;/a&gt;, was one of the faces among the crowd. &amp;quot;He told us we should go indie, and we were like, &amp;apos;Indie, what&amp;apos;s that?&amp;apos;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They&amp;apos;d soon find out. After a couple of rounds of funding, and lots of iteration, the trio had a fully-formed game ready to go. It was smart puzzler with lots of potential, but as &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/qube-review/" target="_blank"&gt;PC Gamer&amp;apos;s review&lt;/a&gt; said at the time, it had too few ideas to be a classic. Its plain white walls felt sterile, devoid of personality&amp;#x2014;a world away from Portal, which it was inevitably compared to.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month the group&amp;#x2014;now called Toxic Games&amp;#x2014;released a sequel that improves on the original in nearly every way. It&amp;apos;s one of the most accomplished puzzlers this year, and a very pretty game too. So how did the team go from humble student project to tight, polished puzzler? I spoke to Da Rocha, now the developer&amp;#x2019;s managing director, to find out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toxic Games made the original Q.U.B.E. without an art team, and opted to &amp;quot;play to its strengths&amp;quot; with minimalist visuals that would let the puzzles shine. In Q.U.B.E. 2, they&amp;apos;ve gone all out. The game is split into district areas&amp;#x2014;one an overgrown forest where you jump over the gnarly roots of thick trees, the next built from cavernous laboratory chambers with rotating walls. It&amp;apos;s all full of color and shiny surfaces that amplify the stylish lighting.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The art team initially pictured the player being stranded in the desert, but were inspired to add more varied environments by The Crystal Maze, a cult-classic British game show in which teams travel through themed sectors completing puzzles and obstacle courses. &amp;quot;The same white, sterile environment can get a bit tiring on your eyes, a bit intense,&amp;quot; Da Rocha says. &amp;quot;So we wanted to make it much more colorful and go for some different themes: a jungle theme, a sand theme.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We brought in an art director and took a chance on a graduate environment artist, and he knocked it out of the park with the assets. Our producer and writer Ben Hill had a clear vision of what the environment would look like, so they all liaised together to create this beautiful world.&amp;quot; The key was attention to detail. Art director Harry Corr knew the game&amp;#x2019;s environment so well by the end that at one point in development he spotted a single light shaft out of place.&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Switching the magnet's polarity lets you surf that block over the airflow of a fan, which nudges your trajectory just enough for you to make it onto a high ledge and exit the level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;apos;s not just a better-looking game&amp;#x2014;it&amp;apos;s more complex, and its puzzles are more satisfying to solve. In the original you could only place a block of a certain color on a predefined surface, marked by the corresponding color. In Q.U.B.E. 2, you can place any block in any available spot, which requires a little more thought. The number of cubes goes down from five to three&amp;#x2014;Da Rocha says that was &amp;quot;cutting the fat&amp;quot;&amp;#x2014;but to make up for the change it introduces magnets, oil slicks, fans that make you float, and doors that have to be burned to open.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Individually, these mechanics are hardly ground-breaking, but Q.U.B.E. 2 does an excellent job making you feel like you&amp;apos;re mastering its toolset by gradually ramping up the complexity. &amp;quot;We wanted to keep it very simple and build complexity into the puzzles themselves. We wanted to make it easier to understand,&amp;quot; Da Rocha says. The team wanted each mechanic, introduced one-by-one as you progress, to feel like a &amp;quot;new toy to play with.&amp;quot; That means you&amp;apos;re given three or four easy puzzles when you first encounter each one, and then pushed onto trickier tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about them is how they interact, and how the game creates challenges by layering them on top of each other. When you first come across the magnets, for example, you&amp;apos;ll simply be bouncing cubes into their range, rotating them so they face a door, and then switching them to &amp;apos;repel&amp;apos;, which makes them fire the block out and smash the door down.&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soon you&amp;apos;re using them in conjunction with previously introduced mechanics. In one memorable puzzle you use the attract/repel switches to fling a block across the map and then, eventually, you end up standing on top of that block while a magnet holds it in place. Switching the magnet&amp;apos;s polarity lets you surf that block over the airflow of a fan, which nudges your trajectory just enough for you to make it onto a high ledge and exit the level. Sticking that landing made me grin for a good few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the end you&amp;apos;re playing with four or five different systems at a time. One of the final puzzles requires you to continuously rotate a wall using the magnet that&amp;apos;s sticking to it to catch a block that you&amp;apos;ve bounced from on high. Meanwhile, you&amp;apos;re coating a different block in oil so that you can skid it across the level, timing a switch for a flamethrower to set that block on fire at just the right moment so that you can then nudge it into a flammable door. It all gets pretty complex, and some of the later puzzles might require a full half hour of head-scratching before you crack them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of what makes Q.U.B.E. 2 a better game is Toxic Games&amp;apos; growth behind the scenes. The initial team of three is now eight-strong, and unfilled positions were taken up by contractors, including a producer to keep everything on schedule. That means that Da Rocha and the core team could spend more time on the game itself. &amp;quot;In Q.U.B.E. 1 it was us wearing many hats, which is probably good for us in the long-term, but in the short-term it&amp;apos;s a killer. If you&amp;#x2019;re doing the design of the game then the business development will suffer, so with this we&amp;apos;ve got key people involved in every aspect. That&amp;apos;s freed up time to work on the development and the fun stuff.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the moment, we're looking at other stuff. We've done some other prototypes, and we're taking a little mental break.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Dan Da Rocha&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team all worked remotely, but the end result is coherent. Its one weakness is the story, which is muddled, takes itself too seriously, and involves a few too many logical leaps. The basic premise is that you&amp;apos;re archaeologist Amelia Cross, and you wake up in an alien landscape with no idea how you got there. It&amp;apos;s set up to be a personal tale about her family, which you find out about through inner monologue, but then goes off-track and ends up being about the relationship between humans and a strange race of machines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;apos;re given zero reason to care about these machines other than the fact that they (mild spoiler alert) are in control of the landscape that you&amp;apos;re puzzling through. The game doesn&amp;apos;t devote enough time to dialogue to explain this properly, and as a result tries to pack too much into each encounter with another character, which just left me confused.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does provide breaks in pace, and some of the dialogue happens when you&amp;apos;re confronted with the game&amp;apos;s most dramatic vistas so you can admire the view while you listen in. It&amp;apos;s unobtrusive enough that it never stopped me from enjoying Q.U.B.E. 2&amp;apos;s puzzles, which is where the meat of the game lies, just like in the first game&amp;#x2014;which barely had a story at all until they added one in a Director&amp;apos;s Cut edition.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether the overall improved sequel hits its mark with players as well as the original remains to be seen, but regardless, it might well be the last Q.U.B.E. game the studio makes. When I ask Da Rocha whether he&amp;apos;s working on a third, he chuckles. &amp;quot;We&amp;apos;ve joked about it. At the moment, we&amp;apos;re looking at other stuff. We&amp;apos;ve done some other prototypes, and we&amp;apos;re taking a little mental break.&amp;quot; He mentions that some of the team, during development of Q.U.B.E. 2, worked on Thorn, an experimental sci-fi job simulator that came out exclusively in a Humble Bundle. &amp;quot;We want to explore that further.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact there may not be another Q.U.B.E. game makes this one feel even more special. Despite its narrative flaws, it&amp;apos;s a game that any puzzle fan should play, and the fact that nine years ago it was just an idea by three undergraduate students is testament to the power of the indie scene to reward original ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2365953485466362604</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 03:08:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Overkill's The Walking Dead dev diary explores apocalyptic Georgetown</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2365953485464558498</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for The Walking Dead&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2navr599NWM"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overkill&amp;apos;s The Walking Dead, the upcoming four-player co-op zombie FPS, has released a developer diary showcasing the neighborhood of Georgetown in Washington D.C.. You can watch it above, as producer Saul Gascon and a few lighting and environmental artists describe what went into designing the look and feel of the town in the aftermath of a zombie apocalypse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Payday studio Overkill announced The Walking Dead back in 2014, with an original plan to release it in 2016, which was then pushed to 2017. It&amp;apos;s now due out in fall of this year. You can learn more at &lt;a href="https://www.overkillsthewalkingdead.com/"&gt;the official site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2365953485464558498</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 15:00:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Five in-game cults that are a far cry from Far Cry 5</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2365952982540453965</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for BioShock&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/03/Unitology_020-620x300.jpg" alt="Unitology_020" width="620" height="300" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-529705" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cults in games have a long, proud tradition of getting to go full wackadoo. Mostly, they&amp;#8217;re a really nice device to lean on, especially in a game where you want to fill the world with collectibles and audio logs and you need some narrative to build that space. Also, they&amp;#8217;re pretty easy in that, if you don&amp;#8217;t give a flip about collectibles, you can generally parse that cults are evil and cultists deserve to die. &lt;a href="https://www.pastemagazine.com/articles/2017/05/the-knife-of-aristotle-isnt-just-a-fake-fake-news.html"&gt;I may have learned a few things about that the hard way this year&lt;/a&gt;. That said, &lt;a href="http://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/far-cry-5"&gt;Far Cry 5&lt;/a&gt; releases this week and focuses on a cult in America that uses religion and being pretty crap people in general to take over an entire state. In preparation, we look back at some of the wackier cults to be featured in games&amp;#8217; proud lineage of brainwashing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/25/five-in-game-cults-that-are-a-far-cry-from-far-cry-5/#more-529703" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Brock Wilbur)</author><guid>2365952982540453965</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 18:34:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capture Stunning HD Shots with Nvidia Ansel in Q.U.B.E. 2</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982533009108</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
For those of you with Nvidia graphics cards, Ansel is fully integrated in Q.U.B.E. 2 so you can capture stunning HD shots like this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/31518971/dfbd4754ff2950e28f5e42c3f0d02886e953fa91.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/31518971/8edfb6d067df0637d74e91d69f96ac0661d32197.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can view the full HD versions here:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://images.nvidia.com/geforce-com/international/images/geforce-experience/gdc-2018/qube-2-nvidia-ansel-003-3840x2160.jpg"&gt;https://images.nvidia.com/geforce-com/international/images/geforce-experience/gdc-2018/qube-2-nvidia-ansel-003-3840x2160.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://images.nvidia.com/geforce-com/international/images/geforce-experience/gdc-2018/qube-2-nvidia-ansel-007-3840x2160.jpg"&gt;https://images.nvidia.com/geforce-com/international/images/geforce-experience/gdc-2018/qube-2-nvidia-ansel-007-3840x2160.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks!</description><author>Toxic Games</author><guid>2365952982533009108</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 17:18:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Daily Deal - INSIDE 55% Off And LIMBO 80% Off</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/38488/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Announcement&lt;/b&gt; for LIMBO&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Today's Deal: Save 55% on &lt;a href='http://store.steampowered.com/app/304430/'&gt;INSIDE&lt;/a&gt; and 80% on &lt;a href='http://store.steampowered.com/app/48000/'&gt;Limbo&lt;/a&gt;!*&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Look for the deals each day on the front page of Steam.  Or follow us on &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/steam_games'&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href='http://www.facebook.com/Steam'&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for instant notifications wherever you are!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;*Offer ends Sunday at 10AM Pacific Time&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/304430/"&gt;&lt;img src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steam/apps/304430/capsule_467x181.jpg" style=" float: left; margin-right: 12px; height: 181px; width: 467px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/48000/"&gt;&lt;img src="https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/steam/apps/48000/capsule_467x181.jpg" style=" float: left; margin-right: 12px; height: 181px; width: 467px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description><author>Valve</author><guid>2365952982533005997</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop Update - March 23, 2018</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982531910171</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Alien Swarm: Reactive Drop&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/27357479/b6fd1ef5dadafd08cbcb218525cd0176f442cf0d.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This update brings bug fixes and a new VScript function for use in add-ons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix vindicator and devastator shotgun shell ejection. Previously only one shotgun shell was ejected after multiple shots. Now each shot ejects an empty shotgun shell.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix aliens crowding on an incapacitated marine&amp;#39;s body. When marine is incapacitated and other marines are not around aliens were piling up around the incapacitated body.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix grenade launcher&amp;#39;s grenade colliding with bot marines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make npc_cscanner not collide grenade launcher&amp;#39;s grenades and players&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix drones warping through marines in ASBI challenge&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added the following VScript function for CBaseEntity. PrecacheModel( string modelPath ) //Precache a model after the map has loaded.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix asw_buzzer SpeedScale. It&amp;#39;s now possible to change the m_fSpeedScale for the buzzer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix Take A Break being greyed out on servers which have lobby disabled&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><author>Dmitriy</author><guid>2365952982531910171</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 10:00:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hitman Episode 2: Sapienza is currently free on PC, PS4 and Xbox One</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/eurogamer/2365952982527309117</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/b&gt; for HITMAN™&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="//cdn.gamer-network.net/2018/articles/2018-03-22-03-16/hitmans-sapienza-map-and-accompanying-missions-are-currently-free-in-the-spring-pack-1521688591895.jpg/EG11/resize/300x-1/format/jpg/1962756.jpg" alt=""/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developer IO Interactive is giving away Hitman's Sapienza map, and its accompanying missions, for free on PC, PS4, and Xbox One, as part of its newly released Spring Pack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Spring Pack is essentially Episode 2 in Hitman's six-episode season (IO &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2017-12-13-hitmans-paris-episode-free-over-christmas"&gt;gave away Episode 1: Paris&lt;/a&gt; in December), and features the World of Tomorrow story mission, 20 levels of Mastery with weapon and item unlocks, over 100 challenges, plus seven achievements/trophies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also includes all Contracts, Challenge Packs, and Featured Contracts that IO has released for Sapienza, and all Sapienza-based Elusive Targets have been re-activated as part of the giveaway. Full details &lt;a href="https://www.ioi.dk/hitman-spring-pack/" target="_blank"&gt;can be found over on IO's website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2018-03-21-hitman-episode-2-sapienza-is-currently-free-on-pc-ps4-and-xbox-one"&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2365952982527309117</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 23:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The best metroidvania games on PC</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2365952982525814920</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Cave Story+&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our round-up of the best Metroidvania games. That slightly awkward portmanteau refers to a hybrid genre inspired by Metroid and Castlevania. They tend to be 2D platformers that have you exploring dungeons, defeating bosses, and picking up items that unlock new zones of the map. Within this simple format there is plenty of room for variation and, it turns out, lots of gorgeous art.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few of the games on the list have been lovingly crafted by small teams and even individuals over the course of a decade or so. Others, like Dead Cells, experiment with fusing the metroidvania with other genres to create a powerful hybrid. Whichever games you pick, expect lots of 2D platforming and some tough boss fights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ori and the Blind Forest&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/387290/Ori_and_the_Blind_Forest_Definitive_Edition/"&gt;Ori&amp;apos;s&lt;/a&gt; warmly animated world and slightly tearful opener barely hint at the incredibly tricky platforming challenges that follow. PC Gamer&amp;apos;s Philippa Warr has compared this to a teddy bear that wants to punch you in the face&amp;#x2014;it&amp;apos;s a cute and beautiful-looking game, but damn tricky. The pleasant soundtrack puts you at ease while the game rarely does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#xA0;Axiom Verge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the very best modern examples of the form, &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/332200/Axiom_Verge/"&gt;Axiom Verge&lt;/a&gt; is set in a dark, Giger-esque alien world populated by mysterious giant mechanical beings and, of course, a slew of bullet hell boss monsters. New paths open up as you discover fresh alien gadgetry, like a trenchcoat that lets you phase through walls, and a device that lets you control a small alien bug to crawl into new cave systems.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Combat is simple&amp;#x2014;blast the alien things flapping around each level&amp;#x2014;but there are loads of weapons to discover, and plenty of secrets if you&amp;#x2019;re determined enough to glitch or blast your way through secret walls. It&amp;#x2019;s a sinister and slightly unnerving game with some genuinely dark moments, but that makes it a fitting tribute to the lonely hostile corridors of the original Metroid games.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hollow Knight&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one takes a while to get going, but once you have a few upgrades it&amp;#x2019;s a spectacular hand-drawn metroidvania with a snappy melee combat system. &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/367520/Hollow_Knight/"&gt;Hollow Knight&lt;/a&gt; borrows its melancholy apocalyptic atmosphere from Dark Souls, and also its currency recovering system&amp;#x2014;if you make it back to the place you died you can reclaim your last life&amp;#x2019;s earnings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hollow Knight looks gorgeous, and it&amp;#x2019;s full of interesting bug characters that sell you new gear and give you extra quests. The bosses are challenging and the dodge-and-slash combat is a serious test of skill once you&amp;#x2019;ve unlocked a few moves and started running into the game&amp;#x2019;s more serious enemies. The world is beautifully put together, too, and you learn more about the fate of the city as you dash, skip, and double-jump into new zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Owlboy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#x2019;ll notice that many of these games are set underground in endless cave systems. &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/115800/Owlboy/"&gt;Owlboy&lt;/a&gt; is set in a floating cloud kingdom. As said Owlboy, Otus, you have to flap around the world in a slightly cumbersome manner befitting a character who is regarded as an idiot by his village. You can teleport friends into your claws as you fly around. Different pals come with different abilities; some will fend off nearby enemies with projectile attacks, others will help you to access new zones in true metroidvania fashion. It&amp;#x2019;s tricky to say much about Owlboy without spoiling the story, but suffice to say it&amp;#x2019;s an emotional ride depicted in lovingly detailed pixel art.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shadow Complex Remastered&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blast your way through a military compound with machine guns in this &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/385560/Shadow_Complex_Remastered/"&gt;futuristic Metroidvania&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#x2019;s billed as a &amp;#x201C;2.5D&amp;#x201D; game, which means you run and jump on a 2D plane, but can shoot into the background as soldiers and battle robots. You play as an ordinary man called Jason Fleming who gets lost on a hike and stumbles across a high-tech group bent on starting a civil war in the US. The game escalates from there you strap on their armour, raid their armoury and start blasting their mechs. The game was originally released on XBOX Live Arcade, but lives on Steam now as Shadow Complex Remastered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cave Story+&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daisuke Amaya&amp;#x2019;s seminal indie metroidvania is available on PC as &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/200900/Cave_Story/"&gt;Cave Story+&lt;/a&gt;, which features the original 320x240 visuals and the updated version. You play an amnesiac boy who wakes up in a cave full of rabbit folk called Mimigas. They are being picked off by the malign creations of a mad scientist, who you need to chase across 15 levels. It&amp;#x2019;s a big game, especially considering it was made by one very dedicated creator with a clear love for the 16-bit era. An absolute classic and a must-play if you love metroidvanias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Iconoclasts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From one solo creator to another. Joakim Sandberg spent many years painstakingly designing, animating and composing for &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/393520/Iconoclasts/"&gt;Iconoclasts&lt;/a&gt;. The result is a cheery and colourful metroidvania starring a friendly mechanic called Robin. This is a relatively shooty one featuring more than 20 bosses, but the worlds are packed with chatty characters. It&amp;#x2019;s worth picking up to see what seven years of one guy&amp;#x2019;s life&amp;#x2019;s work looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Steamworld Dig 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approachable, and not too difficult, the &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/571310/SteamWorld_Dig_2/"&gt;Steamworld Dig&lt;/a&gt; games deliver a gentle hit of Metroidvania action supplemented by lots of Terraria-style digging. You can pickaxe your way through the levels, but this isn&amp;#x2019;t a sandbox. You have to tunnel your way to new zones and grab new gadgets to upgrade your hero, a steam-powered cowboy robot in the first game and a blue woman in flying goggles in the second. The sequel has more varied environments and a bigger world to explore, so that&amp;#x2019;s the best place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dead Cells&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/588650/Dead_Cells/"&gt;Dead Cells&lt;/a&gt; straddles the line between Metroidvania and roguelike, which makes it a warped child of Super Metroid, Castlevania and Rogue. You battle through randomised dungeons, starting from the beginning each time you die. As you chop up enemies in beautifully animated exchanges of sword-blows and bow attacks they drop cells that you can pour into your character.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This persistent element eventually gives your guy the sturdiness to reach new zones you haven&amp;#x2019;t seen before, fulfilling the typical metroidvania exploration pattern. Dead Cells is a game about blasting through dungeons as quickly and efficiently as possible. When you arrive in an area a timer starts on a hidden treasure door somewhere on the level, if you can find it before the timer expires, you get access to a room full of special items and sweet cash. Dead Cells is a high pressure game compared to others in this list (bar Ori and Hollow Knight), but if you like action and great pixel art Dead Cells is a good option, though it still has some time to mature in Early Access.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2365952982525814920</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 17:19:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Watch the Accolades Trailer for Q.U.B.E. 2 </title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982525759202</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/31518971/8fd8df70d05ab5c85de8b3df356e7f8c06071bc4.gif"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&amp;#39;re proud to release our accolades trailer for Q.U.B.E. 2 which includes recent review scores and quotes from publications such as Destructoid, Gamespot and IGN.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The game has been praised by both press and players so thank you all for your support! Watch the full version here: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://youtu.be/mttDXi8T6Hs"&gt;https://youtu.be/mttDXi8T6Hs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope you enjoy watching it and feel free to check out the game yourself if you haven&amp;#39;t already! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/359100/QUBE_2/"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/app/359100/QUBE_2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks!</description><author>Toxic Games</author><guid>2365952982525759202</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 17:09:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Machinarium studio Amanita Design on its new horror game, PUBG, and cardboard</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2365952982525714045</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Machinarium&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;VIDEO: An interview with Lukas Kunce of Amanita Design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;apos;s the week of the Game Developers Conference here in San Francisco, which means devs from all over the world are in town to show off their games, talk about how they&amp;apos;re made, and throw business cards at strangers.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lucky for us, Lukas Kunce of Amanita Design, creators of point-and-click classics like Machinarium and the Samorost series, was kind enough to sit down with me away from business card firing range. We had a nice chat about their most recent game &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/chuchel-reivew/"&gt;Chuchel&lt;/a&gt;, what they&amp;apos;re working on now, and the future of adventure games.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also learned a bit about what the studio is working on now, including &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/the-creators-of-machinarium-and-chuchel-are-making-a-horror-game/"&gt;a horror game&lt;/a&gt; and another built of 3D scans of cardboard creations. For fans of fluff, we also discussed whether Chuchel will get the plushie treatment, what the hell the blockchain is, and brainstormed what an Amanita shooter would look like. (Hint: it won&amp;apos;t look like anything.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Listen:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/dl.pcgamer.com/PCG_Show_123_March19_2018_GDC_02_AMANITA.mp3"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Download the MP3 directly&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/pc-gamer/id383093125?mt=2"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Subscribe on iTunes&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.pcgamer.com/spark_podcast/2/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Grab the podcast RSS feed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your flapping heads for this episode:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/My_beards"&gt;&lt;u&gt;James Davenport&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LukasKunce" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Lukas Kunce&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2365952982525714045</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 16:45:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hitman s second episode is free for keepsies right now</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2365952982525601195</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for HITMAN™&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/03/hitman.jpg" title="Holiday - celebrate." width="620" height="300" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-528351" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second episode of the fab sneak-o-murder sandbox &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/hitman/"&gt;Hitman&lt;/a&gt; is free right now, yours for keepsies if you grab it by April 3rd. This is Ian Hitman&amp;#8217;s holiday to the sunny Italian seaside town of Sapienza, a colourful maze leading down to beautiful white sands. If you&amp;#8217;ve tried earlier free bits of Hitman but weren&amp;#8217;t sure about it, do give this a go as Sapienza is so much of an improvement over them. &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/21/hitman-episode-2-is-free-right-now/#more-528345" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Alice O'Connor)</author><guid>2365952982525601195</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 15:56:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Announcing Oddworld: Abe's Origins</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982525493905</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Oddworld: Abe's Oddysee&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Hello Oddworld fans!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We&amp;#39;re delighted to announce Oddworld: Abe&amp;#39;s Origins, a new art book from Indie By Design that charts the visual and development history of our classic titles, like Oddworld: Abe&amp;#39;s Oddysee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3953414/cc1168aa3b97117cdf5d39e6ba7486227dc7a062.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you&amp;#39;d like to read more about the project, please check it out here - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1869209521/oddworld-abes-origins-book-and-game-collection"&gt;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1869209521/oddworld-abes-origins-book-and-game-collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oddworld: Abe&amp;#39;s Origins will also include both Abe&amp;#39;s Oddysee and Abe&amp;#39;s Exoddus on a special physical PC release on DVD ROM, complete with instruction manual.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/3953414/f155acb2059db5d6854c1efadfc864172c359067.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope you like the project!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks, your friends at Oddworld and Indie By Design.</description><author>Oddworld Admin</author><guid>2365952982525493905</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 15:23:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hitman's best level is free for a limited time </title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2365952982525171682</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for HITMAN™&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/uk-weather-latest-easter-bank-holiday-snow-temperature-drop-weekend-forecast-a8264836.html"&gt;&lt;u&gt;perpetual snow warnings&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Met Office reckons Spring has kicked off in the Northern Hemisphere. If you can&amp;apos;t be convinced, you might fancy a complimentary trip to sunny Sapienza. &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/the-making-of-sapienza-hitmans-best-level/"&gt;Hitman&amp;apos;s best level&lt;/a&gt; is going free for a limited time.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of the game&amp;apos;s Spring Pack, the free download extends from now through April 3 whereafter the Sapienza mission is yours to keep for good.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developer IO Interactive explains that Elusive Targets have been reactivated too, and that the special offer also boasts 20 levels of Mastery (including weapon and item unlocks), over 100 challenges, and all of the Escalation Contracts, Challenge Packs and Featured Contracts specific to Episode 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XpvSU_VBEjQ"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on all of that can be found &lt;a href="https://www.ioi.dk/hitman-spring-pack/"&gt;over here&lt;/a&gt;. And before you go, let me share this excerpt from Phil&amp;apos;s &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/hitman-episode-2-review/"&gt;85-scoring Sapienza mission review&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sapienza&amp;apos;s freedom is an important distinction over Paris, but there&amp;apos;s another factor that makes it work so well. In The Showstopper mission, targets Viktor Novikov and Dalia Margolis host a fashion show and auction respectively. As such, they&amp;apos;re notable figures in a public space&amp;#x2014;on guard and suspicious.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In World of Tomorrow, your targets are living their lives. It&amp;apos;s not that they&amp;apos;re unprotected&amp;#x2014;their mansion is crawling with guards&amp;#x2014;but they aren&amp;apos;t suspecting anything out of the ordinary. That makes for a profound difference in how the levels play out. The challenge is less intricate, and that let&amp;apos;s 47 more naturalistically discover opportunities.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, Hitman&amp;apos;s Spring Pack is free to download now through April 3.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2365952982525171682</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 13:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Play Sapienza for FREE!</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982525116509</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for HITMAN™&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.akamai.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/4679451/7b7c8eb82e46f1a435aec02fddbcb8e26b1b0bd1.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Spring has arrived and it’s time to travel somewhere sunny! Your destination is Sapienza and everyone is invited via the HITMAN Spring Pack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The HITMAN Spring Pack is a completely FREE download and includes the entire Sapienza location (Episode 2). It&amp;#39;s yours to keep permanently and all of your progress will carry through to the full game when you buy the Game of the Year Edition - just make sure to download it before April 3rd!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You’ll get the main story mission, ‘World of Tomorrow’, 20 levels of Mastery (including weapon and item unlocks), more than 100 challenges, 7 achievements/trophies and ALL of the Escalation Contracts, Challenge Packs and Featured Contracts that we’ve released for Sapienza. On top of all that, any Elusive Targets that are re-activated in Sapienza will also be playable through the Spring Pack.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/236870/HITMAN/"&gt;http://store.steampowered.com/app/236870/HITMAN/&lt;/a&gt;</description><author>TravisIOI</author><guid>2365952982525116509</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 12:53:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hotfixes for 1.2 patch out now</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2365952982523849147</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Overgrowth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
1.2.1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Updated Steam API DLLs. This may fix some compatibility issues&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.2.2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix performance bug when Steam is running at same time as game (for some people this is as big as a 30% performance boost)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixes to several Therium-2 levels&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix to &amp;lt;ControlScript&amp;gt; functionality in character XML&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Removed unused SDL game controller haptic subsystem initialization (fixes crash on Launch on Linux)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make error non-fatal when failing to fully initialize a detected game controller&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.2.3&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix crash in hotfix 1.2.2 when launching game with 0 workshop mods installed (whoops!)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Known issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is an issue for some people where you try to launch the game and both the game and Steam crash. We&amp;#39;re still investigating the cause of this, but we believe this is due to the Steam shader pre-cache feature.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To work around this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;Steam -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Shader Pre-Cache -&amp;gt; uncheck Enable Shader Pre-Cache&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Delete this folder: C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\steamapps\shadercache\25000&lt;/li&gt;</description><author>kavika</author><guid>2365952982523849147</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 04:28:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Stanley Parable creator wants his next game to defy the rules of games </title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2365952982523708416</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for The Stanley Parable&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davey Wreden, creator of the The Stanley Parable and The Beginner&amp;apos;s Guide, discussed his current game design goals during an indie panel at GDC 2018 today. Wreden didn&amp;apos;t officially announce or nail down anything, but he did offer an intriguing glimpse at some of the ideas he&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;shooting for&amp;quot; and what we might see next from the eccentric designer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I&amp;apos;ve been thinking a lot about why people continue playing a game after they&amp;apos;ve started, assuming it&amp;apos;s somewhat fun or interesting on a core mechanical level,&amp;quot; Wreden said. &amp;quot;Why does a person want to put in hour after after on this one game as opposed to playing a different game? What creates their engagement?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wreden grouped the reasons for this into three categories. Firstly, to become better or to optimize, &amp;quot;the enjoyable feeling that you are better now at the game than you were when you started playing.&amp;quot; Secondly, to make progress, &amp;quot;watching your number go up or gaining more items or more stuff.&amp;quot; And thirdly, to see more content, &amp;quot;we like the story, we like the characters, we like the world, and we want to continue to see more of it.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;To me, these three things sum up what 99.9 percent of games are doing to engage players,&amp;quot; he continued. &amp;quot;And we know this is effective on some level and it can be a lot of fun. We all like games like this. The question I&amp;apos;ve been grappling with lately is, how could you make a game that is engaging, compelling and does not rely on any of these three things to make you interested?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;These three points all rely on something outside the act of play itself to be interesting. With the first, you&amp;apos;re imagining a future version of yourself who&amp;apos;s better at the game. With the second, you&amp;apos;re imagining a future where your number is bigger. With the third, you&amp;apos;re imagining how cool it will be to see the rest of the story. They&amp;apos;re all future-motivated. I would love to explore play that&amp;apos;s engaging and compelling in this very moment, without that reliance on the future.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The weird goal that I was setting for myself is to create a game that is intrinsically fun to play and has the kind of context that would make us say &amp;apos;this is a videogame,&amp;apos; but, at its core, does not rely on any of these three things to be compelling. I think they can still be there, but can they be something other than the sole direct reason why you want to continue playing?&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What would a game be like where you make interesting choices, but you can&amp;apos;t get better at making those choices, or you can&amp;apos;t make more optimized choices? What about a game where you&amp;apos;re growing or making progress in an interesting way, but where the outcomes are obscure enough that you can&amp;apos;t see what the outcomes will lead to? What about a game that has a story, but you don&amp;apos;t need to see every piece of content to get the story?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;All of these sound counterintuitive, but that&amp;apos;s why I&amp;apos;m so excited. The bizarre, impossible-sounding goal I&amp;apos;ve set for myself is to create a game that does all of these things. I don&amp;apos;t have a good answer yet as to how exactly I&amp;apos;ll do that.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If anyone can find a good answer to these wonky questions, it&amp;apos;s probably Wreden. The Stanley Parable scribbled all over narrative conventions, and The Beginner&amp;apos;s Guide was as much an intimate lecture on Wreden&amp;apos;s design process as it was a game. He&amp;apos;s made a name for himself by breaking the rules. It will be interesting to see if he can do it again and one-up his own auteurism.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2365952982523708416</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 03:26:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The creators of Machinarium and Chuchel are making a horror game</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2982945658370941694</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Machinarium&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find this eerie face on &lt;a href="http://www.jaromirplachy.net/games.html" target="_blank"&gt;Jarom  r Plach  's website&lt;/a&gt;, the only game project without a name or description.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a GDC interview with PC Gamer, Lukas Kunce of Amanita Design, creators of point-and-click classics like Machinarium and the slapstick comedy adventure Chuchel (&lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/chuchel-reivew/" target="_blank"&gt;which is a riot&lt;/a&gt;), confirmed that the studio is working on four new games, one of which is the studio&amp;apos;s first attempt at horror.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;apos;s the most games the studio has worked on at once, says Kunce. &amp;quot;We usually had one game going on at a moment, but now it&amp;apos;s four.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While chatting about the musicians behind Amanita&amp;apos;s games, Kunce gave us a few hints about what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it's like Chuchel is a full out burst of comedy, this is a full out burst of disturbing things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Lukas Kunce, Amanita Design&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Right now, Floex is not working on anything, but he&amp;apos;s probably going to start working pretty soon on one of the four secret projects, and DVA are working on another from Jarom&amp;#xED;r Plach&amp;#xFD;, who just finished Chuchel,&amp;quot; says Kunce. &amp;quot;And he&amp;apos;s already almost finished another game.&amp;quot;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jarom&amp;#xED;r Plach&amp;#xFD; is better known putting his creative energy into some of Amanita&amp;apos;s more buoyant, pleasant games, but if he can do scary as well as he does cute, then we&amp;apos;re in for some prime spooks.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;apos;s going to be a horror game, actually. Yeah, I&amp;apos;ve already played a bit and it&amp;apos;s so disturbing,&amp;quot; Kunce tells us. &amp;quot;Yeah, it&amp;apos;s like Chuchel is a full out burst of comedy, this is a full out burst of disturbing things.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We should know more by the end of the year, but Kunce didn&amp;apos;t want to make any promises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The horror game will probably be whatever the opposite of this is.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I asked if Amanita was always going to stick to 2D design, Kunce dropped a few details about one of the other three games in development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Well one of the games is played from the 2D perspective, but it&amp;apos;s actually made in 3D, so we can probably say we&amp;apos;re not 2D anymore.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He continues, &amp;quot;All of the assets and all of the buildings in the game and characters are made from actual cardboard and painted and stuff. And then they&amp;apos;re scanning it into Unity and kind of animating it and post-processing it. It&amp;apos;s got a super unique look.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;apos;ll be able to listen to our complete conversation soon, in which we ask what an Amanita shooter would look like, whether Chuchel will get the plushie treatment, and what the hell the blockchain is.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2982945658370941694</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 22:25:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>HDR for PC games is a hot mess (but it s nice when it works)</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2982945658370293450</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for HITMAN™&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-526597" src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/03/assassins-creed-hdr-620x330.jpg" alt="assassins-creed-hdr" width="620" height="330" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of the things I have had to do in order to get a workable version of HDR (also known as high dynamic range), the new-ish display technology that significantly ramps up brightness, darkness and vibrancy, on my PC (not including the acquisition of a fancy monitor):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Try four different display cables&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8211; Adjust as many as seven different brightness/contrast/colour etc shaders &lt;em&gt;per game&lt;/em&gt;. (I have spent long, unhappy hours doing this to date)&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8211; Manually turn on HDR on the monitor, manually turn HDR on in Windows then manually turn on HDR in the game settings. Or sometimes HDR off in Windows but on in the game then alt-tab back to Windows and turn HDR on, and off, and on, and off. Or sometimes alt-tab and alt-tab and alt-tab and alt-tab and alt-tab until HDR suddenly, randomly kicks in. When I exit the game, I have to manually turn it all back off again or Windows is unusable.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8211; Install an unfinished preview build of Windows 10 whose HDR isn&amp;#8217;t totally broken on Nvidia cards.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8211; Almost completely lose my sense of whether anything is actually different after all of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The egg yolks in &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/08/final-fantasy-15-pc-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Final Fantasy XV&lt;/a&gt; were a bit shinier, though.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/20/hdr-for-pc-games-2018/#more-526595" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Alec Meer)</author><guid>2982945658370293450</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 18:00:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Last Chance for the 20% off Discount from Q.U.B.E. 2</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2982945658367136359</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Q.U.B.E: Director's Cut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
It&amp;#39;s now less than 24 hours for you to pick up Q.U.B.E. 2 with the 20% launch discount on Steam. It ends tomorrow at 5PM GMT so grab it while you can!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img style="display: inline-block; max-width: 100%;" src="http://cdn.edgecast.steamstatic.com/steamcommunity/public/images/clans/4959436/c71738b0b59e906438e629d35a132957eb8254af.jpg"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks!&lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Toxic Games</author><guid>2982945658367136359</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 21:13:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The best space games on PC</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2095718613784630851</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Starbound&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survival horror, simulation, strategy, FPS, and many more genres feature in this, our roundup of the best space games you can play on PC right now. Whether you&amp;apos;re hunting pirates, building a colony on Mars, or fleeing in terror from a hungry alien on a stricken space station, these galactic games will appeal to anyone who&amp;apos;s ever dreamed of leaving boring old Earth behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Homeworld Remastered Collection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2015&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Relic/Gearbox Software&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.homeworldremastered.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
One of the best singleplayer RTS campaigns ever made, and beautifully remastered by Gearbox. The sight of thousands of your ships streaking across the game&amp;#x2019;s vividly colourful space-scapes is hugely dramatic. And battles are tense and tactical, with many types of ship to command, including colossal battleships. The Remastered Collection looks great on modern PCs and comes complete with the original Homeworld and its sequel.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Read more &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/homeworld-remastered-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Homeworld Remastered Collection review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Surviving Mars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a  target="_blank"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2018&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; Haemimont Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/464920/Surviving_Mars/" target="_blank"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Leaving Earth behind, humanity heads to Mars to start a new colony: and you&amp;apos;re in charge of it. Your new civilisation will grow from one small dome in the Martian desert to a bustling, sprawling off-world metropolis. But just make sure you don&amp;apos;t run out of oxygen or power, because on this ruthless planet it&amp;apos;s a death sentence for every citizen under your control.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/surviving-mars-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Surviving Mars review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tacoma&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2017&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; Fullbright&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://tacoma.game/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The crew has mysteriously abandoned the Tacoma lunar transfer station, and you&amp;#x2019;ve been sent to investigate and recover its precious AI, Odin. This atmospheric sci-fi mystery from the makers of Gone Home is wonderfully written, with a cast of rich, nuanced characters telling a compelling story through interactive AR recordings. Exploring the hyper-detailed station is a delight thanks to the game&amp;#x2019;s extraordinary attention to detail, and the more you learn about Tacoma, the deeper the mystery gets.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Read more &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/tacoma-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Tacoma review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Elite Dangerous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2014&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Frontier Developments&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.elitedangerous.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
An entire galaxy is your playground in this space sim. Starting with a basic ship and a handful of credits, you shape your own destiny. Do you become a fearsome pirate? A master trader? An explorer? The beauty of Elite is being able to play in a way that suits you. From thrilling dogfights to gentle exploration, there&amp;#x2019;s something for everyone. And its ships are all an absolute dream to fly, whether it&amp;apos;s a nimble fighter or a heavy duty cargo hauler.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Read more &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/visiting-nasas-latest-discovery-in-elite-dangerous/" target="_blank"&gt;Visiting NASA&amp;apos;s latest discovery in Elite Dangerous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;EVE Online&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2003&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;CCP Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eveonline.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Live another life&amp;#x2014;in space! There&amp;#x2019;s nothing else like EVE Online on PC, a massively multiplayer RPG where everything is controlled by players. It&amp;#x2019;s a living galaxy in which thousands of capsuleers fight, trade, mine, and explore together. Break away from the relative safety of your police-patrolled starting system and you&amp;#x2019;ll find a ruthless, cosmic Wild West, where piracy, espionage and scamming are rife. Whether you&amp;#x2019;re fighting in a massive space war, where thousands of real-world dollars hang in the balance, or just exploring New Eden on your own, EVE is an unforgettable experience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/eve-onlines-biggest-scammer-tells-us-his-secrets/" target="_blank"&gt;EVE Online&amp;apos;s biggest scammer tells us his secrets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Everspace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a  target="_blank"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2017&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Rockfish Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/396750/EVERSPACE/" target="_blank"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
When you die in roguelike Everspace, you&amp;#x2019;re dead. But money earned carries over and can be spent on upgrades, which means you&amp;#x2019;ll be more powerful for your next run through the cosmic gauntlet. And these perks keep adding up, allowing you to travel deeper into space, and more boldly, with every successive attempt. It&amp;#x2019;s a compelling loop, and when you die you&amp;apos;re never frustrated: just excited to start again, wondering how far you&amp;apos;ll make it this time.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/death-is-the-road-to-glory-in-everspace/" target="_blank"&gt;Death is the road to glory in Everspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Star Wars: Empire at War&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2006&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Petroglyph&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.gog.com/game/star_wars_empire_at_war_gold_pack" target="_blank"&gt;GOG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Developed by Petroglyph, a studio founded by Westwood veterans, this real-time strategy is one of the best Star Wars games on PC. The streamlined interface and accessible systems might turn off some hardcore strategy fans, but in the thick of its chaotic, thrilling land and space battles the game is irresistible&amp;#x2014;especially if you&amp;#x2019;re a Star Wars fan. And hero units like Darth Vader and Luke Skywalker only add to the excitement.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/pitting-star-wars-against-star-trek-in-star-wars-empire-at-war/" target="_blank"&gt;Pitting Star Wars against Star Trek in Star Wars: Empire at War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Heat Signature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a  target="_blank"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2017&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; Suspicious Developments&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/268130/Heat_Signature/" target="_blank"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In this top-down sci-fi action game you board spaceships and use an array of weapons and gadgets to take out the crew. The genius lies in how much creativity you&amp;apos;re given to play your own way, inspired by the best immersive sims. And how you react to the chaos that erupts when your presence on the ship becomes known makes Heat Signature a powerful anecdote generator. Things might not always go to plan, but that&amp;apos;s just part of the fun.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Read more &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/8-sadistic-ways-to-take-out-guards-in-heat-signature/" target="_blank"&gt;8 sadistic ways to take out guards in Heat Signature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Duskers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2016&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Misfits Attic&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://duskers.misfits-attic.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Despite being viewed entirely through a retro-futuristic computer interface, Duskers is one of the scariest, most tense sci-fi horror games on PC. In it you pilot a fleet of drones searching derelict spaceships for fuel, upgrades, and clues about why the galaxy is so mysteriously devoid of life. The ships you board are crawling with strange creatures, which makes looking for clues in those narrow, dark corridors an especially nerve-racking experience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/duskers-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Duskers review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a  target="_blank"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year&lt;/strong&gt; 2017&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; Bungie&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.destinythegame.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Bungie&amp;apos;s addictive FPS/MMO hybrid features some of the prettiest alien landscapes on PC. From the forested ruins of Earth and the vast seas of Titan, to the red jungles of Nessus and the volcanic Io, every location is a pleasure to loot-and-shoot in. The endgame doesn&amp;apos;t have the iron grip it perhaps should, but sci-fi fans will get a kick out of this vivid, colourful setting.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/bungie-outlines-how-it-plans-to-fix-destiny-2-in-2018/" target="_blank"&gt;Bungie outlines how it plans to fix Destiny 2 in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Dig&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;1995&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; LucasArts&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gog.com/game/the_dig" target="_blank"&gt;GOG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A mission to divert an asteroid heading for Earth goes awry, sending a group of astronauts to a distant, seemingly abandoned world. Some of the puzzles are maddeningly obscure, even for a LucasArts point-and-click adventure, but the colourful, bizarre planet feels genuinely alien. Great voice acting too, with X-Files star Robert Patrick playing the lead character.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/reinstall-the-dig/" target="_blank"&gt;Reinstall: The Dig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Universe Sandbox 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year&lt;/strong&gt; 2014&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; Giant Army&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://universesandbox.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This space simulator lets you become an all-powerful cosmic deity, manipulating replicas of real galaxies and solar systems and witnessing the (often catastrophic) results of your meddling. Increase the mass of Jupiter and you&amp;#x2019;ll see the rest of our solar system being sucked into it, or delete the Sun and watch Earth and the other planets drift away confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Event[0]&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2016&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Ocelot Society&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/470260/Event0/" target="_blank"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Stranded alone somewhere near Jupiter on an old luxury starship, your only hope of returning home is an AI that has serious emotional problems. You interact with Kaizen using your keyboard, and sometimes it&amp;apos;ll be willing to help you. But then it&amp;apos;ll change its mind and decide the best thing to do is close the airlock and trap you outside the ship until you run out of air. A clever adventure with the understated mood of a &amp;apos;70s sci-fi film.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/event0-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Event[0] review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mass Effect 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2010&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; BioWare&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/24980/Mass_Effect_2/" target="_blank"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If you&amp;#x2019;ve ever fantasised about being Captain Picard, in command of your own starship, exploring the galaxy, meeting weird aliens, being confronted with cosmic dilemmas, then Mass Effect 2 is that in game form. It&amp;#x2019;s part Star Wars space opera, part brilliant Star Trek episode, and one of the best sci-fi games on PC. It doesn&amp;#x2019;t have the freedom of Elite and is largely a linear experience, but it takes you on an unforgettable journey around the galaxy, visiting bizarre planets and getting involved in the lives of the aliens who live on them. We love the whole series, but we all agree that this is our favourite.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/the-mass-effect-games-ranked-from-worst-to-best/" target="_blank"&gt;The Mass Effect games ranked from worst to best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Stellaris&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2016&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Paradox&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.paradoxplaza.com/stellaris/STST01G-MASTER.html" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Developed by Paradox, of Crusader Kings and Europa Universalis fame, this sci-fi epic puts the &amp;#x2018;grand&amp;#x2019; in grand strategy. Explore the universe, form alliances with alien factions, and engage in the odd large-scale space battle. The multitude of systems makes Stellaris a powerful story generator, and you never know what strange beings you&amp;#x2019;ll meet among the stars.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Read more &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/stellaris-utopia-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Stellaris: Utopia review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alien: Isolation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2014&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; Creative Assembly&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alienisolation.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Amanda Ripley, daughter of Ellen, is hunted through a dilapidated space station by a xenomorph in this incredible survival horror. Taking its cues from Ridley Scott&amp;apos;s original 1979 film, it&amp;apos;s a masterpiece of slow-burning tension. And the station itself, Sevastopol, is a great example of lo-fi sci-fi, with chunky retro-futuristic tech and eerie flickering lights. One of the most faithful movie adaptations ever, and a great horror game in its own right.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/what-alien-isolation-gets-right-that-alien-covenant-gets-wrong/" target="_blank"&gt;What Alien: Isolation gets right that Alien: Covenant gets wrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No Man&amp;apos;s Sky&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2016&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Hello Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.nomanssky.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This is one of the most dazzlingly colourful sci-fi universes on PC, and being able to seamlessly transition from space to the surface of a planet is an impressive technical feat. The addition of features like base-building and a mission system in recent updates give you a lot more to actually do when you touch down on these worlds, and the procedural generation algorithm has been tweaked to make for weirder, prettier planet surfaces.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/no-mans-sky-mods/" target="_blank"&gt;The best No Man&amp;apos;s Sky mods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Star Wars: TIE Fighter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year&lt;/strong&gt; 1994&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; Totally Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gog.com/game/star_wars_tie_fighter_special_edition" target="_blank"&gt;GOG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A rare opportunity to be the bad guy in George Lucas&amp;#x2019;s beloved space opera. With a variety of Empire-themed missions&amp;#x2014;dogfights, escorts, attacking capital ships&amp;#x2014;and a story to follow, it&amp;#x2019;s one of the best Star Wars games LucasArts ever published. Of course, you can replace this entry with Star Wars: X-Wing if you&amp;#x2019;d prefer to play as the boring old Rebel Alliance.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/the-best-star-wars-games-on-pc/" target="_blank"&gt;The best Star Wars games on PC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FTL: Faster Than Light&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2012&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Subset Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/212680/FTL_Faster_Than_Light/" target="_blank"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
FTL mixes turn-based and real-time strategy together to capture the experience of captaining a Star Trek-style spacecraft. It&amp;#x2019;s a strong roguelike, too, with a backdrop of a familiar yet fun sci-fi universe that comes with its own semi-humorous lore and a neat set of narrative beats that make the journey to its finale endlessly exciting. Being able to name your ship and crew makes it all the more heartbreaking when they die together in enemy space.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/the-writing-in-ftl/" target="_blank"&gt;The writing in FTL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wing Commander: Privateer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;1993&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Origin Systems&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gog.com/game/wing_commander_privateer" target="_blank"&gt;GOG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Fans of the series will argue endlessly about which Wing Commander is the best, but we love Privateer&amp;#x2019;s darker feel. It&amp;#x2019;s a rich sandbox in which you can be a mercenary, a pirate, a merchant, or a mix of all three. You jump between systems looking for bounties to hunt and ships to rob, and the first-person dogfights are a thrill. There&amp;#x2019;s a linear story, but the real joy lies in doing your own thing and carving your own path through the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#xA0;EVE: Valkyrie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2016&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;CCP Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.evevalkyrie.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If you have a VR headset, this is the game to play on it. In Valkyrie you get to experience EVE Online&amp;#x2019;s famous space battles from the more intimate perspective of an individual fighter pilot. The feeling of being strapped into a cockpit, hurtling through space at immense speeds, is a visceral one. And the combat has been tuned specifically for virtual reality.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/eve-valkyrie-review/" target="_blank"&gt;EVE: Valkyrie review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kerbal Space Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2015&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Squad&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://kerbalspaceprogram.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Wrestle with gravity and the laws of physics as you build your own spacecraft and attempt to explore the cosmos. A robust, compelling sandbox of possibilities that&amp;#x2019;s as funny as it is clever. Escaping Kerbin&amp;#x2019;s atmosphere and landing on the Mun (without exploding) for the first time with a ship you&amp;#x2019;ve built yourself is about as satisfying as PC gaming gets.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/kerbal-space-program-making-history-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Kerbal Space Program: Making History review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Take On Mars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2013&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Bohemia Interactive&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mars.takeonthegame.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If you like your space games a little more grounded, try Arma developer Bohemia&amp;#x2019;s Take On Mars. It&amp;#x2019;s a space exploration and colonisation simulator largely based on real astro-science. You can build a Curiosity-style rover and explore the surface of the red planet or construct your own Martian colony. A game for folk who want the sci without too much of the fi.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/building-a-mighty-space-base-in-take-on-mars/" target="_blank"&gt;Building a mighty space base in Take On Mars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#xA0;Sins of a Solar Empire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2008&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Ironclad Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sinsofasolarempire.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Mixing real-time strategy with 4X elements, Sins is a game of galactic conquest. Choose a faction, gather resources and become a mighty space-lord. Commanding its real-time wars is thrilling, but combat isn&amp;#x2019;t always the answer: you can use diplomacy to conquer systems too. A refreshingly slow-paced RTS with some truly massive space battles to stare slack-jawed at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Space Engineers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2013&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Keen Software House&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.spaceengineersgame.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harvest asteroids for building materials then craft them into floating bases, flyable spaceships, and more besides. You can hover around the map with a jetpack or build a gravity generator to walk safely on the surface of bigger asteroids. One of the best co-op build-&amp;#x2019;em-ups on PC.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/an-erratic-journey-to-the-moon-in-space-engineers/" target="_blank"&gt;An erratic journey to the Moon in Space Engineers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Starbound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2013&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer&lt;/strong&gt; Chucklefish Games&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://playstarbound.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Terraria-esque survival with a science fiction twist. Hop between randomly generated planets on a starship, hunt alien creatures for food, build colonies and underground bases, and try not to die in the process. A brilliant sci-fi sandbox with a charming art style. Playable races include robots, beings made of solar energy, ape-like creatures, and colourful wingless birds.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/starbound-review/" target="_blank"&gt;Starbound review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SpaceEngine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year &lt;/strong&gt;2010&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Developer &lt;/strong&gt;Vladimir Romanyuk&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Link &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://spaceengine.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you like feeling small and insignificant? Then play SpaceEngine, which features, incredibly, the entire universe. Or at least the bit we know about. Focus on Earth, then pull back at top speed, and you suddenly become aware of how you&amp;#x2019;re on a tiny speck of dust hurtling through an endless void. The tech is remarkable, allowing you to travel effortlessly between galaxies and land on planets. But besides exploring, there isn&amp;#x2019;t much else to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2095718613784630851</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 15:37:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March Map Jam - The Protagonist Dies at the End</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/steam_community_announcements/2982945658361759358</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Community Announcements&lt;/b&gt; for Overgrowth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;With the new 1.2 patch, it&amp;#39;s time to start a map jam!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edit: The jam is now complete. Come here to see the announcement, find the list of new mods, and to cast your vote for your favorite! &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://steamcommunity.com/gid/103582791430184966/announcements/detail/1663392709273977374"&gt;https://steamcommunity.com/gid/103582791430184966/announcements/detail/1663392709273977374&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Starting on the 18th of March, anyone who would like to participate has two weeks to create a map with the level editor using the theme given to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The theme of the map jam is &lt;strong&gt;Protagonist Dies At The End&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The deadline is March 30th.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For tutorials on how to create a map in the level editor, check here:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://steamcommunity.com/app/25000/discussions/0/1697167355219210068/"&gt;Steam forum post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLuNY3k_ozhofaucF0mq043_QAj8eEgXzV"&gt;Youtube playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://wiki.wolfire.com/index.php/Editor_Interface"&gt;Wolfire wiki page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For discussion about the map jam, join &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://discord.gg/wolfire"&gt;the official Wolfire Discord&lt;/a&gt;, and check out the #map-jam-march-2018 channel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Rules:
- You can make any kind of map you want, as long as it fits the theme.
- All maps have to be completed by March 30th.
- It should be uploaded to the Workshop, but your level can also be uploaded here through Discord.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Interpret the theme in any way you want, and most importantly, have fun!</description><author>kavika</author><guid>2982945658361759358</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 09:30:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>People love farming simulators, Pure Farming 2018 wants to take that global</title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/rps/2982945658359317871</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;Rock, Paper, Shotgun&lt;/b&gt; for Stardew Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images//2018/03/pure_farming_2018_01_0-620x350.jpg" alt="pure_farming_2018_01_0" width="620" height="350" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-527219" srcset="https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images/2018/03/pure_farming_2018_01_0-620x350.jpg 620w, https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images/2018/03/pure_farming_2018_01_0-768x434.jpg 768w, https://assets.rockpapershotgun.com/images/2018/03/pure_farming_2018_01_0.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tag/pure-farming"&gt;Pure Farming&lt;/a&gt; 2018 is out now. Farming Sim games now come from several competitive developers but also that competition leaves me confused because most entries in the Farm Gaming World seem interchangeable. I&amp;#8217;m missing a key element in what draws people in, but this genre keeps raking in money hand over fist, so the problem must be with me. Let&amp;#8217;s take a look at what Pure Farming 2018 is bringing to the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: Whoops, I got a bit carried away in writing this game up the first time. I have some frustrations with the genre and it got a bit out of hand. Sorry to any digital farmers whom may have been offended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/17/people-love-farming-games-for-some-reason-heres-another-one/#more-527203" class="more-link"&gt;(more&amp;hellip;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><author>contact@rockpapershotgun.com (Brock Wilbur)</author><guid>2982945658359317871</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 16:39:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Which game actually lived up to the hype? </title><link>http://store.steampowered.com/news/externalpost/pcgamer/2982945658358101644</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Via &lt;b&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/b&gt; for Half-Life 2, Portal 2, METAL GEAR SOLID V: THE PHANTOM PAIN&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, snap! It&amp;apos;s yet another &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/tag/pcg-qa/" target="_blank"&gt;PCG Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/a&gt;, where every Saturday we ask the panel of PC Gamer writers a question about PC gaming. You&amp;apos;re also very welcome to share your thoughts in the comments below. This week: &lt;strong&gt;which game actually lived up to the hype?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Jody Macgregor: The Witcher 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hated the first Witcher game, and although the second one&amp;apos;s an improvement in a lot of ways I still thought most of it was dull&amp;#x2014;apart from the bit where you get drunk and wake up with a tattoo, obviously. So when glowing reviews came out for The Witcher 3 I ignored them. There was plenty of other stuff to play in 2015: Tales From the Borderlands, Rocket League, Life is Strange, Pillars of Eternity, Devil Daggers, Her Story. I was busy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took a solid year&amp;apos;s worth of articles about how incredible every aspect of The Witcher 3 was, from the side quests to the potion-making to the characters to the wind in the goddamn trees, before I finally caved and tried it. Everyone was right, it&amp;apos;s now on my &amp;quot;best games of all time&amp;quot; list, and I&amp;apos;ve become one of those people who says you should turn the music down so you can hear the wind in Velen. There&amp;apos;s an entire subreddit devoted to whinging about games journalism&amp;apos;s never-ending love affair with writing about The Witcher 3, but without that constant praise I wouldn&amp;apos;t have pushed past my disinterest to give it the chance it deserved. And now I&amp;apos;ve become one of those people who won&amp;apos;t shut up about The Witcher 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Samuel Roberts: Metal Gear Solid V&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone will agree with this one, but I&amp;apos;ve lived through multiple Metal Gear hype cycles (MGS2 and MGS4 most memorably), and this is the one game that really deserved it. While this Metal Gear has the worst story in the series by far, it&amp;apos;s also a superior stealth game. With its suite of upgrades and repeatable missions, I easily played MGSV for over 100 hours, and I have no doubt I&amp;apos;ll reinstall it someday.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chris Livingston: Portal 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the original Portal was a near-perfect experience. You learned to play as you played and each test chamber increased in complexity at a rate that was challenging but never frustrating. It was funny and surprising and satisfying, and short enough that it didn&amp;apos;t have time to wear out its welcome. When trailers for Portal 2 began appearing, I was just as excited as anyone else, though I wasn&amp;apos;t really expecting to love it in the same way. More complex, more characters, more story, more puzzles, more more more. I just couldn&amp;apos;t imagine it matching the original, which proved (to me at least) that less is more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It definitely lived up to the hype, though. Portal 2 is amazing, funny, challenging, surprising, and every bit as brilliant as the first. Maybe it&amp;apos;s still true that less is more, but that doesn&amp;apos;t mean more is less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Jarred Walton: Half-Life 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piggybacking off Chris here, Half-Life 2 was an incredible follow-up to one of the best (if not the best) games of the &amp;apos;90s. The original Half-Life surprised the hell out of me with ways it changed the first-person shooter. After playing a ton of Quake and Quake 2, story seemed to be an afterthought, but Half-Life revolutionized the genre. Okay, the Xen levels at the end almost ruined it, but I still wanted more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then I waited, waited, and waited some more. Daikatana proved that games too long in development could suck, and HL2 felt like it might be doomed to the same fate. But with the addition of the gravity gun and physics, plus a great setting and story that made you care about the characters, it exceeded its source material in every way. I&amp;apos;m still holding out hope for HL3, naturally, but those are some massive shoes to fill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tom Senior: Deus Ex: Human Revolution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was dangerously excited when a new Deus Ex was announced. I was hyped to the extent that it would have really stung if a new Deus Ex fell well short of expectations. Human Revolution had a few problems, but it was exactly the atmospheric cyberpunk playground I wanted and the art direction added a new dimension to the Deus Ex universe. Due to the technological limitations of the era the old Deus Ex games struggled to show art or architecture (apart from that silly Earth-in-a-giant-claw statue at the start). Human Revolution decided that everything would be gold, and full of triangles, and its depiction of futuristic augments was gorgeous. I would quite like a pair of Jensen arms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Human Revolution really got Deus Ex. It had hacking, vents, and intricate levels. But it also had something else, something &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt;: retractable arm-swords. Not many people would look at the groundbreaking masterpiece of Deus Ex and think &amp;apos;this needs retractable arm-swords&amp;apos;, but Eidos Montreal had the vision to make retractable arm-swords happen. I will always respect them for that.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Andy Kelly: Grand Theft Auto: Vice City&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the buzz around Vice City vividly. Every time I saw that stylish advert on TV, the one with &amp;apos;I Ran&amp;apos; by Flock of Seagulls, I got a tingle of excitement. Magazines were full of gushing previews, treating every morsel of information like it was the biggest scoop since Watergate. And then when it came out, it was everything I dreamed it would be. A bigger, more detailed city. An incredible soundtrack. More fun and varied missions. A better story. An all-star cast. HELICOPTERS. Being able to fly around a city of that size back then was a genuine thrill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;GTA III was great, but it felt like an experiment in places; a concept for what a 3D Grand Theft Auto game could be. But Vice City was the first time Rockstar really nailed it, and laid a solid foundation for the 3D era of their world-conquering series. The &amp;apos;80s (or at least some exaggerated, romanticised version of it) has begun to saturate pop culture to an annoying degree lately, so I can&amp;apos;t see Rockstar returning to that setting. It&amp;apos;s too obvious. But I would like to see Vice City again in a different, more contemporary era, perhaps showing the bleak, faded aftermath of its hedonistic &amp;apos;80s heyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Andy Chalk: Deus Ex: Human Revolution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I saw &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mjhkpTWIBuA" target="_blank"&gt;this teaser&lt;/a&gt; I made a noise like a ten-year-old opening the latest issue of Tiger Beat. Then I saw &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hoRwOux7Ofw" target="_blank"&gt;this teaser&lt;/a&gt;, and I pretty much hyperventilated and passed out. I knew in my heart that DX: Human Revolution couldn&amp;apos;t be that good, because Deus Ex was lightning in a bottle: Ugly, clunky, with terrible voice acting and a ridiculous, incoherent story, all of which somehow got smushed together into basically the best game ever made. How do you fall down a flight of stairs and land in a bed of roses twice?&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then Human Revolution came out, and it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; that good. Not perfect, and I will never not be mad about those boss fights. But Adam Jensen is the perfect successor (predecessor, I suppose) to JC Denton, I loved the visual style (including the piss filter) and the music (because it&amp;apos;s not Deus Ex without a great soundtrack), and the whole thing just felt right: Not as off-the-conspiracy-theory-hook as the original, but big and sprawling and unpredictable&amp;#x2014;a legitimate point of entry into that world. It took more than a decade to get from Deus Ex to Human Revolution, and it was worth the wait.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author></author><guid>2982945658358101644</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 09:09:03 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>